<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data center on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/data-center/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data center on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 15:30:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/data-center/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oh...Spanning Tree</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2019/01/02/oh...spanning-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 15:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2019/01/02/oh...spanning-tree/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s the &amp;quot;S&amp;quot; word we don&#39;t like to hear, and often times it has degraded networks or even took them down entirely. (All Systems Down - an older but classic story) It&#39;s also one of those things that nobody really likes, we even had network companies, as well as IEEE try to replace it with something else. Remember the names like TRILL, and IEEE 802.1aq (SPB) or Cisco&#39;s FabicPath technologies? You had all of these different flavors that showed a lot progress, but they never really took off for one reason or another.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco UCS Emulator 3.1(1ePE1)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/07/16/cisco-ucs-emulator-3.11epe1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 20:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/07/16/cisco-ucs-emulator-3.11epe1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you are studying any Cisco Data Center certs this tool might come in handy for some hands on learning. The Cisco UCS emulator is a VM you can spin up in VMware Workstation,Fusion or in ESXi. This emulator can be helpful in understanding the UCS platform and UCS manager. You are able to push policies and alter configurations and even import/export these configurations into and out of the &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; world to apply them/test them.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed the 640-911 DCICN</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/05/14/passed-the-640-911-dcicn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 01:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/05/14/passed-the-640-911-dcicn/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco started this exam back in 2012 and I have thought/semi-studied about this test for about over a year now, just did not feel comfy about it until recently. I took the test last week and passed, however there were some questions on the exam I noticed that weren&#39;t on the exam blueprint so that kind of surprised me. I was happy to still be able to pass the exam but I was caught off guard.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Enhanced vPC on Nexus 5600</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/09/10/setting-up-enhanced-vpc-on-nexus-5600/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/09/10/setting-up-enhanced-vpc-on-nexus-5600/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I&#39;ve played around with two Cisco Nexus 5672UP switches which will be in production soon but before that I wanted to see what it took to get enhanced vPC online. Along the way I was into some new territory as I never stood up vPC before, so in this post I have posted some things to keep in mind and running-config examples, all of which I hope is helpful for a reference.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter-VLAN Routing on the Nexus 5k</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 15:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I previously had the chance to play around with the 5596UP switch, and made some notes on how to configure inter-vlan routing. Since this was a 5596UP switch I needed a layer 3 card to take advantage of it. The next-generation units the 5600 include layer 3 without a card required along with introducing 40GB uplinks! However in this post let&#39;s go back to the basics and configure inter-vlan routing on a nexus switch and in this case I am using a 5596UP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 7)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you made it past the earlier chapters this one should be interesting, like before I am going through each chapter of the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Comment below if you have questions in this chapter, last week we learned about subnetting and in this chapter we will learn about the NX-OS which is Cisco&#39;s Data Center switches. Let&#39;s begin! Overview: This was short chapter in introducing the NX-OS product line and into the virtualized enviroments that data centers are now becoming.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 5)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 19:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last week we covered chapter four which talked about the TCP/IP and the DoD models and what role they cover in networking as we learned that every application like FTP, DNS, DHCP depend on it. Like always post questions if you have any about the book CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I&#39;ll continue to cover topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 4)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 18:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off on Chapter 3 on CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Like before feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter three we discussed about Ethernet Technologies and in chapter four we will learn about the TCP/IP protocol which is fundamentally the protocol that makes the Internet work.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 2)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 19:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am continuing the ongoing of series of blog posts that follow the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I figured that this type of post would help me and anybody else looking at studying for the exam. Feel free to post questions below as if on a study group, In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting FEX (5k to 2k)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/12/01/connecting-fex-5k-to-2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 15:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/12/01/connecting-fex-5k-to-2k/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was pretty excited to get my hands on some of the Cisco Nexus product line which focuses on switching in the data center. The gear I have is an evaluation unit so I made some notes and one thing I was impressed is how easy it is to connect a Nexus 5K to a Nexus 2k also known as a fabric extender. I have kept it simple as the gear I have is a single Nexus 5596 along with a single Nexus 224TP-E who needs redundancy right?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed 640-554!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/06/29/passed-640-554/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/06/29/passed-640-554/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Short story, I am proud to say that I passed! I have studied off and on in the beginning of the year but I did set a date to take the exam which was June 28th .As that date was getting closer I buckled down and reviewed the materials again and focused in on some areas that I knew I was weak in.
So how was the 640-554 exam, what did I use to pass the exam and what exam am I focusing on next?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Data Center</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 02:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco has now introduced another associate level exam, the CCNA Data Center exam. Like the name suggests this exam focuses on the Data Center and if passed you can continue up the stack by also taking the CCNP Data Center exam which was also recently introduced as well. Still want more a little more, if you are up for the challenge you can also tackle the CCIE Data Center which is an exam that was introduced in March of 2012.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Nexus 1000v?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/03/17/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 17:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/03/17/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network_cloud I have worked with the Nexus 1000v product and wanted to share my thoughts on it. I want to explain in this blog what this product is and what it does. The Nexus 1000v can be virtual or a hardware appliance and is considered to be a virtual switch that runs in VMware. The major benefit to this product is the visibly you get when running in a virtual environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
