<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network performance on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/network-performance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network performance on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 17:00:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/network-performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating VLANs</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today this tutorial is going to be talking about creating VLANs (Virtual Local Area Networks) with a Cisco Catalyst switch. By creating a VLAN you are separating the network, why would you do this? There are some several reasons, like separating your production network from a guest network, and separating a test environment from a production network. This all adds security to your network. You can separate core critical network components from the rest of the production network for added security, easier troubleshooting along with separating or segmenting your network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collision Domains vs Broadcast Domains</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These different types of domains mean different things and when designing a LAN both of these domains can harm the performance of your network. If you are not aware of the difference between these two, this tutorial should help you out. If you have a small network at your home there is usually the router/modem that is connected via phone line or cable to the ISP that router/modem is then connected to a switch or they even have a switch built into the device.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
