<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cisco Troubleshooting on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/cisco-troubleshooting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cisco Troubleshooting on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 04:58:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/cisco-troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Network Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/11/11/network-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 04:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/11/11/network-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/thinking.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/thinking.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The thing that makes networks awesome is the fact that once you setup a network you&#39;re not done. That may sound like a drawback but it is excellent job security! Engineers or administrators must watch the performance of an organization&#39;s network to make sure that productivity is not affected. Network outages can have a huge effect on an organization, lost revenue and the cost of unproductive employees can severely damage the organization, Earlier this year I also talked about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting Process&#34;&gt;troubleshooting process&lt;/a&gt; which goes hand in hand with network troubleshooting. One of the major things a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_administrator&#34; title=&#34;Network administrator&#34;&gt;network engineer&lt;/a&gt; or administrator needs to have is documentation of the network. That may sound like common sense and it is but with outdated documentation or no documentation at all makes it difficult to diagnose where the problem is and even more difficult if more help is needed from outside sources. Just with your computer, car and home, networks need to have a regular maintenance from time to time. Spending time on an operational network can improve its performance and uptime. Instead using the &amp;quot;duct tape&amp;quot; approach when outages occur. So we know documentation is important but it always seems to be on the backburner, &amp;quot;I&#39;ll get to it when there is time to burn&amp;quot; From my recent experience working with a hospital is that when things went down I had no idea where to start, the documentation was outdated twice over and let&#39;s just say the problem could have been fixed in 5 minutes instead of an hour. Needless to say I broke out &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Visio&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Visio&#34;&gt;Microsoft Visio&lt;/a&gt; and worked from the ground up. Having documentation is good idea but the kicker is to remember to update it when changes occur :). &lt;strong&gt;Simple problems are usually simple solutions&lt;/strong&gt;, we all have been there, a problem comes up 5 minutes before heading home and the problem itself is simple but for whatever reason the solution cannot be found. From my experience from troubleshooting labs and real world environments I have found that looking at the whole problem helps and take it one step at a time. For example a server or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_computer&#34; title=&#34;Personal computer&#34;&gt;PC&lt;/a&gt; no longer has &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_network&#34; title=&#34;Access network&#34;&gt;network access&lt;/a&gt;, does another PC or server that&#39;s on the same network able to use the resources needed? Continue to use the Troubleshooting Process and ask those simple questions until the solution is found. &lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t cover your tracks!&lt;/strong&gt; I have done this couple of times myself, when configuring a device like a router, switch, firewall etc. no matter how simple the configuration change seems to be always, copy the commands to a text file after you configured the device. Or better yet copy the commands to a text document first, read it through to make sure it seems correct and if something fails reverse the command. &lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t copy-run start!&lt;/strong&gt; This kind of goes with the one above but this method has saved me in some sketchy areas. When I take an already working device and throw some extra commands on it and now it disconnects from the network making an already problem worse than before. A simple reload or a pull of a power plug brings the device up before I made those changes. Once I have confirmed that those commands worked I then issue the famous copy run start command. &lt;strong&gt;Monitor your network,&lt;/strong&gt; How do you know what &amp;quot;normal&amp;quot; looks like when you have nothing looking at it? There are tons of paid and free tools to help you find that &amp;quot;normal&amp;quot; network load. So when something happens outside of normal you know about it. Some tools that I have worked with are &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paessler_Router_Traffic_Grapher&#34; title=&#34;Paessler Router Traffic Grapher&#34;&gt;PRTG&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi_Router_Traffic_Grapher&#34; title=&#34;Multi Router Traffic Grapher&#34;&gt;MRTG&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syslog&#34; title=&#34;Syslog&#34;&gt;Syslog&lt;/a&gt; servers like Kiwi Syslog, I have also heard of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nagios&#34; title=&#34;Nagios&#34;&gt;Nagios&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whatsupgold.com/&#34; title=&#34;WhatsUp Gold&#34;&gt;WhatsUp Gold&lt;/a&gt;, and much more. A simple search will point you in the right direction ;). I hope this information is helpful when troubleshooting networks because although it can be a headache sometimes it&#39;s my favorite part of the job. If you have any ideas for the next topic that deals with either ICND1 or ICND2 you can always comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/wireless/tablets-welcomed-won%e2%80%99t-byod-increase-my-device-troubleshooting-costs/&#34;&gt;Tablets Welcomed. Won&#39;t BYOD increase my device troubleshooting costs?&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/&#34;&gt;The Codes of ICMP&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prweb.com/releases/2010/03/prweb3712464.htm&#34;&gt;Ipswitch WhatsUp Gold Receives Network Products Guide 2010 Product Innovation Award in Network Management&lt;/a&gt; (prweb.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Process</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/thinking.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/thinking.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today&#39;s post is going to be talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Troubleshooting&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting&#34;&gt;troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; and where to start the troubleshooting process. Yes there is an actual process that every technician should be aware of. You can also use this troubleshooting process at home, you may not know how to fix it but at least you know where the issue is and find someone who can.  Before we begin if you haven&#39;t seen yet, let me introduce to you the troubleshooting process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to gather information about the problem. (What happened?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep it simple, verify the obvious issues FIRST! (Is the device powered on?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try some quick solutions first (restart, reinstall, verify connections)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gather information from the device (Device Manger, if you are in routers or switches use &amp;quot;Show&amp;quot; commands and &amp;quot;Debug&amp;quot; commands)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your research skills! Evaluate the problem and try possible solutions. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet&#34; title=&#34;Internet&#34;&gt;Internet&lt;/a&gt; searches, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_forum&#34; title=&#34;Internet forum&#34;&gt;Online Forums&lt;/a&gt;, past experiences etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally keep note of what you did even if you did not fix the issue. (Keep an engineer notebook!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may look simple, and it is! This is the exact method I use when troubleshooting a problem. Troubleshooting is a hard skill to have, as you really can&#39;t learn from it in a book. You have to have experience with the type of technology you&#39;re working with. One thing I use all the time is my research skills this can be a life saver if you know what to look for, use key details! The internet can be helpful but putting generic terms like &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_XP&#34; title=&#34;Windows XP&#34;&gt;windows XP&lt;/a&gt; is not working&amp;quot; will not help you but instead waste your time. Use the key terms when have an issue like an error code, type the error message, describe what you can&#39;t do, etc. Chances are somebody somewhere has had the same problem or at least something like it and decided to post it. Another thing I like to do when checking on a problem is going to the source! Although there are helpful places around web like forums, and chat systems I usually use this last. If I am having a problem with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Windows&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Windows&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; for example I&#39;ll go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; Support. Same thing if I have an issue with a Cisco product I&#39;ll go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; Support webpage before I go and search my problem around the web. Finally remember ask other technicians if they have seen the problem. By using these steps and guidelines will be able to become better at troubleshooting like before it&#39;s something you can&#39;t learn from a book you must have experience with technology before you can even start troubleshooting. My last word of advice is keeping a record! Write down the steps you did, why did them and what where the solutions to the problem? If you couldn&#39;t figure it still write it down. That way if the issue occurs again you and other people know exactly how to fix the problem or also know what solutions not work last time and not waste any of your time, like always I hope this information was informative and if you have an idea about the next ICND1 or ICND2 topic comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
