<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VIRL on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/virl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VIRL on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 13:05:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/virl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cisco FTDv in Cisco VIRL</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/06/14/cisco-ftdv-in-cisco-virl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 13:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/06/14/cisco-ftdv-in-cisco-virl/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco is actively pushing their Firepower Threat Defense software with the new Firepower 2100 units on their way this summer in effort to eventually replace the ASA5525-X, ASA5545-X and ASA5555-X platforms. When using FTD you must also have the Firepower Management Center (FMC) available to manage and configure these devices. This gets difficult especially if you want to test things out because not everyone has Cisco Firepower lying around unused. How are you supposed to test and learn the depths of this product?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco VIRL and Windows VMs</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/01/08/cisco-virl-and-windows-vms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 01:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/01/08/cisco-virl-and-windows-vms/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the neat features of Cisco VIRL is it runs on an open platform, with OpenStack as the orchestration program running on top of an Ubuntu operating system. This gives VIRL additional flexibly by being able to run third-party VMs with KVM begin the hypervisor. In this guide I’ll walk through some of the steps I took to get Windows XP up and running in VIRL. :) If you have a more recent version of Windows that&#39;s in the current decade following this guide is pretty much the same just adjust the disk space and RAM to fit the requirements.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco VIRL – Update</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/11/18/cisco-virl-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 13:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/11/18/cisco-virl-update/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco released VIRL almost a year ago and it’s not at the 1.0 version yet but it’s getting close as they have done some good work towards the product since it first lunched. Cisco VIRL is like GNS3 which is simulation platform that runs Cisco’s current operating systems so instead of buying used Cisco hardware you can run this program on your computer. This software is geared towards proof-of-concept designs, for personal and training on Cisco Certifications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco VIRL is out ... for a price</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/12/05/cisco-virl-is-out-...-for-a-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 03:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/12/05/cisco-virl-is-out-...-for-a-price/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just wanted to put this up has Cisco has recently released VIRL. This is a network simulation platform that you can run Cisco operating systems on which are the same operating systems that run on Cisco hardware so anything you do in this simulation environment would be realistic if it was running on dedicated hardware. You would be able to test your changes before throwing them in production. Some things that are different between VIRL and CML (Cisco Modeling Labs)
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Modeling Labs … Waiting</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/06/28/cisco-modeling-labs-waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 20:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/06/28/cisco-modeling-labs-waiting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just waiting for CML, (Cisco Modeling Labs) it’s been little over a month since going to Cisco Live in San Francisco and with all the information of next-generation hardware and security with Source Fire I was pretty beat with a lot of note taking and PowerPoint slides. However the last session on the last day of the Cisco Live talked about Cisco’s Modeling Lab program. I also tried it out in the Cisco DevNet area earlier in the week during Cisco Live and I was impressed with the product.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
