<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MAC address on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/mac-address/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MAC address on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 17:00:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/mac-address/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic Understanding of EtherChannel</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/04/basic-understanding-of-etherchannel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/04/basic-understanding-of-etherchannel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network cables Let&#39;s start the New Year with understanding EtherChannel which is having more than one link connected to a server, switch, or router and treating it like one logical link. This is a fault-tolerant technique that is becoming a common setup in highly available, core devices. Cisco has come up with their own proprietary version call EtherChannel. The open standard that IEEE approved is 802.3ad which works with other venders and is often called LAG for short.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Store-and-Forward vs. Cut-Through Switching</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/05/store-and-forward-vs.-cut-through-switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/05/store-and-forward-vs.-cut-through-switching/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network-Cable-Color Switching in the network can happen in two ways, these layer-two devices send frames but they can forward them in different ways. These different modes have positive and negative effects which depend on the type of network environment that runs through them! Store-and-forward is just like the name suggests, the switch receives a frame on a port and stores the frame in it&#39;s memory buffer until the frame has been completely received.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the month of August I talked about the &amp;quot;beginnings&amp;quot; of layer two redundancy mainly looking at the basic foundations and fundamentals of having layer two redundancy. Let&#39;s continue are discussion about redundancy in the layer two environment. To review what STP does (Spanning Tree Protocol) it works at layer two of the OSI model. If more than one path is available in the network the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until the active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network-diagram In a perfect world we would never need redundancy on a network infrastructure, but as you know as well as I know we don&#39;t live in a perfect world. Hardware will eventually fail, bottlenecks will appear, and the speed of our network will become slower when we max the bandwidth on links. So having redundancy in routers, connections, and having a hierarchy network is one of best choices to make when improving the efficiently of the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VTP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some people hate it, some people love it. It&#39;s the Cisco proprietary VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) which in short means that Cisco switches can exchange VLAN configuration, instead of manually configuring each switch with the same VLANs. I also suggest if you don&#39;t know what a VLAN is check out the post Creating VLANs Let&#39;s get right into understanding VTP. The thing that makes VTP shine is what it does, although simple to understand it saves time by automatically distributing VLAN information.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Port Security</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/31/configuring-port-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/31/configuring-port-security/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure Today this tutorial is going to be talking about how to configure port security on a Cisco Catalyst switch. Port security is one of the first things you can do to keep your network secure from unauthorized access. Port security can restrict devices so only devices you allow are granted access to network resources. If and when an unauthorized device is connected to a port you can decide what you want the switch to do.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collision Domains vs Broadcast Domains</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These different types of domains mean different things and when designing a LAN both of these domains can harm the performance of your network. If you are not aware of the difference between these two, this tutorial should help you out. If you have a small network at your home there is usually the router/modem that is connected via phone line or cable to the ISP that router/modem is then connected to a switch or they even have a switch built into the device.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a Router Routes</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 17:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial will be going over the basic information of how a router routes IP packets. Routers are used in the OSI layer three or the network layer. These routers have IP addresses and forward IP packets to the proper destination. This guide is somewhat basic and is assuming you have some information of how IP addressing works and along with what routing protocols are. So let&#39;s focus first on how a host or a computer forwards traffic and then look at how a router forwards traffic.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cracking WEP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/14/cracking-wep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2011 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/14/cracking-wep/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BackTrack is Linux network security audit tool for security professionals. This tool is used for testing and penetrating networks. That being said** This tutorial is for educational use only. This is meant only to teach that WEP is an insecure option, and is recommend to use a harder encryption. Using this tutorial on a network that you do not have permission to access or is not yours, could be illegal! ** This was tested on BackTrack version 4 and the steps outlined in this tutorial were successful.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
