<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ISM band on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/ism-band/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ISM band on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 15:00:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/ism-band/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>802.11n</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/11/802.11n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/11/802.11n/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On this Monday let&#39;s wrap up the 802.11 wireless standards, Friday I talked about the 802.11g (See the post 802.11g) and before that I talked about the 802.11b (See the post 802.11b ) I also talked about 802.11a, (See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of last week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So let&#39;s end the discussion and talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11g</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/08/802.11g/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/08/802.11g/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well again we are continuing the discussion about the wireless standards. Yesterday I talked about 802.11b (See the post 802.11b), and before that I talked about 802.11a,(See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Standards) So on this Friday let&#39;s talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11b</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/07/802.11b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 17:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/07/802.11b/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off the discussion, todays post will be talking about 802.11b wireless standard that was developed by IEEE. Yesterday&#39;s post we talked about the 802.11a standard. (See the post 802.11a) We also we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I went over some Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So now that we are up to speed lets learn about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11a</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/06/802.11a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/06/802.11a/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing the discussion about wireless standards we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) Today&#39;s post will be talking about the IEEE 802.11a standard. On Monday I talked about the Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post will be going over the second standard 802.11a out of the five standards that make up the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11 - Legacy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/05/802.11-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 15:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/05/802.11-legacy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday we talked about the wireless concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post one of the five standards that make up the 802.11. The 802.11 – Legacy has its called now and is not in use anymore by manufactures and is now obsolete was the first wireless standard available for consumer laptops. When the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
