<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Access control list on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/access-control-list/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Access control list on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 17:46:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/access-control-list/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is the Nexus 1000v?</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2012/03/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 17:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2012/03/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/network_cloud_david_klan_01_svg_med.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/network_cloud_david_klan_01_svg_med.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;network_cloud&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I have worked with the Nexus 1000v product and wanted to share my thoughts on it. I want to explain in this blog what this product is and what it does.  The Nexus 1000v can be virtual or a hardware appliance and is considered to be a virtual switch that runs in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VMware&#34; title=&#34;VMware&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;. The major benefit to this product is the visibly you get when running in a virtual environment. Remember in the virtual environment the network engineer has a cloudy vision of what&#39;s going, because the built-in switch within VMware does not get that technical it just works. This is fine for most people but not all, especially the network technicians we want that visibly and the Nexus 1000v does that and more! The Nexus replaces the built-in switch in VMware and installs a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_machine&#34; title=&#34;Virtual machine&#34;&gt;virtual machine&lt;/a&gt; called the VSM (Virtual Supervisor Module) and depending on the configuration you can have two VSMs for redundancy. These VSMs can be either virtual or a hardware appliance (Nexus 1010) Depending on how many &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VMware_ESX&#34; title=&#34;VMware ESX&#34;&gt;ESX&lt;/a&gt; hosts you have in your environment each of them will have VEM (Virtual Ethernet Module) which are the work horses and provide packet forwarding. The VSMs and VEMs make up a single Nexus 1000v switch, which appears to be a single modular switch to the network technician. Each VSM can have a maximum of 64 VEMs (or 64 physical ESX hosts) It has always been that server administrators deal with the operating system and the applications running on that server. While the network administrators manage the switches and related policies. The link between the server and switch usually a cable separates these roles, until virtual came along and smashed these roles together usually the server administrator has to deal with it. With the Nexus 1000v these roles are now separate in the virtual environment with added functionality like PVLANs, receive rate limiting, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quality_of_service&#34; title=&#34;Quality of service&#34;&gt;QoS&lt;/a&gt;, Access Control Lists (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control_list&#34; title=&#34;Access control list&#34;&gt;ACLs&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DHCP_snooping&#34; title=&#34;DHCP snooping&#34;&gt;DHCP snooping&lt;/a&gt;, SPAN, ERSPAN, AAA, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netflow&#34; title=&#34;Netflow&#34;&gt;NetFlow&lt;/a&gt;, SNMP and many other features that are not available with the VMware vSwitch. Check out this marketing video that summarizes the Nexus 1000v. [youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pgksWMUBmcI] I hope this information is helpful, check back in a couple of weeks or so because I want to go through the process of setting up the Nexus 1000v, understanding some basic terminology of the Nexus 1000v and go over the CLI. Anybody that is familiar with Cisco IOS CLI will find that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NX-OS&#34; title=&#34;NX-OS&#34;&gt;NX-OS&lt;/a&gt; is almost the same. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/datacenter/nexus-1000v-responding-to-scale-requirements-with-10000-ports-per-virtual-switch/&#34;&gt;Nexus 1000V Responding to Scale Requirements with 10,000+ Ports per Virtual Switch&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.co.uk/2012/02/01/cisco_40ge_100ge_switches/&#34;&gt;Cisco Nexus ports stretched to take 40GE and 100GE loads&lt;/a&gt; (go.theregister.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/datacenter/nexus-1000v-updates-bring-scalability-and-cloud-readiness-to-the-network/&#34;&gt;Nexus 1000V Updates Bring Scalability and Cloud Readiness to the Network&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ioshints.info/2012/02/ibm-launched-nexus-1000v-competitor.html&#34;&gt;IBM launched a Nexus 1000V competitor&lt;/a&gt; (ioshints.info)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding CBAC</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/02/understanding-cbac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/02/understanding-cbac/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Although using hardware firewalls are an excellent step forward when securing your network. They can cost money and are not cheap to set up and configure. Using CBAC is built-into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/en/US/products/ps6537/products_ios_sub_category_home.html&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; router and helps filter those unwanted protocols that are in your network. When setting up routers as firewalls you have some choices like using CBAC the &amp;quot;Classic&amp;quot; firewall, or zone based policy (ZBF). Today we will talk about CBAC and how to understand the core components of what make &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context-based_access_control&#34; title=&#34;Context-based access control&#34;&gt;CBAC&lt;/a&gt; possible. CBAC stands for Content-Base-&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control&#34; title=&#34;Access control&#34;&gt;Access-Control&lt;/a&gt; and uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control_list&#34; title=&#34;Access control list&#34;&gt;ACLs&lt;/a&gt;. (Access Control Lists) Unlike the established TCP session and reflexive ACLs CBAC has several advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitors TCP connections, (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transmission_Control_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Transmission Control Protocol&#34;&gt;Three-way handshake&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintains &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_Datagram_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;User Datagram Protocol&#34;&gt;UDP&lt;/a&gt; session information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracks TCP sequence numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspects DNS queries and replies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inspection&#34; title=&#34;Inspection&#34;&gt;Inspect&lt;/a&gt; common &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Control_Message_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Control Message Protocol&#34;&gt;ICMP&lt;/a&gt; messages types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports applications that rely on multiple connections (FTP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspects embedded address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspects &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Application Layer&#34;&gt;Application Layer&lt;/a&gt; information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACLs only look at the network layer and sometimes the transport layer. CBAC is application aware, meaning CBAC is a stateful firewall which keeps track of the state of network connections such as TCP streams, and UDP communication travelling across it. The firewall is programmed to distinguish legitimate packets for different types of connections. Only packets matching a known connection state will be allowed by the firewall; others will be rejected. Because CBAC only matches packets (TCP, UDP and other protocols) it was specified to look at, it will then depend on the ACL if that packet is allowed access or denied. CBAC creates openings in ACLs at the interfaces that inspect the traffic by adding a temporary ACL entry for a specific session. The openings are created when the internal network starts a session with the outside network that would normally be denied. The traffic is only allowed back through the firewall if it is part of the same session and has the correct properties that CBAC is looking for. For example let&#39;s say a user starts an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Session_management&#34; title=&#34;Session management&#34;&gt;http session&lt;/a&gt; in the protected network and the packet moves to the outside or unprotected network. CBAC is configured to inspect http traffic and there is an ACL on the inbound (outside interface) blocking http traffic from the unprotected network to the protected network. So the packet is allowed access to the unprotected network because the ACL is on the inbound interface and not the outbound interface. So the ACL does not look at the packet, CBAC however looks at the packet and in the inspection rules the packet is allowed access to the unprotected network, CBAC adds an entry in its state table. Because a new entry is added a dynamic ACL is created on the external interface to the protected network. This dynamic ACL will allow http traffic back into the protected network. This opening is only active it the session is open, once the session closes the ACL is removed. Once removed any traffic that starts from the unprotected network will be denied access to the protected network. This depends on the ACL which checks inbound connections from the unprotected network.&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/cbac-firewall-config/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/cbac-firewall-config.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;CBAC Firewall&#34; title=&#34;CBAC Firewall-config&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/cbac-firewall-config.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; To configure CBAC there are four steps to set up CBAC efficiently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick an interface of where you want CBAC to be inspecting; this depends on the flow of your network and the amount of interfaces you have installed on your router. (DMZ, Web server, E-mail servers, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure IP ACLs at the interface. The network technician must define what type of traffic is allowed and will not be inspected by CBAC and which traffic is blocked and will be inspected by CBAC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define inspection rules. The network technician should specify each desired application layer to inspect along with generic TCP, ICMP and or UDP fields. Inspection rules are configured by statements each listing a protocol and specifying the inspection rule name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally apply the inspection rule to an interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBAC is considered the &amp;quot;classic&amp;quot; firewall compared to zone based, it is relatively simple to configure and understand. However unlike zone based CBAC can get complex when multiple CBAC configurations on a router exists. Remember CBAC also uses ACLs if configured and implemented poorly these ACLs can block traffic even when CBAC allows them. I hope this tutorial was helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
