<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rancid on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/rancid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rancid on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 02:43:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/rancid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rancid can’t SSH to older ISRs?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/03/03/rancid-cant-ssh-to-older-isrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 02:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/03/03/rancid-cant-ssh-to-older-isrs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well its 2016 and you still have that one-of-kind Cisco ISR 2811 or 3845 running in the environment? You followed and installed Rancid, all the new stuff works like it should but when you try to connect to that “one-of-kind” 2811 with Rancid it closes the connection... :/
This is a simple fix and the bug is reported here: LINK. The bug is something with OpenSSH which is installed on your Linux operating system and Rancid rides on top of it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Rancid</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/02/27/configuring-rancid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/02/27/configuring-rancid/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In my last post I talked about Installing Rancid on Centos 7 so be sure to check that out. In this post we now want to actually use Rancid so I’ll walk through on how to setup Rancid to login into network equipment and get configurations.
To recap: Rancid is a great tool to help monitor a device configuration for any changes. It also keeps track of them by using CVS (Concurrent Version System) for backups, so you can go back and compare versions or revert to a previous configuration.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Rancid and ViewVC on Centos 7</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/01/03/install-rancid-and-viewvc-on-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/01/03/install-rancid-and-viewvc-on-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I want to walk though the steps to install Rancid on CentOS 7 minimal. Rancid is a great tool to help monitor a device configuration for any changes. It also keeps track of them by using CVS (Concurrent Version System) for backups, so you can go back and compare versions or revert to a previous configuration. Rancid supports multiple hardware from Cisco, HP, Dell, Juniper and more. This is all open-source so you can create custom scripts or add commands to really make this a personal repository that fits your company.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
