<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 17:26:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ten Years</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2021/01/03/ten-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 17:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2021/01/03/ten-years/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;A new year, a new plan and a new direction, its been ten years since I started this thing and I have to be honest I loved everything about it. 2020 was crazy... I think were getting close in seeing an ending, but everyone&#39;s life has been affected by this. My work/home life has changed. My priorities have shifted, and because of that this website is going to go static. It&#39;s time for change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is content from 2011 all the way to 2021 on this site. During those years you can tell my writing style has changed and the amount of posts I did throughout the years. The way I introduce topics, I start to get more personal instead of a tutorial style post, all of it a learning experience for me. My original goal for this site was to just to get better at my writing skills. To be able to explain something technical with words and try to keep it easy to understand, which is sometimes impossible with technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I have grown professionally with this site being the backbone of it, in 2011 I graduated college and was hired as a Network Engineer! My first &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; job into a career of opportunities which I took this site along the way. It&#39;s got some history in here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site was also something else for me, during these years my personal life has changed, and to be honest this site was an escape for me, I was ignoring everything around me including questions I didn&#39;t want to answer about myself and my life, it worked for the most part all the way through 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was sitting down on the grass during lunch with a close friend a couple summers ago, I knew this person for three years at the time, and still close friends to this day. Normally we talked about a lot of things in the past but this more, something was different. We talked for hours about life, goals, and relationships. This person opened up to me about the their life, their story, their struggles and it was tipping point for me. I realized right then I had choice to make, I could really open up to this friend like they did to me and tell them my story. Tell them who I am, they would be the first person to know this about me. I could also just ignore it, change the subject and escape into some other topic to talk about it. That spilt-multi-second decision changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, don&#39;t escape into something and not answer the hard questions you&#39;re ignoring. Be proud of who you are, be grateful to the friends, relationships and family that you have, and don&#39;t be afraid if you&#39;re going against the grain. That is what makes all the difference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m planning on continuing to write probably on a different URL but feel free to follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lewiryan&#34;&gt;@lewiryan&lt;/a&gt; or this site as one one day I&#39;ll post something about it! Thank you for reading this and using this site as a reference, it&#39;s truly been wonderful and life growing experience for me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;
It is official this site is now static! Over the past months I have been moving this site to its forever home and I got to say I&#39;m impressed with the static website generator called Hugo! Although it has been a manual process and it&#39;s still ongoing there is going to content that is not been cleaned but I&#39;m getting there and will put out another update! I am so grateful that I did this, Going over each these posts is a reflection for me and a reminder of posts I remember doing, others I don’t at all! Also, during this migration, I have changed some content and tweaked some posts by mostly added photos and a little grammar help along that way. So it&#39;s &amp;quot;technically&amp;quot; not static yet but the foundation is there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site will probably mean more to me than it does for you, but it’s been part of my life and I don&#39;t want to just dump it and forget about it. Read the first 10 years of my adult life, towards the ending a more personal Ryan comes out...and like always I hope this is helpful!&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Always Changing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/08/15/its-always-changing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 19:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/08/15/its-always-changing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Something that I&#39;ve been pondering while working from home and I think everybody is doing this... re-evaluating their priorities. I like to call it the loop, we get so caught into repetition...its our comfort when things are predictable but when something comes along and changes our lives, good or bad we have to adapt to those changes and potentially change our life direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier in January and last year I recognized my personal life had been the status quo for way too long. I talked about &lt;a href=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/2020/01/03/goals/&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/a&gt;. I started to think about where do I see my personal life in five, ten, twenty years from now? What about my professional life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a younger age while I still in high school I knew what my professional life was going to look like. I always loved technology and so I made goal, even though I may not known exactly how I would get there but I jumped feet first into it. Taking college courses in high school in the field that I&#39;m in today. It&#39;s one thing the education system always reminded me, &amp;quot;think about your future, your career&amp;quot;. All important for a teenager to think about but it consumed me...throughout the remaining years in high school and in college its what I was focused on..my professional life, all the while leaving my personal life behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to say that someone shouldn&#39;t be focused on their career and education but I had questions about my personal life that I really didn&#39;t want to figure out while I was in high school or college. I kind of thought while I was focused on my professional life, my personal life would just fall into place. Nine years later I was doing well professionally, one of the reasons I started this blog was to be focused professionally. However my personal life was a nonexistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed like my life was hitting a ceiling and I would only break though if I figured out my personal paradigm. I had choice really, either stay with how things stand and have everything be predictable, or answer those internal questions about myself and be comfortable with the fact that I may not know where this personal life journey may take me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve realized that although I teat my professional and personal life as two different paradigms, those paradigms are revolving around me. What actions in either of them affects me as a person as well as the paradigms themselves. When I look my at professional life I don&#39;t think I&#39;ve hit that ceiling yet, but acknowledgement that someday I will have to answer those questions again... like I did high school and be comfortable with the possibility of not knowing exactly were my professional life journey takes me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We become what we think about&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Earl Nightingale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is always changing and so making adjustments to our paradigms multiple times to re-evaluate our life circumstances is what everyone should be doing throughout their life. Hopefully helping us ask those questions where do I see myself five, ten, twenty years from now? What&#39;s important to me, the people I care about, the people I love? Most of the time you can&#39;t answer these right away, in time having these questions around you make you aware of who you really want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Keeps Turning</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/05/21/the-world-keeps-turning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 15:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/05/21/the-world-keeps-turning/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Well..couple of things have changed these past months that have had a lasting impact on everyone on this earth. A single reminder that we all share a common home on this place, even though we sometimes think were world&#39;s apart from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time I&#39;ve been working from home, and busier then ever making sure the lights stay on. I like to think of myself as a lighthouse keeper or some type of engineer maintaining a spacecraft floating in space sending &amp;quot;pings&amp;quot; waiting for reply... We&#39;ll get a response and when we do, we&#39;ll be ready for the next adventure, we always are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are changing around us, and every change is different depending where you are and who you are. One thing is for sure life events happen to us all the time but I think its important that we step back for a second and self-reflect on them, because that’s when things happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ups and downs personal and professional let these events change you throughout your life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about them, self-reflect on them, it’s these milestones that I believe are so important and ultimately the purpose of life. Let&#39;s take what we&#39;ve learned, continue to learn, pull ourselves and others up because this is the place we call home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2020/08/08/vtis-with-asa/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;VTIs with ASA – Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-08-08 09:41:19&#34;&gt;Aug 6, 2020&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] The World Keeps Turning and we’ll continue to navigate the times as technology plays such a critical piece in making sure communication between people and or systems goes uninterrupted. We as engineers are right in the middle of it… like always I hope this information is helpful, stay calm and carry on! […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed 640-554!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/06/29/passed-640-554/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/06/29/passed-640-554/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Short story, I am proud to say that I passed! I have studied off and on in the beginning of the year but I did set a date to take the exam which was June 28th .As that date was getting closer I buckled down and reviewed the materials again and focused in on some areas that I knew I was weak in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how was the 640-554 exam, what did I use to pass the exam and what exam am I focusing on next?  The 640-554 exam that I took surprised me which left me at the edge of the seat the entire testing period! 8-O There where lot of difficult questions that I would have missed if I hadn’t of re-reviewed the study materials, along with the amount of questions I had to go through to meet the 90 minute deadline, but it was worth it! After I saw my passing score on screen it definitely was a fair score that I received. I did not feel cheated or have any questions that weren’t on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/web/learning/exams/list/iins.html#~Topics&#34; title=&#34;640-554 IINS&#34;&gt;exam topic list&lt;/a&gt;, so I was overall pleased with the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to question that is often asked, what materials did I use to pass the exam?  I used the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Security-640-554-Official-Guide/dp/1587204460/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1372552672&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=ccna+security+640-554+official+cert+guide&#34; title=&#34;CCNA Security 640-554 Official Cert Guide &#34;&gt;CCNA Security 640-554 Official Cert Guide&lt;/a&gt; authored by Keith Barker and Scott Morris which is an excellent study guide. I also used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.cbtnuggets.com/it-training-videos/series/csco_640_554&#34; title=&#34;Cisco CCNA Security 640-554 - Implementing Cisco IOS Network Security (IINS)&#34;&gt;CBT Nugget Series Cisco CCNA Security 640-554&lt;/a&gt; which is also by Keith Barker to at first learn about the material, take some notes on it and then review it in the cert guide by going through the chapters, reviewing the questions that are in the beginning of the chapters, along with using the study material that was included in the book. I also had some lab gear that was helpful in either following along with the CBT videos or just building some test labs. The lab I have follows the one I posted back in September (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/09/07/cisco-lab-setup/&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Lab Setup&#34;&gt;Cisco Lab Setup&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also recently was able to get two more 2960 &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Catalyst&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Catalyst&#34;&gt;Cisco Catalyst&lt;/a&gt; switches. :) So what is my next plan? Not sure I might look at that new &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/&#34; title=&#34;CCNA Data Center&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center&lt;/a&gt; exam which was announced last fall and it also looked like they may have some study material for it, at least for first exam (640-911 DCICN). I might start on the CCNP journey but either way I am still planning on posting on this blog with tutorials, ideas and other stories. I am also happy that I was able to make some changes of the layout and color of this blog, I hope you enjoy the new look and like always I hope this information is helpful and enjoy your summer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2013/03/26/ccna-version-2-0-refresh/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;CCNA Version 2.0 Refresh « Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-07-06 10:00:01&#34;&gt;Jul 6, 2013&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-29 23:14:04&#34;&gt;Jun 6, 2013&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, Good Luck on the CCDA, that is another exam I have been looking at as well. Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22theos888@live.com%22&#34;&gt;just plain ol&#39; Kev&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-30 23:49:02&#34;&gt;Jun 0, 2013&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good job! Glad you are keeping the blog going. Lammle has a new study guide for CCNA data center that just came out. Kevin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22yow@yahoo.com%22&#34;&gt;yow&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-29 20:35:27&#34;&gt;Jun 6, 2013&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;yow! congrats man! I&#39;m gunning for my CCDA also within the year, and let&#39;s hope I get to post something like this too, :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2013/09/30/ccna-2-0-whats-new/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;CCNA 2.0 What’s New? « Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-09-30 18:35:05&#34;&gt;Sep 1, 2013&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICND2 - Passed!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 16:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;So I just passed my ICND2 &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_%28assessment%29&#34; title=&#34;Test (assessment)&#34;&gt;exam&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;m now &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CCNA&#34; title=&#34;CCNA&#34;&gt;CCNA&lt;/a&gt; certified!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a long road to travel over a year ago I passed &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interconnecting_Cisco_Networking_Devices_Part_1&#34; title=&#34;Interconnecting Cisco Networking Devices Part 1&#34;&gt;ICND1&lt;/a&gt; which I recived the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Certified_Entry_Networking_Technician&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician&#34;&gt;CCENT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Certification&#34; title=&#34;Certification&#34;&gt;certification&lt;/a&gt; but with just general life getting in the way I also saw my chance of getting CCNA status stepping further in the distance. If you read how I passed ICND1 will find that the way I studied for this exam was totally different from studying for the ICND1.  When I finished the ICND2 exam I saw my score and I was proud that I passed but I knew I could have done better but I don&#39;t think I would&#39;ve. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had this exam on my chest for over a year and it drag the matierial became boring and started to dry out because of the consent stop and go style of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Study_skills&#34; title=&#34;Study skills&#34;&gt;studying&lt;/a&gt;. (Don&#39;t do THIS!) This type of studying was going on for months until I decided to go with it because I was tired of relearning it. I studied for the upcomming exam about three weeks ago and on average was about eight hours a week. The book I used was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/ICND2-640-816-Official-Guide-Edition/dp/1587204355/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1337044210&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; title=&#34;CCNA ICND2 640-816 Official Cert Guide (3rd Edition)&#34;&gt;CCNA ICND2 640-816 Official Cert Guide by Wendell Odom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So how did I study for the exam -&lt;/strong&gt;
Well I studied alone for this one, unlike my ICND1 exam. (That was 50 percent of the battle) The other half of it was I had this exam on my chest for a long time. I would also read the material over and over. Yet I would not take the test because of other issues that would come up. I finally said that I am going to schedule this test and take it no matter if I am ready or not, or I would just keep delaying it. In the ICND1 post I made last year make sure you know the material, you can&#39;t guess at this stuff! You have to know it inside and out. If it is multiple choice I always look at the answers first before reading the question. I looked over the book the night before the exam date and really was asking myself questions that I could see on the exam, like the default AD distance of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Shortest_Path_First&#34; title=&#34;Open Shortest Path First&#34;&gt;OSPF&lt;/a&gt; is?, Use &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classless_Inter-Domain_Routing&#34; title=&#34;Classless Inter-Domain Routing&#34;&gt;VLSM&lt;/a&gt; to break this network down so it doesn&#39;t waste addresses, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long did it take? -&lt;/strong&gt;
I originally started studying for the exam in April of 2011 so it took over a year for me to take this test. Don&#39;t let that scare you, I could have probably taken it in 4 months or so but could not find the time, and life in general. However I passed, which shows that if you keep going for it you will get where you want to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test Date -&lt;/strong&gt;
So when I scheduled the test I also scheduled it on my birthday, not sure why I did maybe I felt lucky :). I felt pretty good when I started the exam but that soon changed for the worse. Let&#39;s just say I took the &amp;quot;I&#39;ll study what I think I need&amp;quot; approach. Which worked for me but if you are new to this field I would study everything. Although I passed I was nervous because I spent too much time thinking over the questions and simulations and at the end I had 2 minutes to spare when I finished the exam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To close for comfort! Make a discussion and move on don&#39;t over think it. Looking back at my post &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/&#34; title=&#34;How I passed the ICND1 Exam&#34;&gt;How I passed the ICND1 exam&lt;/a&gt; I can still say that you need to fully understand how to set up routers and switches and just a general concept of the idea. I really think one of the main reasons I passed was that I fully understood the concepts which for the most part is in the ICND1 exam. Taking the two-part exam help me because it focused on key areas of what to study. I think my next certification I&#39;m looking at is CCNA Security but I&#39;m not sure yet and I&#39;m taking a break first. :) Like always I hope this information is helpful and If you are going for your CCNA I wish you the best because I love the that feeling when you pass, because you know it was totally worth it!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://networkingnerd.net/2012/05/14/so-long-to-the-ccip/&#34;&gt;So Long To The CCIP&lt;/a&gt; (networkingnerd.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/21/hdlc-vs-ppp/&#34;&gt;HDLC vs. PPP&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/&#34;&gt;Part 2 - The Joys of Subnetttting - VLSM!&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;CCNA Security – 640-554 | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-05-28 11:23:44&#34;&gt;May 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-05-21 13:29:37&#34;&gt;May 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Kane, No I don&#39;t have an e-mail address for this site yet, but you can to continue to comment. What&#39;s your question? Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-09-22 15:20:00&#34;&gt;Sep 6, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Darwin, To be honest the Cisco Academy is what really got me hooked into this stuff. If you can afford it I would go for it. They provided the equipment, practice exams and labs along with access to Packet Tracer which is an awesome simulation tool that beats getting real equipment in the CCNA level. What is also nice is once you leave the Academy you still have access to it. The difference with me is I waited too long after I finished the Academy to feel comfortable taking the test although I still knew this stuff I needed a review and it helped that I took the Academy. Don’t take too long after you finish the Academy to take the test... I wish you luck :) Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/dar0d&#34; title=&#34;dar0d@twitter.example.com&#34;&gt;Darwin Rodriguez (@dar0d)&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-09-22 09:52:52&#34;&gt;Sep 6, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am in the Cisco Academy right now, CCNA semester 2. Since it took you a year to get ready for the CCNA and passed it studying on your own, do you think it is worth to go to the Cisco Academy? I am thinking in studying it on my own and save some bucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22Kan3@hushmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Kane&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-05-20 12:34:47&#34;&gt;May 0, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats dude. Is there anyway to email / contact you? Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22fahdsuleman@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;namelessone&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-10-09 07:36:58&#34;&gt;Oct 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;does the icnd 2 exam recertify your icnd 1? i did my icnd 1 over 2 years ago and am now getting around to icnd 2 - will it recertify my icnd 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-10-09 18:22:34&#34;&gt;Oct 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Namelessone, Yes it will. If you already have your ICND1 and you pass your ICND2 it will renew your ICND1 and also give you CCNA status. :) Going to Cisco&#39;s website also helps for more information: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/web/learning/le3/learning_career_certifications_and_learning_paths_home.html&#34; title=&#34;IT Certification and Career Paths&#34;&gt;IT Certification and Career Paths&lt;/a&gt; Goodluck, Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I passed the ICND1 Exam</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Well my first of the many &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Career_Certifications&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Career Certifications&#34;&gt;Cisco certifications&lt;/a&gt; that I plan take in the future was a success! I was able to pass the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interconnecting_Cisco_Networking_Devices_Part_1&#34; title=&#34;Interconnecting Cisco Networking Devices Part 1&#34;&gt;ICND1&lt;/a&gt; exam. This blog post is going to be a little different in that I want to share how I was able to pass this test and talk about my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well in January after finishing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Networking_Academy&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Networking Academy&#34;&gt;Cisco Networking Academy&lt;/a&gt; in the Exploration series I wanted to go ahead and take shot at the ICND1 exam. Now I knew that this was not going to be easy, by looking at online sites like CLN (Cisco Learning Network) and reading the horror stories of people missing by one point, having a hard time &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Understanding&#34; title=&#34;Understanding&#34;&gt;understanding&lt;/a&gt; the material, not fully prepared, etc. But also reading success stories about how people passed and what they did to pass, really made me jump on the opportunity. Another thing that made me want to try it was the discounted price I was able to get, by going into the Cisco Networking Academy and doing fairly well I was able to apply for a voucher, which helped that determination I had when &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Study_skills&#34; title=&#34;Study skills&#34;&gt;studying&lt;/a&gt; for the ICND1 exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what did I do to pass this this exam?&lt;/strong&gt; 
Well although I finished the Cisco Networking Academy I needed to review the fundamental topics again. So I bought the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Official-Certification-Library-640-802-Containing/dp/1587201836/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1300551785&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;CCNA Official Exam Certification Library (Exam 640-802), Third Edition (Containing ICND1 and ICND2 Second Edition Exam Certification Guides)&lt;/a&gt; I wanted something that really covered it all in one book, and I am very pleased that I went ahead and got it. But reading a book I don&#39;t think cuts it, you need to fully understand how to set up routers, and switches. That&#39;s where either packet tracer or access to physical equipment comes in. Since I am part of the Cisco Networking Academy I had access to physical and simulation software that I could use. One thing I can agree on is with Cisco &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_%28assessment%29&#34; title=&#34;Test (assessment)&#34;&gt;exams&lt;/a&gt; you want to make sure that you know how a set of commands work and know what they do and when to apply them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So how did I study and how long did it take me to study?&lt;/strong&gt;
Well at first I wanted to study alone I felt that I could get more done. However if possible I would suggest finding a friend that also wants to get certified or at least someone who you can teach the material to. I think I learned a lot more and having discussions with each other and it helped both of us understand the material. For the ICND1 exam it took three months of us studying and preparing for the exam. We mainly used the book from Wendell Odom and did some web searches for ICND1 practice questions. Another thing that helped me was joining the Cisco Learning Network. By asking and answering questions on the discussion pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can I pass the ICND1 exam?&lt;/strong&gt;
Make sure you know the material. Its sounds simple but when I was taking the exam the questions I was given were questions that I would&#39;ve failed if I hadn&#39;t went over the book, online practice questions, and discussions. I felt confident in my answers, I was not second guessing myself and I knew the material inside and out. Another thing I did before taking the exam was go over the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/web/learning/le3/current_exams/640-822.html&#34;&gt;ICND1 exam topics.&lt;/a&gt; I made sure I could explain every topic that was listed.
 
In the end it shows as at the end of the exam I received an excellent score! Having said that there is always someone who wants the easy route and one thing I can say that &lt;strong&gt;won&#39;t&lt;/strong&gt; help you is a thing called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brain_dump&#34; title=&#34;Brain dump&#34;&gt;brain dumps&lt;/a&gt;. Which are questions that a person would memorize and some if not all are taken from the official exams. In addition you are violating the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-disclosure_agreement&#34; title=&#34;Non-disclosure agreement&#34;&gt;non-disclosure agreements&lt;/a&gt;. I don&#39;t understand why people would do this type of thing. To me it sounds like more work than to really just understand the material. It degrades the certification and really does not help anyone. So my advice is don&#39;t pay that amount of money because usually they are about has much as the official exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is my first time taking the exam what can I expect?&lt;/strong&gt;
Like you I was nervous so nervous, I reviewed and reviewed and went over everything again and again. I would agree to this which is you are battling with yourself. Relaxing is important and one thing I like when taking the Cisco exams is you start with a tutorial, I think this helps you get into the mode and you start to calm down. You have about 15 minutes to just breathe and get ready to take the exam and don&#39;t over think it! Simple questions usually want a simple answer. Although test taking tips help you have to know the material in the end to pass, you can&#39;t guess at this stuff. Set a goal and take the exam. Looking back I&#39;m glad I did. It showed that I&#39;m in right the career path and shows to employers that I know the material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&#39;s next well I&#39;m taking a break this week, and will start again next week with some more Cisco information and tutorials. I&#39;m also going to start reviewing the ICND2 exam soon and currently I&#39;m estimating that this one will take longer than three months. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
