<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 17:26:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ten Years</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2021/01/03/ten-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 17:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2021/01/03/ten-years/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new year, a new plan and a new direction, its been ten years since I started this thing and I have to be honest I loved everything about it. 2020 was crazy... I think were getting close in seeing an ending, but everyone&#39;s life has been affected by this. My work/home life has changed. My priorities have shifted, and because of that this website is going to go static for a while with an unknown date of return.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Always Changing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/08/15/its-always-changing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 19:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/08/15/its-always-changing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Something that I&#39;ve been pondering while working from home and I think everybody is doing this... re-evaluating their priorities. I like to call it the loop, we get so caught into repetition...its our comfort when things are predictable but when something comes along and changes our lives, good or bad we have to adapt to those changes and potentially change our life direction.
Earlier in January and last year I recognized my personal life had been the status quo for way too long.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Keeps Turning</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/05/21/the-world-keeps-turning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 15:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/05/21/the-world-keeps-turning/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well..couple of things have changed these past months that have had a lasting impact on everyone on this earth. A single reminder that we all share a common home on this place, even though we sometimes think were world&#39;s apart from each other.
During this time I&#39;ve been working from home, and busier then ever making sure the lights stay on. I like to think of myself as a lighthouse keeper or some type of engineer maintaining a spacecraft floating in space sending &amp;quot;pings&amp;quot; waiting for reply.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed 640-554!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/06/29/passed-640-554/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/06/29/passed-640-554/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Short story, I am proud to say that I passed! I have studied off and on in the beginning of the year but I did set a date to take the exam which was June 28th .As that date was getting closer I buckled down and reviewed the materials again and focused in on some areas that I knew I was weak in.
So how was the 640-554 exam, what did I use to pass the exam and what exam am I focusing on next?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICND2 - Passed!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 16:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I just passed my ICND2 exam, I&#39;m now CCNA certified!
This was a long road to travel over a year ago I passed ICND1 which I recived the CCENT certification but with just general life getting in the way I also saw my chance of getting CCNA status stepping further in the distance. If you read how I passed ICND1 will find that the way I studied for this exam was totally different from studying for the ICND1.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I passed the ICND1 Exam</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well my first of the many Cisco certifications that I plan take in the future was a success! I was able to pass the ICND1 exam. This blog post is going to be a little different in that I want to share how I was able to pass this test and talk about my experience.
Well in January after finishing the Cisco Networking Academy in the Exploration series I wanted to go ahead and take shot at the ICND1 exam.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
