<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Link Layer on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/data-link-layer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Link Layer on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 15:10:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/data-link-layer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure SSH on Dell Power-Connect</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/10/how-to-configure-ssh-on-dell-power-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 15:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/10/how-to-configure-ssh-on-dell-power-connect/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/keys.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/keys.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;keys&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Although not dealing with Cisco directly Dell switches are around in network closets and with my limited experience with them I thought this would be a perfect blog post to show the differences between Dell and Cisco. I like to think of Dell CLI like a dumb downed version of the Cisco CLI so I had some time to play around with a Dell 6248P switch and wanted to figure out how to get SSH working in the thing. Couple searches around the web and some guess and check methods I was able to get SSH working and disable telnet sessions from connecting to the switch. Compared to a Cisco switch dell has few commands when configuring SSH. This switch was configured with an IP address and user name and passwords before I touched it but I don&#39;t think would too hard to figure out. :) So if you never touched a Dell switch like I have but worked with Cisco CLI you&#39;ll find that it is similar which is nice feature, I used telnet to remote into the switch which is insecure and sends information in plain text, which is why we are moving to SSH. So after typing the username and password I was prompted a familiar sign. I typed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;enable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to get into privilege EXEC mode. [code]EdgeSW0D&amp;gt;enable[/code] From there I found a command that will display your public keys on the device that is if you have any. The command was &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;show crypto key mypubkey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Notice how no keys have been configured yet) [code]EdgeSW0D#show crypto key mypubkey RSA Key is not Generated yet ! DSA Key is not Generated yet ![/code] From privilege EXEC mode I typed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;configure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the prompt, once I was in there I found the crypto command and generated some DSA keys with the following command: **&lt;em&gt;crypto key generate dsa&lt;/em&gt; ** [code]EdgeSW0D#configure EdgeSW0D(config)#crypto key generate dsa DSA key generation started, this may take a few minutes................ DSA key generation complete.[/code] Under the configuration mode I also noticed the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ip ssh server&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; command but once I hit enter I got the following error: [code]EdgeSW0D(config)#ip ssh server SSH could not be enabled.[/code] It took me awhile to figure this issue out, I played around with a another Dell switch and at least to what I found out online and my guess and check methods I noticed that the command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ip ssh server&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; works only when both DSA and RSA keys are configured. It does not matter that order as long as switch has both of them and the version of the Dell switch I used when writing post this was the latest version 3.3. Once I created RSA keys with the already created DSA keys the command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ip ssh server&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; went through. To create RSA keys it is the same command but substitute DSA with RSA. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;crypto key generate rsa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [code]EdgeSW0D(config)#crypto key generate rsa RSA key generation started, this may take a few minutes..... RSA key generation complete. EdgeSW0D(config)#ip ssh server[/code] Go ahead and leave the telnet session open and connect to the switch via SSH to verify SSH is working so you don&#39;t lock yourself out. I issued the command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;show sessions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to see that I have two sessions with this switch Telnet and SSH. [code]EdgeSW0D#show sessions Connection Host Address Port ---------- ----------------------- ----------------------- ----------- 0 172.27.227.67 172.27.227.67 Telnet 1 172.27.227.67 172.27.227.67 SSH [/code] Once I verified that SSH is working I can disable telnet so only SSH connections are allowed and accepted, with the following command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ip telnet server disable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. [code]EdgeSW0D#configure EdgeSW0D(config)#ip telnet server disable[/code] That&#39;s it! If you want a refresh on how Cisco does it check the blog post I posted back in March &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/29/configuring-ssh/&#34; title=&#34;Configuring SSH&#34;&gt;Configuring SSH&lt;/a&gt;. Like always I hope this information is helpful and if you have an idea of the next topic let me know by posting below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pauldotcom.com/2011/08/how-a-week-old-privilege-escal.html&#34;&gt;What do you mean privilege escalation is not HIGH RISK?&lt;/a&gt; (pauldotcom.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tychoish.com/rhizome/9-awesome-ssh-tricks/&#34;&gt;9 Awesome SSH Tricks&lt;/a&gt; (tychoish.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://moocode.com/posts/5-simple-two-factor-ssh-authentication&#34;&gt;Simple Two-Factor SSH Authentication&lt;/a&gt; (moocode.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symkat.com/ssh-tips-and-tricks-you-need&#34;&gt;imabonehead: Symkat - SSH: Tips And Tricks You Need&lt;/a&gt; (symkat.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/09/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/09/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In the month of August I talked about the &amp;quot;beginnings&amp;quot; of layer two &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Redundancy_%28engineering%29&#34; title=&#34;Redundancy (engineering)&#34;&gt;redundancy&lt;/a&gt; mainly looking at the basic foundations and fundamentals of having layer two redundancy. Let&#39;s continue are discussion about redundancy in the layer two environment. To review what STP does (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanning_Tree_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Spanning Tree Protocol&#34;&gt;Spanning Tree Protocol&lt;/a&gt;) it works at layer two of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt;. If more than one path is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Network Layer&#34;&gt;network&lt;/a&gt; the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until the active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.) So although there are multiple links connected physically to offer redundancy, logically the switches in the network only see one path that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethernet_frame&#34; title=&#34;Ethernet frame&#34;&gt;Ethernet frame&lt;/a&gt; can travel. Remember without STP networks would be on the fritz when we introduce redundancy in the environment. STP or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IEEE_802.1D&#34; title=&#34;IEEE 802.1D&#34;&gt;IEEE 802.1D&lt;/a&gt; is an open standard so it is not just on Cisco equipment but others as well which helps in a multivendor situation. So how does looping occur without the use STP? Looking at the picture below we can see the broadcasts frames are flooding the network which is by design but the thing that changes is these broadcasts will continue to flood the network because there is on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_to_live&#34; title=&#34;Time to live&#34;&gt;TTL&lt;/a&gt; (Time-To-Live) on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Link_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Data Link Layer&#34;&gt;data link layer&lt;/a&gt; of the OSI model. As more packets are passed and created the network will become slower and slower and eventually devices on the network will become unavailable this called a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcast_radiation&#34; title=&#34;Broadcast radiation&#34;&gt;broadcast storm&lt;/a&gt;. [caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1534&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;584&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;STP Loop Example (Broadcast Storm)&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/stpfl.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/stpfl.png&#34; alt=&#34;An example of an STP loop&#34; title=&#34;STP Loop&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] There are also more problems when not using STP besides broadcast storms like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MAC_address&#34; title=&#34;MAC address&#34;&gt;MAC address&lt;/a&gt; table becoming unstable in each switch. This causes the MAC table to be unreliable because of the looping frames in the network. These frames are usually sent to the wrong locations in the network. Multiple frames can also be a problem because of looping frames multiple frames appear on the network and if they are delivered to the intended host it can confuse the host and more likly drop the frames. So looking at the same picture but with STP enabled we can see that broadcast frame will travel the network without looping. On S1 one of the ports is in a blocking state and blocks all traffic coming into that port and traffic coming out of that port. [caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1539&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;584&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;STP Enabled&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/stp-enable/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/stp-enable.png&#34; alt=&#34;STP Enabled&#34; title=&#34;STP Enable&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] The magic about STP is when the link between S2 and S3 becomes disconnected it will bring the link between S2 and S1 online and continue to send packets! When the link becomes available again it switch back to blocking on S1. So let&#39;s stop there for now and check back next week to see the last chapter of STP, how does it calculate which switch goes to blocking? What other advantages does STP offer? That&#39;s all next week, I hope this information is helpful and if you have an idea of the next topic that deals with either ICND1 or ICND2 let me hear it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/&#34;&gt;The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.co.uk/2011/08/03/network_resiliency/&#34;&gt;Belt and braces stop the network falling down&lt;/a&gt; (go.theregister.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.avaya.com/blogs/archives/2011/08/resiliency-and-redundancy---not-the-same.html&#34;&gt;Resiliency and Redundancy - NOT the same&lt;/a&gt; (avaya.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techbookshelf.com/2011/08/31/cisco-nexus-vpc-configuration-and-spanning-tree-elimination/&#34;&gt;Cisco Nexus vPC Configuration and Spanning-Tree Elimination&lt;/a&gt; (techbookshelf.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-07 18:51:46&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve do you have any questions? Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Steve]( &#34;svu@uppertraining.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-07 12:27:32&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome Site. Ryan can you please contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Welcome CCT (Cisco Certified Technician Certification) | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/21/welcome-cct-cisco-certified-technician/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-21 20:44:38&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[The “Ending” of Layer Two Redundancy | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/14/the-%e2%80%9cending%e2%80%9d-of-layer-two-redundancy/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-14 11:17:26&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Store-and-Forward vs. Cut-Through Switching | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/05/store-and-forward-vs-cut-through-switching/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-10-05 10:16:16&#34;&gt;Oct 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/08/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/08/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/network-diagram.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/network-diagram.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;network-diagram&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In a perfect world we would never need redundancy on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Network Layer&#34;&gt;network&lt;/a&gt; infrastructure, but as you know as well as I know we don&#39;t live in a perfect world. Hardware will eventually fail, bottlenecks will appear, and the speed of our network will become slower when we max the bandwidth on links. So having redundancy in routers, connections, and having a hierarchy network is one of best choices to make when improving the efficiently of the network. But in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt; there is one layer that can&#39;t have redundancy at least logically and that is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstraction_layer&#34; title=&#34;Abstraction layer&#34;&gt;Layer&lt;/a&gt; two of the OSI model. If you follow this blog way back when I talked about the OSI model, layer two belongs to the switches and by design the ethernet frame does not support a TTL (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_to_live&#34; title=&#34;Time to live&#34;&gt;Time-To-Live&lt;/a&gt;) like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Protocol&#34;&gt;IP packet&lt;/a&gt;. So bring forth STP, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanning_Tree_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Spanning Tree Protocol&#34;&gt;Spanning Tree Protocol&lt;/a&gt; which works at layer two of the OSI model. If more than one path is available in the network the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.) So although there are multiple links connected physically to offer redundancy, logically the switches in the network only see one path that ethernet frame can travel. &lt;strong&gt;Your Thought:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait...I have plugged into multiple Cisco switches before to create a redundant path and I did not notice anything wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s because by default STP is enabled, to the average person they can plug away and create redundant paths with switches and cause no harm to the network. But if STP has been disabled on those switches or switches that don&#39;t support STP (dumb switches), a Layer 2 loop can occur. A Layer 2 loop is a nightmare if this happens in a production network and can happen in seconds. Loops result in high &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_processing_unit&#34; title=&#34;Central processing unit&#34;&gt;CPU&lt;/a&gt; load on all switches caught in the loop. Because the same frames are constantly being forwarded back and forth between all switches in the loop, the CPU of the switch ends up having to process a lot of data. This slows down performance on the switch when legitimate traffic arrives.  A host caught in a network loop is not accessible to other hosts on the network. Because the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MAC_address&#34; title=&#34;MAC address&#34;&gt;MAC address&lt;/a&gt; table is constantly changing with the updates from the broadcast frames, the switch does not know which port to send the unicast frames out to reach the destination. The unicast frames end up looping around the network as well. As more and more frames end up looping on the network, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcast_radiation&#34; title=&#34;Broadcast radiation&#34;&gt;broadcast storm&lt;/a&gt; occurs. What makes this even more fun is if you try connecting to the switches to solve this problem, good luck :). Most of the time you have to physically turn off the switches to kill the broadcast storm and if it happened once expect it to happen again. To make things worse if any end-devices are connected to the switch ports that are experiencing a broadcast storm they too have a hard time keeping up with the mountain of broadcast frames being sent and sometimes malfunction. Usually you would have to disconnect the switch from the redundant links and apply STP to it and then re-connect the redundant links in order for your network to be broadcast storm free. Although I&#39;m just getting started I think by just introducing this topic will help you better understand it later, I will get into more of this STP magic and how this really helps us design a hierarchy network. Like always I hope this information was informative and if you can&#39;t wait a simple search about STP will help. You can also go right to the source for more STP information at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; Support and Documentation. Have an idea of the next topic either ICND1 or ICND2 let me know about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/smallbusiness/get-data-to-its-destination-faster/&#34;&gt;Get Data to Its Destination Faster&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/17/the-osi-layer/&#34; title=&#34;The OSI Layer&#34;&gt;The OSI Layer&lt;/a&gt;  (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.co.uk/2011/06/16/network_tuning/&#34;&gt;When tuning the server, don&#39;t forget the network&lt;/a&gt; (go.theregister.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-07 12:08:56&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
