<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>640-911 on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/640-911/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 640-911 on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 01:55:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/640-911/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Passed the 640-911 DCICN</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/05/14/passed-the-640-911-dcicn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 01:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/05/14/passed-the-640-911-dcicn/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco started this exam back in 2012 and I have thought/semi-studied about this test for about over a year now, just did not feel comfy about it until recently. I took the test last week and passed, however there were some questions on the exam I noticed that weren&#39;t on the exam blueprint so that kind of surprised me. I was happy to still be able to pass the exam but I was caught off guard.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Hexadecimal to Decimal and Binary</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/04/22/converting-hexadecimal-to-decimal-and-binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 02:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/04/22/converting-hexadecimal-to-decimal-and-binary/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The purpose of this post is to reference the CCNA Data Center (640-911) exam. This exam starts the conversation of IPv6 and since IPv6 is hexadecimal this post starts the talk about how we look at a hexadecimal values and learn how to convert them to binary and decimal. If you know subnetting skills then this won’t be that difficult. If you are new then check out The Wonders of Binary post as well as Part 1 and Part 2 of subnetting.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 10 &amp; 11)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 01:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just like before if you have followed, I have gone over the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle and in this post we cover two chapters. Feel free to comment below if you have any questions on either of these two chapters.
Chapter 10 Overview: Chapter 10 starts us back in the book, before we do any configuring and we learn about routing protocols, and remember the difference between static and dynamic routing (name implies it) Also know the default administrate distances of the different routing protocols (starts on page 297).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 7)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you made it past the earlier chapters this one should be interesting, like before I am going through each chapter of the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Comment below if you have questions in this chapter, last week we learned about subnetting and in this chapter we will learn about the NX-OS which is Cisco&#39;s Data Center switches. Let&#39;s begin! Overview: This was short chapter in introducing the NX-OS product line and into the virtualized enviroments that data centers are now becoming.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 6)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/20/640-911-chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 19:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/20/640-911-chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s start chapter six of the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle, feel free to post questions if you have any. Like before I have covered the topics of the each chapter. Last week we learned about the different IP classes and today we get a course in subnetting. Let&#39;s go over what you should know if you want to pass the exam.
Overview: It seems I have talked subnetting to death on this blog, repetition, repetition, repetition.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 5)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 19:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last week we covered chapter four which talked about the TCP/IP and the DoD models and what role they cover in networking as we learned that every application like FTP, DNS, DHCP depend on it. Like always post questions if you have any about the book CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I&#39;ll continue to cover topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 4)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 18:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off on Chapter 3 on CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Like before feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter three we discussed about Ethernet Technologies and in chapter four we will learn about the TCP/IP protocol which is fundamentally the protocol that makes the Internet work.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 2)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 19:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am continuing the ongoing of series of blog posts that follow the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I figured that this type of post would help me and anybody else looking at studying for the exam. Feel free to post questions below as if on a study group, In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 1)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/16/640-911-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 17:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/16/640-911-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I bought the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I have decided it would be a good idea to go over the topics of each chapter of this book in series of blog posts. The idea of this is to work together if on a study group, go over the topics in each chapter of the book, talk about examples and to get an idea of what the exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
