<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>640-916 on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/640-916/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 640-916 on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 12:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/640-916/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Passed the 640-916 DCICT</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/08/passed-the-640-916-dcict/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/08/passed-the-640-916-dcict/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a little more than year in the making since I passed my last Cisco exam the 640-911 but I finally did it and passed the 640-916. I can now call myself CCNA Data Center Certified. :) If you ever get the chance to take go up Data Center route it really is interesting of all the products and services Cisco has in their portfolio. Cisco UCS, OTV, Fabicpath and FCoE are just really cool technologies to learn about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main studying tool I used was the Cisco Official Certification Guide and I poked around the Cisco Learning Network on the Data Center study group. So what&#39;s next for me? Well I think its time to take another step forward and climb up to the professional level of Cisco Certifications. I don&#39;t know when I want to start that but it&#39;ll probably be sooner rather than later. It&#39;s been a little more than five years of when I passed my first Cisco certification. After finishing the Cisco Network Academy I was able to tackle the ICND1 and looking back at the ICND1 its changed curriculum twice since I took it, which is a common theme in this industry. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22later@me.com%22&#34;&gt;Rohit&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-09-06 06:04:06&#34;&gt;Sep 2, 2016&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;congratulations Ryan !!! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
