<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wi-Fi on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/wi-fi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wi-Fi on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 15:15:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/wi-fi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Super WiFi</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/29/welcome-super-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 15:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/29/welcome-super-wifi/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WiFi_Logo Wow July is almost over and I only posted one topic! Before August comes up I wanted to post at least one more topic which deals with the wireless side of the networking world. Ever heard of Super WiFi? The IEEE has published this standard recently its official number is 802.22. What does Super WiFi bring to the table compared to other WiFi Standards? Well according to IEEE these speeds can bring up to 22Mbps to devices as far has 62 miles!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11a</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/06/802.11a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/06/802.11a/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing the discussion about wireless standards we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) Today&#39;s post will be talking about the IEEE 802.11a standard. On Monday I talked about the Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post will be going over the second standard 802.11a out of the five standards that make up the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cracking WEP</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/14/cracking-wep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2011 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/14/cracking-wep/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BackTrack is Linux network security audit tool for security professionals. This tool is used for testing and penetrating networks. That being said** This tutorial is for educational use only. This is meant only to teach that WEP is an insecure option, and is recommend to use a harder encryption. Using this tutorial on a network that you do not have permission to access or is not yours, could be illegal! ** This was tested on BackTrack version 4 and the steps outlined in this tutorial were successful.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11ac Standard</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/21/802.11ac-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 18:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/21/802.11ac-standard/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some things are making news in the wireless world, the IEEE wants another wireless standard in the mix called the 802.11ac, now the fastest standard they have is the 802.11n(speeds up to 300 Mbps), which was recently published in October of 2009. What is so great about the 802.11ac development? Well one thing is the speed, it is estimated that it will be able to carry up to 1 gigabit per second!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
