<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LAN on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/lan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LAN on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 13:15:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/lan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Private VLANs</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2018/01/09/private-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 13:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2018/01/09/private-vlans/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s start out 2018 with private VLANs, with PVLANs the network gets a little more privacy added to it. When we have privacy on the network we can seclude certain parts of it. Essentially, &amp;quot;you can go about your business - move along, move along&amp;quot;. Private VLANs allow us to segment networks within a single VLAN. So in this post we&#39;ll go over the types of PVLANs as well as setup a network topology with private VLANs, Let&#39;s get started!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLAN Access Lists (VACLs)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2017/11/20/vlan-access-lists-vacls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2017/11/20/vlan-access-lists-vacls/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VACLs are another good layer of security to help control who can talk to who, much like access control lists that are in firewalls and routers, however the difference is VACLs operate at layer two of the OSI model. There could be situations where you have multiple hosts on the same LAN and want to block traffic from reaching certain hosts within that same network, how would you go about blocking that type of traffic without using a router or firewall?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLBP Load Balancing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2017/08/17/glbp-load-balancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 14:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2017/08/17/glbp-load-balancing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We could use HSRP or VRRP to have a redundant default gateway for our PC/server networks. Although this works well we now have hardware powered-on and just sitting around waiting for its counterpart to fail, we are not actively using it. We could split up networks or use multiple default gateways within the same network but who does that? Well if your router or layer three switch happens to have that Cisco logo on it and a software release of at least 12.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Routing Protocols</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 16:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dynamic Routing If you ever wanted to set up a network manually, you will quickly find how much overhead is required to get PCs, printers, and other network equipment. That&#39;s where dynamic routing protocols come into play although they are helpful I strongly urge you to understand static routing first. (See the post Configure Static Routing) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s get the foundation of understanding dynamic routing protocols. By definition a routing protocol is a set of messages, rules and algorithms used by routers for the overall purpose of learning routes to other networks not physically connected to it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Static Routing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plugging Cisco routers together and hoping they work out of the box is not something you should hope for. A router can learn about networks in two ways, manually from configured static routers which we will talk about today and dynamic routing protocols which will talk about on Wednesday. Let&#39;s get started! Static routes are not that uncommon they at first need some attention to get set up but after it is working nothing needs to change.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
