<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ICND1 on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/icnd1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ICND1 on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 12:15:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/icnd1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up GNS3 1.1 on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/10/28/setting-up-gns3-1.1-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 12:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/10/28/setting-up-gns3-1.1-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s only been a week since GNS3 1.0 was released and it&#39;s already been updated to 1.1 so in this post I have Ubuntu 14.04 LTS with the latest updates and its time to set up GNS3. GNS3 is an open source tool that helps network professionals run a virtual network right on their computer, GNS3 is not a simulation program but rather an emulation program. So if you wanted to test a configuration change but did not want to run it on production you can run it in GNS3 instead.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 01:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Cisco Lab When it comes to learning and getting started with Cisco there are some tools that will help out a lot like Packet Tracer, GNS3 and other emulators. These are great tools for that &amp;quot;simulation&amp;quot; of hands on learning, but you can&#39;t always stay in that area. I find it best to get hands on with &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; Cisco Gear and so with this post I&#39;ll go through my current setup of what I have and ask that question when it is a good time to get a lab?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1 - The Joys of Subnetting!</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 20:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since network technicians work with IP addressing, it is hugely important to understand subnetting. I remember back when I started to learn subnetting it was confusing and I wanted nothing to do with it. The thing that made me change my mind was after I understood it and how important it is. In the &amp;quot;Cisco world&amp;quot; they don&#39;t cover useless topics...right? ;) there is always a reason why they expect you to know this and it&#39;s not just for the exams.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trunking Administrative Modes</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/02/11/trunking-administrative-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 22:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/02/11/trunking-administrative-modes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            cisco-switch-blade When looking at the CCNA it is good idea to get a hold of trunking between switches along with that there are a couple of administrative modes that each physical interface on Cisco switch can be when you are trunking between them. Remember that when we are trunking it usually carries all VLANs (This can be changed) but there are different ways to make trunking between links happen. When you are in an interface on a Cisco switch you can change the operational mode of that interface by issuing the switchport mode command.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Router on a Stick</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/31/configure-router-on-a-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 10:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/31/configure-router-on-a-stick/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A while ago I talked about putting different VLANs on a switch, remember a VLAN is virtual network that although physically it may look like on the same network that does not always mean the case. By having VLANs you are segmenting the network and the only way to get to the other side is having a router. I have already configured the Cisco switch as posted in Creating VLANs but in summary I have three VLANs total VLAN 1 which is the native VLAN, VLAN 2 and VLAN 3 (which is called support.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Tiers</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/21/the-three-tiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 19:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/21/the-three-tiers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network_switch Working towards the CCNA Cisco talks about a hierarchical network there are three layers to this design. Access Layer, distribution layer and the core layer. Each of them have their own set of functions and is also considered to be a best practice when the network continues to grow and for redundancy along with just a better way to manage it. The Access layer is the layer that devices connect to, such as PCs, printers, and IP Phones.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Codes of ICMP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post I wanted to talk about the widely used Ping command. Which is one of the best methods (I think) to begin network troubleshooting. When part of the network goes down it is sometimes hard to figure out why? When you issue the ping command or the extended ping command in a Cisco router several ICMP codes can come up on the router. Let&#39;s discuss them! The first status code &amp;quot;!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network-diagram In a perfect world we would never need redundancy on a network infrastructure, but as you know as well as I know we don&#39;t live in a perfect world. Hardware will eventually fail, bottlenecks will appear, and the speed of our network will become slower when we max the bandwidth on links. So having redundancy in routers, connections, and having a hierarchy network is one of best choices to make when improving the efficiently of the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the Cisco Discovery Protocol. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between router or switch is set up correctly at least up to layer two in the OSI model. This also helps us discover Cisco devices that are in are network and which interfaces these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed information CDP gives out which helps you has a network administrator build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Vector Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 16:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Couple weeks ago I talked about routing protocols and in the post I mentioned two routing protocol features distance vector and link state. Although these protocols fundamentally do the same thing by getting information on remote networks they get this information in a different way. For today let&#39;s introduce distance vector routing. With a distance vector routing protocol, a router learns about a route to a different network (that&#39;s the purpose of a routing protocol) the router only knows the &amp;quot;distance&amp;quot; to get there this is usually called the metric.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classful vs. Classless Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 16:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud-Computing-icon Before the internet and general networking become popular into what it is now, there were and still are routing protocols that only do classful routing. What is classful routing? When I was talking about Dynamic Routing earlier (See the post Dynamic Routing Protocols) I mentioned there was a difference between classful routing and classless routing. So in today&#39;s post let&#39;s focus on these two but important topics when using routing protocols.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS Commands</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 17:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the master list of some of the many Cisco IOS Commands that go with the CCNA track. This list also talks about what each command does in brief detail. You may also find that some commands may or may not be used for a CCNA level but offer some important information. If you don&#39;t know what a command does or understand it, I would look at Cisco documentation. Since this is a pretty big list of commands you can see the links to move to the different sections within this page.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Wireless LAN Security</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/18/basic-wireless-lan-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 16:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/18/basic-wireless-lan-security/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wireless-Security-Icon Although having a wireless LAN sounds like a wonderful idea, there are things that need to be implemented like security. A wireless LAN can be uncontrollable has it is just radio waves and anybody can receive them. Having and using good security practices can help you be under control of your wireless LAN. Not having any security in a wireless LAN environment will cause anybody to have access to the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VTP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some people hate it, some people love it. It&#39;s the Cisco proprietary VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) which in short means that Cisco switches can exchange VLAN configuration, instead of manually configuring each switch with the same VLANs. I also suggest if you don&#39;t know what a VLAN is check out the post Creating VLANs Let&#39;s get right into understanding VTP. The thing that makes VTP shine is what it does, although simple to understand it saves time by automatically distributing VLAN information.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Routing Protocols</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 16:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dynamic Routing If you ever wanted to set up a network manually, you will quickly find how much overhead is required to get PCs, printers, and other network equipment. That&#39;s where dynamic routing protocols come into play although they are helpful I strongly urge you to understand static routing first. (See the post Configure Static Routing) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s get the foundation of understanding dynamic routing protocols. By definition a routing protocol is a set of messages, rules and algorithms used by routers for the overall purpose of learning routes to other networks not physically connected to it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Static Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plugging Cisco routers together and hoping they work out of the box is not something you should hope for. A router can learn about networks in two ways, manually from configured static routers which we will talk about today and dynamic routing protocols which will talk about on Wednesday. Let&#39;s get started! Static routes are not that uncommon they at first need some attention to get set up but after it is working nothing needs to change.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Cisco SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we will be going over the steps that are required to set up the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger) The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. SDM is fairly easy to set up but you still need at least some experience in the router command-line to get SDM working. This tutorial is already assuming that the Cisco SDM program has been installed on the PC.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Process</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Troubleshooting Today&#39;s post is going to be talking about troubleshooting and where to start the troubleshooting process. Yes there is an actual process that every technician should be aware of. You can also use this troubleshooting process at home, you may not know how to fix it but at least you know where the issue is and find someone who can. Before we begin if you haven&#39;t seen yet, let me introduce to you the troubleshooting process:
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11n</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/11/802.11n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/11/802.11n/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On this Monday let&#39;s wrap up the 802.11 wireless standards, Friday I talked about the 802.11g (See the post 802.11g) and before that I talked about the 802.11b (See the post 802.11b ) I also talked about 802.11a, (See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of last week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So let&#39;s end the discussion and talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11g</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/08/802.11g/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/08/802.11g/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well again we are continuing the discussion about the wireless standards. Yesterday I talked about 802.11b (See the post 802.11b), and before that I talked about 802.11a,(See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Standards) So on this Friday let&#39;s talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11b</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/07/802.11b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 17:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/07/802.11b/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off the discussion, todays post will be talking about 802.11b wireless standard that was developed by IEEE. Yesterday&#39;s post we talked about the 802.11a standard. (See the post 802.11a) We also we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I went over some Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So now that we are up to speed lets learn about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11a</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/06/802.11a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/06/802.11a/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing the discussion about wireless standards we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) Today&#39;s post will be talking about the IEEE 802.11a standard. On Monday I talked about the Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post will be going over the second standard 802.11a out of the five standards that make up the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11 - Legacy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/05/802.11-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 15:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/05/802.11-legacy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday we talked about the wireless concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post one of the five standards that make up the 802.11. The 802.11 – Legacy has its called now and is not in use anymore by manufactures and is now obsolete was the first wireless standard available for consumer laptops. When the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Wireless Concepts</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/04/basic-wireless-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 15:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/04/basic-wireless-concepts/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            wireless-connection-icon Mobility is now a common thing in a business environment, you no longer are fixed to specific cubicle in the work place anymore. What is also amazing is it will continue to change and become easier for employees to get work done, with their phone, tablet, and laptop computer. But what makes this possible? What is the underlying component? The internet is becoming more available in more locations, coffee shops, airports, and your cell phone service provider, with 3G and 4G speeds.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating VLANs</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today this tutorial is going to be talking about creating VLANs (Virtual Local Area Networks) with a Cisco Catalyst switch. By creating a VLAN you are separating the network, why would you do this? There are some several reasons, like separating your production network from a guest network, and separating a test environment from a production network. This all adds security to your network. You can separate core critical network components from the rest of the production network for added security, easier troubleshooting along with separating or segmenting your network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Port Security</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/31/configuring-port-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/31/configuring-port-security/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure Today this tutorial is going to be talking about how to configure port security on a Cisco Catalyst switch. Port security is one of the first things you can do to keep your network secure from unauthorized access. Port security can restrict devices so only devices you allow are granted access to network resources. If and when an unauthorized device is connected to a port you can decide what you want the switch to do.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collision Domains vs Broadcast Domains</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These different types of domains mean different things and when designing a LAN both of these domains can harm the performance of your network. If you are not aware of the difference between these two, this tutorial should help you out. If you have a small network at your home there is usually the router/modem that is connected via phone line or cable to the ISP that router/modem is then connected to a switch or they even have a switch built into the device.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding UDP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 16:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Forever ago I talked about TCP (Understanding TCP) and I said that in that post that UDP would be another day, well this is the day where we get to understand UDP, which stands for User Datagram Protocol. UDP is the total opposite of the TCP communication. UDP in short sends information or data without notifying the receiver that its sending data. UDP is considered a connectionless protocol, and does not guarantee the reliability or order the packets like TCP does.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I passed the ICND1 Exam</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well my first of the many Cisco certifications that I plan take in the future was a success! I was able to pass the ICND1 exam. This blog post is going to be a little different in that I want to share how I was able to pass this test and talk about my experience.
Well in January after finishing the Cisco Networking Academy in the Exploration series I wanted to go ahead and take shot at the ICND1 exam.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Network Attacks</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/17/common-network-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 16:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/17/common-network-attacks/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network attacks have always been around but they are getting more advanced every day. These attacks are also easy to set up and use. In the past these types of attacks would have to be pulled off by someone who really knew about computers and to know what they are doing. That&#39;s a true hacker, now there are programs that do the same damage and sometimes more with a couple clicks of a mouse, so now anybody can bring down a network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a Router Routes</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 17:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial will be going over the basic information of how a router routes IP packets. Routers are used in the OSI layer three or the network layer. These routers have IP addresses and forward IP packets to the proper destination. This guide is somewhat basic and is assuming you have some information of how IP addressing works and along with what routing protocols are. So let&#39;s focus first on how a host or a computer forwards traffic and then look at how a router forwards traffic.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telecommuting Services</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/11/telecommuting-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 17:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/11/telecommuting-services/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is going to talk about the major technologies that make Teleworking or also called telecommuting possible. This is when an employee performs his or her job away from the office, usually from their home office. By doing this it allows personal convenience, less travel to and from the workplace. At an Organization level it provides continuity of operations, Secure, reliable and manageable access to information, cost-effective integration of data, voice, video and applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossover or Straight through?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 18:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The EIA/TIA puts the standards in UTP cable, and when cabling a network there are two standards. T568A and T568B these standards are important when deciding to put a crossover cable or straight through cable This tutorial is going to be talking about when and where to apply these different standards. We are going to be focusing on the UTP cable and with the RJ-45 connectors; in order for the communication to work properly we need to make sure we understand where to put these cables.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress.com Hit by a DoS Attack</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/04/wordpress.com-hit-by-a-dos-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 15:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/04/wordpress.com-hit-by-a-dos-attack/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday, (March 3rd 2011) there was a massive DoS attack that hit WordPress.com. Cisco Skill&#39;s uses WordPress.com has a hosting provider but is not believed to one of the sites hit. There still is no word on who or why they targeted WordPress.com but goes to show that Denial of Service is still a popular type of attack and although simple to set up they can still bring down enterprise networks.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding TCP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/25/understanding-tcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 18:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/25/understanding-tcp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial is going to be talking about the TCP protocol. Every time you connect to a website you are using the HTTP protocol, but below that you are also using a TCP protocol. The nature of TCP is to provide error recovery; there are other services or applications that use TCP. HTTP however is a common protocol that is used in online applications. Remember TCP is not the only protocol in the transport layer of the OSI model, there is another called UDP but that&#39;s another day.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wonders of Binary</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/15/the-wonders-of-binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 17:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/15/the-wonders-of-binary/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with IP addresses and subnet masks you need to have an understanding of how binary works. Binary is still used in computers today, when computers use numbers and letters they use them in a binary format. This guide will be going over numbers, and focusing on the IP addresses in how a computer sees that decimal number. Binary is a relatively easy in understanding and is just another way of looking at numbers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring RIPv2</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/09/configuring-ripv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 17:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/09/configuring-ripv2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide will go over how to configure RIPv2 on Cisco routers. This guide follows a packet tracer activity that is posted at the end of this tutorial. RIPv2 configuration is pretty simple to understand with really only three required commands to use besides the network command which depends how many networks are connected to your router. RIPv2 Layout So following the packet tracer that is used with this tutorial the first step is to configure the hostname on the routers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Router Configuration</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/01/26/basic-router-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 14:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/01/26/basic-router-configuration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the things you do first when setting up a Cisco router in lab environments and production environments is basic router configuration. By having a good understanding of basic router configuration you will have the essential building blocks and be able to apply additional knowledge upon router configuration. This tutorial is assuming that you are in a lab environment, additional security measures for production environments are recommended and are not discussed in this tutorial.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
