<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 10:00:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FMCv - Change IP Address</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/10/01/fmcv-change-ip-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/10/01/fmcv-change-ip-address/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome Back ;) Think about this for a bit, its been years ago when we first configured the our Cisco FMCv in our virtual environment perhaps this is running for years with no problems. (Lucky us!) All of our firewalls connect to it, policies are pushed correctly, IPS rules are updated correctly and we even have URL filtering turned on some devices, and upgrades work out of the box, it just works, again lucky us!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual ISP - Cisco ASA HA Active/Standby</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/03/12/dual-isp-cisco-asa-ha-active/standby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 12:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/03/12/dual-isp-cisco-asa-ha-active/standby/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So a single ISP isn&#39;t cutting it anymore you need a backup just in case the primary fails and might as well add a second ASA into this design, more redundancy equals more up-time, right? On paper it sounds good but in the &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; world there probably is tipping point, more redundancy increases complexity. In this post we&#39;ll aim to keep it simple, with setting up a Cisco ASA HA active/standby pair and then add in the second ISP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Dance</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/11/13/automation-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 15:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/11/13/automation-dance/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I keep doing the automation dance, (yeah...that&#39;s me) there are a lot of different tooling products out there. I have been trying to understand a use case around using it with network automation. Recently I have been dancing around with Ansible. My personal belief is that using any type of these tools would be helpful but it can be a steep learning curve if you really don&#39;t have any programming knowledge.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Many TCP Resets</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/06/20/too-many-tcp-resets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/06/20/too-many-tcp-resets/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So, recently we enforced some firewall rules on a new environment, we did testing of the environment and everything was working as expected. In about 24 hours a lot of traffic from the web infrastructure was being denied and it continued, at first glance it looked like return traffic was being dropped, the web servers were sourcing at port 443 and the destination ports were using dynamic ports (RFC 6335) No user or application problems were reported when we enforced rules, and we waited additional days to see if anything came up.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Site to Site VPN (DHCP)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/04/19/asa-site-to-site-vpn-dhcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/04/19/asa-site-to-site-vpn-dhcp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you don’t already know, site to site VPNs can be a cost-effective way for remote sites to connect to HQ resources instead of a lease line like using MPLS or Metro-E circuits. We can instead use a standard internet connection with a static IP, this is usually cheaper than a dedicated circuit. Our next steps are purchasing a firewall for the remote site (assuming you already have one at HQ) and setup a site to site VPN connection to make the connection.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of WAN Links</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/19/types-of-wan-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 16:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/19/types-of-wan-links/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve found this table that I created a while ago and it lists common WAN connections that businesses use. I have used this table like a reference guide to familiar myself into other protocols. People don&#39;t think of it much but the WAN is a different beast compared the LAN as it uses different protocols besides Ethernet. The WAN or wide area network is what connects us to remote locations within a organization.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Vector Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 16:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Couple weeks ago I talked about routing protocols and in the post I mentioned two routing protocol features distance vector and link state. Although these protocols fundamentally do the same thing by getting information on remote networks they get this information in a different way. For today let&#39;s introduce distance vector routing. With a distance vector routing protocol, a router learns about a route to a different network (that&#39;s the purpose of a routing protocol) the router only knows the &amp;quot;distance&amp;quot; to get there this is usually called the metric.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World IPv6 Day!!</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/08/world-ipv6-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 18:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/08/world-ipv6-day/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IPv6 So what is IPv6 day? Today major companies like Google, Facebook, Yahoo and ISPs (Internet Service Providers) test their IPv6 deployments. Why is this important? Well if you follow IPv4 news you might already know that IPv4 addresses have been exhausted and the need to move to different address space is critical, if new web services are to be deployed. The question is can we run both? Although running two different IP addressing protocols is likely, by &amp;quot;stacking&amp;quot; them that is one reason the Internet Society wanted major sites and ISPs to test out the IPv6 address space.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classful vs. Classless Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 16:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud-Computing-icon Before the internet and general networking become popular into what it is now, there were and still are routing protocols that only do classful routing. What is classful routing? When I was talking about Dynamic Routing earlier (See the post Dynamic Routing Protocols) I mentioned there was a difference between classful routing and classless routing. So in today&#39;s post let&#39;s focus on these two but important topics when using routing protocols.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VTP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some people hate it, some people love it. It&#39;s the Cisco proprietary VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) which in short means that Cisco switches can exchange VLAN configuration, instead of manually configuring each switch with the same VLANs. I also suggest if you don&#39;t know what a VLAN is check out the post Creating VLANs Let&#39;s get right into understanding VTP. The thing that makes VTP shine is what it does, although simple to understand it saves time by automatically distributing VLAN information.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Routing Protocols</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 16:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dynamic Routing If you ever wanted to set up a network manually, you will quickly find how much overhead is required to get PCs, printers, and other network equipment. That&#39;s where dynamic routing protocols come into play although they are helpful I strongly urge you to understand static routing first. (See the post Configure Static Routing) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s get the foundation of understanding dynamic routing protocols. By definition a routing protocol is a set of messages, rules and algorithms used by routers for the overall purpose of learning routes to other networks not physically connected to it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure a Site-to-Site VPN via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 18:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure a site-to-site VPN on a router using the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. (See the post Configuring SDM) Let&#39;s start configuring a site-to-site VPN with SDM! This tutorial is assuming that the configurations to set up Cisco SDM have already been completed.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 17:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Awhile back I talked about the differences between IPS and IDS. (See the post Cisco IDS vs. IPS ) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure an IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) on a router using the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. ( See the post Configure Cisco SDM) Let&#39;s start configuring an IPS with SDM!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Cisco SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we will be going over the steps that are required to set up the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger) The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. SDM is fairly easy to set up but you still need at least some experience in the router command-line to get SDM working. This tutorial is already assuming that the Cisco SDM program has been installed on the PC.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11n</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/11/802.11n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/11/802.11n/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On this Monday let&#39;s wrap up the 802.11 wireless standards, Friday I talked about the 802.11g (See the post 802.11g) and before that I talked about the 802.11b (See the post 802.11b ) I also talked about 802.11a, (See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of last week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So let&#39;s end the discussion and talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11g</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/08/802.11g/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/08/802.11g/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well again we are continuing the discussion about the wireless standards. Yesterday I talked about 802.11b (See the post 802.11b), and before that I talked about 802.11a,(See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Standards) So on this Friday let&#39;s talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collision Domains vs Broadcast Domains</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These different types of domains mean different things and when designing a LAN both of these domains can harm the performance of your network. If you are not aware of the difference between these two, this tutorial should help you out. If you have a small network at your home there is usually the router/modem that is connected via phone line or cable to the ISP that router/modem is then connected to a switch or they even have a switch built into the device.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding UDP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 16:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Forever ago I talked about TCP (Understanding TCP) and I said that in that post that UDP would be another day, well this is the day where we get to understand UDP, which stands for User Datagram Protocol. UDP is the total opposite of the TCP communication. UDP in short sends information or data without notifying the receiver that its sending data. UDP is considered a connectionless protocol, and does not guarantee the reliability or order the packets like TCP does.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telecommuting Services</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/11/telecommuting-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 17:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/11/telecommuting-services/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is going to talk about the major technologies that make Teleworking or also called telecommuting possible. This is when an employee performs his or her job away from the office, usually from their home office. By doing this it allows personal convenience, less travel to and from the workplace. At an Organization level it provides continuity of operations, Secure, reliable and manageable access to information, cost-effective integration of data, voice, video and applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossover or Straight through?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 18:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The EIA/TIA puts the standards in UTP cable, and when cabling a network there are two standards. T568A and T568B these standards are important when deciding to put a crossover cable or straight through cable This tutorial is going to be talking about when and where to apply these different standards. We are going to be focusing on the UTP cable and with the RJ-45 connectors; in order for the communication to work properly we need to make sure we understand where to put these cables.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress.com Hit by a DoS Attack</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/04/wordpress.com-hit-by-a-dos-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 15:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/04/wordpress.com-hit-by-a-dos-attack/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday, (March 3rd 2011) there was a massive DoS attack that hit WordPress.com. Cisco Skill&#39;s uses WordPress.com has a hosting provider but is not believed to one of the sites hit. There still is no word on who or why they targeted WordPress.com but goes to show that Denial of Service is still a popular type of attack and although simple to set up they can still bring down enterprise networks.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding TCP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/25/understanding-tcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 18:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/25/understanding-tcp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial is going to be talking about the TCP protocol. Every time you connect to a website you are using the HTTP protocol, but below that you are also using a TCP protocol. The nature of TCP is to provide error recovery; there are other services or applications that use TCP. HTTP however is a common protocol that is used in online applications. Remember TCP is not the only protocol in the transport layer of the OSI model, there is another called UDP but that&#39;s another day.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11ac Standard</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/21/802.11ac-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 18:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/21/802.11ac-standard/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some things are making news in the wireless world, the IEEE wants another wireless standard in the mix called the 802.11ac, now the fastest standard they have is the 802.11n(speeds up to 300 Mbps), which was recently published in October of 2009. What is so great about the 802.11ac development? Well one thing is the speed, it is estimated that it will be able to carry up to 1 gigabit per second!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS Routers: Auto Secure</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/17/cisco-ios-routers-auto-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 17:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/17/cisco-ios-routers-auto-secure/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Auto Secure is good for small business or IT administrators that may know how to configure a router with networking protocols, setting up IP interfaces, and networks but really don&#39;t have an understanding of the security aspect of the router. So what Cisco has done is implemented a script called Auto Secure. Auto Secure is based on the questions you answer from the prompt usually &amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;no&amp;quot; answers. Sometimes the script wants a little more information depending on your network configuration.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv4 Meet IPv6</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/03/ipv4-meet-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 13:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/03/ipv4-meet-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IPv4 maybe on its last leg with only a few blocks of IPv4 addresses available, computer estimates say that the IANA address depletion was January 27, 2011. Also the calculations for all central IPv4 pool addresses will be depleted by July 25, 2012.
These are estimates and may change as of writing this post. I&#39;ll be sure to update if needed, but the thing to understand is that IPv4 won&#39;t be available within weeks if not months.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Weaknesses Cybercriminals Exploit</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/01/27/common-weaknesses-cybercriminals-exploit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 14:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/01/27/common-weaknesses-cybercriminals-exploit/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            While reading the Cisco Annual Report they came up with seven common social engineering attacks that cybercriminals use. Now these types of attacks are common and are not unheard of. You should be familiar with most if not all these weaknesses that cybercriminals use.
Sex appeal, which means scammers will try to find or put up attractive man or woman. Then tempt the user for information. People should remember if you don&#39;t know the person this will more than likely not be romance but something else.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
