<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:41:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Passed 640-554!</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2013/06/passed-640-554/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2013/06/passed-640-554/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h2 id=&#34;blue_cisco_picturehttpsystemstechblogfileswordpresscom201306blue_ciscotwitter_picturejpghttpsystemstechblogfileswordpresscom201306blue_ciscotwitter_picturejpgshort-story-i-am-proud-to-say-that-i-passed-i-have-studied-off-and-on-in-the-beginning-of-the-year-but-i-did-set-a-date-to-take-the-exam-which-was-june-28th-as-that-date-was-getting-closer-i-buckled-down-and-reviewed-the-materials-again-and-focused-in-on-some-areas-that-iknew-i-was-weak-in-so-how-was-the-640-554-exam-what-did-i-use-to-pass-the-exam-and-what-exam-am-i-focusing-on-next--the-640-554-exam-that-i-took-surprised-me-which-left-me-at-the-edge-of-the-seat-the-entire-testing-period-8-o-there-where-lot-of-difficult-questions-that-i-would-have-missed-if-i-hadnt-of-re-reviewed-the-study-materials-along-with-the-amount-of-questions-i-had-to-go-through-to-meet-the-90-minute-deadline-but-it-was-worth-it-after-i-saw-my-passing-score-on-screen-it-definitely-was-a-fair-score-that-i-received-i-did-not-feel-cheated-or-have-any-questions-that-werent-on-the-exam-topic-listhttpwwwciscocomweblearningexamslistiinshtmltopics-640-554-iins-so-i-was-overall-pleased-with-the-results--now-to-question-that-is-often-asked-what-materials-did-i-use-to-pass-the-exam--i-used-the-ccna-security-640-554-official-cert-guidehttpwwwamazoncomccna-security-640-554-official-guidedp1587204460refsr_1_1sbooksieutf8qid1372552672sr1-1keywordsccnasecurity640-554officialcertguide-ccna-security-640-554-official-cert-guide--authored-by-keith-barker-and-scott-morris-which-is-an-excellent-study-guide-i-also-used-the-cbt-nugget-series-cisco-ccna-security-640-554httpssecurecbtnuggetscomit-training-videosseriescsco_640_554-cisco-ccna-security-640-554---implementing-cisco-ios-network-security-iins-which-is-also-by-keith-barker-to-at-first-learn-about-the-material-take-some-notes-on-it-and-then-review-it-in-the-cert-guide-by-going-through-the-chapters-reviewing-the-questions-that-are-in-the-beginning-of-the-chapters-along-with-using-the-study-material-that-was-included-in-the-book-i-also-had-some-lab-gear-that-was-helpful-in-either-following-along-with-the-cbt-videos-or-just-building-some-test-labs-the-lab-i-have-follows-the-one-i-posted-back-in-september-cisco-lab-setuphttpciscoskillsnet20120907cisco-lab-setup-cisco-labsetup-i-also-recently-was-able-to-get-two-more-2960-cisco-catalysthttpenwikipediaorgwikicisco_catalyst-cisco-catalyst-switches--so-what-is-my-next-plan-not-sure-i-might-look-at-that-new-ccna-data-centerhttpciscoskillsnet20121121ccna-data-center-ccna-datacenter-exam-which-was-announcedlast-fall-and-it-also-looked-like-they-may-have-some-study-material-for-it-at-least-for-first-exam-640-911-dcicn-i-might-start-on-the-ccnp-journeybut-either-way-i-am-still-planning-on-posting-on-this-blog-with-tutorials-ideas-and-other-stories-i-am-also-happy-that-i-was-able-to-make-some-changes-of-the-layout-and-color-of-this-blogi-hope-you-enjoy-the-new-look-and-like-always-i-hope-this-information-is-helpful-and-enjoy-your-summer&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/blue_ciscotwitter_picture.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/blue_ciscotwitter_picture.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Blue_Cisco_picture&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Short story, I am proud to say that I passed! I have studied off and on in the beginning of the year but I did set a date to take the exam which was June 28th .As that date was getting closer I buckled down and reviewed the materials again and focused in on some areas that I knew I was weak in. So how was the 640-554 exam, what did I use to pass the exam and what exam am I focusing on next?  The 640-554 exam that I took surprised me which left me at the edge of the seat the entire testing period! 8-O There where lot of difficult questions that I would have missed if I hadn’t of re-reviewed the study materials, along with the amount of questions I had to go through to meet the 90 minute deadline, but it was worth it! After I saw my passing score on screen it definitely was a fair score that I received. I did not feel cheated or have any questions that weren’t on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/web/learning/exams/list/iins.html#~Topics&#34; title=&#34;640-554 IINS&#34;&gt;exam topic list&lt;/a&gt;, so I was overall pleased with the results.  Now to question that is often asked, what materials did I use to pass the exam?  I used the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Security-640-554-Official-Guide/dp/1587204460/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1372552672&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=ccna+security+640-554+official+cert+guide&#34; title=&#34;CCNA Security 640-554 Official Cert Guide &#34;&gt;CCNA Security 640-554 Official Cert Guide&lt;/a&gt; authored by Keith Barker and Scott Morris which is an excellent study guide. I also used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.cbtnuggets.com/it-training-videos/series/csco_640_554&#34; title=&#34;Cisco CCNA Security 640-554 - Implementing Cisco IOS Network Security (IINS)&#34;&gt;CBT Nugget Series Cisco CCNA Security 640-554&lt;/a&gt; which is also by Keith Barker to at first learn about the material, take some notes on it and then review it in the cert guide by going through the chapters, reviewing the questions that are in the beginning of the chapters, along with using the study material that was included in the book. I also had some lab gear that was helpful in either following along with the CBT videos or just building some test labs. The lab I have follows the one I posted back in September (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/09/07/cisco-lab-setup/&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Lab Setup&#34;&gt;Cisco Lab Setup&lt;/a&gt;) I also recently was able to get two more 2960 &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Catalyst&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Catalyst&#34;&gt;Cisco Catalyst&lt;/a&gt; switches. :) So what is my next plan? Not sure I might look at that new &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/&#34; title=&#34;CCNA Data Center&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center&lt;/a&gt; exam which was announced last fall and it also looked like they may have some study material for it, at least for first exam (640-911 DCICN). I might start on the CCNP journey but either way I am still planning on posting on this blog with tutorials, ideas and other stories. I am also happy that I was able to make some changes of the layout and color of this blog, I hope you enjoy the new look and like always I hope this information is helpful and enjoy your summer!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2013/03/26/ccna-version-2-0-refresh/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;CCNA Version 2.0 Refresh « Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-07-06 10:00:01&#34;&gt;Jul 6, 2013&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] Passed 640-554! (ciscoskills.net) […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-29 23:14:04&#34;&gt;Jun 6, 2013&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, Good Luck on the CCDA, that is another exam I have been looking at as well. Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[just plain ol&#39; Kev]( &#34;theos888@live.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-30 23:49:02&#34;&gt;Jun 0, 2013&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good job! Glad you are keeping the blog going. Lammle has a new study guide for CCNA data center that just came out. Kevin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[yow]( &#34;yow@yahoo.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-29 20:35:27&#34;&gt;Jun 6, 2013&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;yow! congrats man! I&#39;m gunning for my CCDA also within the year, and let&#39;s hope I get to post something like this too, :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[CCNA 2.0 What&amp;#8217;s New? &amp;laquo; Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2013/09/30/ccna-2-0-whats-new/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-09-30 18:35:05&#34;&gt;Sep 1, 2013&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] Passed 640-554! (ciscoskills.net) […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I passed the ICND1 Exam</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/03/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/03/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/cisco_ccent_logo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/cisco_ccent_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Cisco_CCENT_Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Well my first of the many &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Career_Certifications&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Career Certifications&#34;&gt;Cisco certifications&lt;/a&gt; that I plan take in the future was a success! I was able to pass the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interconnecting_Cisco_Networking_Devices_Part_1&#34; title=&#34;Interconnecting Cisco Networking Devices Part 1&#34;&gt;ICND1&lt;/a&gt; exam. This blog post is going to be a little different in that I want to share how I was able to pass this test and talk about my experience.  Well in January after finishing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Networking_Academy&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Networking Academy&#34;&gt;Cisco Networking Academy&lt;/a&gt; in the Exploration series I wanted to go ahead and take shot at the ICND1 exam. Now I knew that this was not going to be easy, by looking at online sites like CLN (Cisco Learning Network) and reading the horror stories of people missing by one point, having a hard time &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Understanding&#34; title=&#34;Understanding&#34;&gt;understanding&lt;/a&gt; the material, not fully prepared, etc. But also reading success stories about how people passed and what they did to pass, really made me jump on the opportunity. Another thing that made me want to try it was the discounted price I was able to get, by going into the Cisco Networking Academy and doing fairly well I was able to apply for a voucher, which helped kept that determination I had when &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Study_skills&#34; title=&#34;Study skills&#34;&gt;studying&lt;/a&gt; for the ICND1 exam. &lt;strong&gt;So what did I do to pass this this exam?&lt;/strong&gt; Well although I finished the Cisco Networking Academy I needed to review the fundamental topics again. So I bought the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Official-Certification-Library-640-802-Containing/dp/1587201836/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1300551785&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;CCNA Official Exam Certification Library (Exam 640-802), Third Edition (Containing ICND1 and ICND2 Second Edition Exam Certification Guides)&lt;/a&gt; I wanted something that really covered it all in one book, and I am very pleased that I went ahead and got it. But reading a book I don&#39;t think cuts it, you need to fully understand how to set up routers, and switches. That&#39;s where either packet tracer or access to physical equipment comes in. Since I am part of the Cisco Networking Academy I had access to physical and simulation software that I could use. One thing I can agree on is with Cisco &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_%28assessment%29&#34; title=&#34;Test (assessment)&#34;&gt;exams&lt;/a&gt; you want to make sure that you know how a set of commands work and know what they do and when to apply them. &lt;strong&gt;So how did I study and how long did it take me to study?&lt;/strong&gt; Well at first I wanted to study alone I felt that I could get more done. However if possible I would suggest finding a friend that also wants to get certified or at least someone who you can teach the material to. I think I learned a lot more and having discussions with each other helped both of us understand the material. For the ICND1 exam it took three months of us studying and preparing for the exam. We mainly used the book from Wendell Odom and did some web searches for ICND1 practice questions. Another thing that helped me was joining the Cisco Learning Network. By asking and answering questions on the discussion pages. &lt;strong&gt;How can I pass the ICND1 exam?&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you know the material. Its sounds simple but when I was taking the exam the questions I was given were questions that I would&#39;ve failed if I hadn&#39;t went over the book, online practice questions, and discussions. I felt confident in my answers; I was not second guessing myself and I knew the material inside and out. Another thing I did before taking the exam was go over the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/web/learning/le3/current_exams/640-822.html&#34;&gt;ICND1 exam topics.&lt;/a&gt; I made sure I could explain every topic that was listed. In the end it shows as at the end of the exam I received an excellent score! Having said that there is always someone who wants the easy route and one thing I can say that &lt;strong&gt;won&#39;t&lt;/strong&gt; help you is a thing called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brain_dump&#34; title=&#34;Brain dump&#34;&gt;brain dumps&lt;/a&gt;. Which are questions that a person would memorize and some if not all are taken from the official exams. In addition you are violating the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-disclosure_agreement&#34; title=&#34;Non-disclosure agreement&#34;&gt;non-disclosure agreements&lt;/a&gt;. I don&#39;t understand why people would do this type of thing. To me it sounds like more work than to really just understand the material. It degrades the certification and really does not help anyone. So my advice is don&#39;t pay that amount of money because usually they are about has much as the official exam. &lt;strong&gt;This is my first time taking the exam what can I expect?&lt;/strong&gt; Like you I was nervous so nervous, I reviewed and reviewed and went over everything again and again. I would agree to this which is you are battling with yourself. Relaxing is important and one thing I like when taking the Cisco exams is you start with a tutorial, I think this helps you get into the mode and you start to calm down. You have about 15 minutes to just breathe and get ready to take the exam and don&#39;t over think it! Simple questions usually want a simple answer. Although test taking tips help you have to know the material in the end to pass, you can&#39;t guess at this stuff. Set a goal and take the exam. Looking back I&#39;m glad I did. It showed that I&#39;m in right the career path and shows to employers that I know the material. So what&#39;s next well I&#39;m taking a break this week, and will start again next week with some more Cisco information and tutorials. I&#39;m also going to start reviewing the ICND2 exam soon and currently I&#39;m estimating that this one will take longer than three months. :)&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
