<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Operating system on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/operating-system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Operating system on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 17:15:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/operating-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Windows 8 Developer Preview</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/12/windows-8-developer-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 17:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/12/windows-8-developer-preview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Changing topics for today, I want to talk about the Windows 8 Developer Preview which was released on September 13th. I had the time to install it under virtual box and was pleasantly surprised! About how fast it installed the easy to understand install prompts and the new &amp;quot;Metro&amp;quot; UI which is aimed at touched devices. Also the ability to switch to the standard Windows operating system. This is an alpha build so it&#39;s not even on at the beta stages yet, Take a look for yourself!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the Cisco Discovery Protocol. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between router or switch is set up correctly at least up to layer two in the OSI model. This also helps us discover Cisco devices that are in are network and which interfaces these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed information CDP gives out which helps you has a network administrator build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Process</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Troubleshooting Today&#39;s post is going to be talking about troubleshooting and where to start the troubleshooting process. Yes there is an actual process that every technician should be aware of. You can also use this troubleshooting process at home, you may not know how to fix it but at least you know where the issue is and find someone who can. Before we begin if you haven&#39;t seen yet, let me introduce to you the troubleshooting process:
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install BackTrack</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 18:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a full install of BackTrack 4 this can be in a virtual machine, dual-boot, or the main OS. So you burned the image that you downloaded from http://www.backtrack-linux.org/ and are ready to go! If not I would recommend you do that first. BackTrack is a Linux penetration testing for network security. This is a free tool that IT administrators can use to audit their network. First put the disk into the tray and restart your computer.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
