<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Operating system on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/operating-system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Operating system on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 17:15:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/operating-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Windows 8 Developer Preview</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/12/windows-8-developer-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 17:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/12/windows-8-developer-preview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Changing topics for today, I want to talk about the Windows 8 Developer Preview which was released on September 13th. I had the time to install it under &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VirtualBox&#34; title=&#34;VirtualBox&#34;&gt;virtual box&lt;/a&gt; and was pleasantly surprised! About how fast it installed the easy to understand install prompts and the new &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metro_Design_Language&#34; title=&#34;Metro Design Language&#34;&gt;Metro&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_interface&#34; title=&#34;User interface&#34;&gt;UI&lt;/a&gt; which is aimed at touched devices. Also the ability to switch to the standard &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Windows&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Windows&#34;&gt;Windows operating system&lt;/a&gt;. This is an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_release_life_cycle&#34; title=&#34;Software release life cycle&#34;&gt;alpha build&lt;/a&gt; so it&#39;s not even on at the beta stages yet, Take a look for yourself! [slideshow] Want to try it for yourself check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/apps/br229516&#34; title=&#34;Windows 8 Developer Preview downloads&#34;&gt;Windows 8 Developer Preview downloads&lt;/a&gt;. This is an alpha build and can be unstable. I would use a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_machine&#34; title=&#34;Virtual machine&#34;&gt;virtual machine&lt;/a&gt; to test it. Although short to the point that&#39;s all I have so check back for other posts. What do like about Windows 8 DP? What don&#39;t you like? Comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://obieosobalu.wordpress.com/2011/10/07/microsoft-releases-white-papers-for-windows-8-developer-preview-edition-for-developers/&#34;&gt;Microsoft releases White papers for Windows 8 Developer Preview Edition for Developers&lt;/a&gt; (obieosobalu.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edugeek.net/forums/windows-8/82759-windows-8-developer-preview-available-download-microsoft.html&#34;&gt;Windows 8 Developer preview is available to download by Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; (edugeek.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thegeekpost.wordpress.com/2011/09/21/windows-8-developer-preview-available-now/&#34;&gt;Windows 8 - Developer Preview Available Now!&lt;/a&gt; (thegeekpost.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.winrumors.com/microsoft-provides-virtualization-recommendations-for-windows-8-developer-preview/&#34;&gt;Microsoft provides virtualization recommendations for Windows 8 developer preview&lt;/a&gt; (winrumors.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.winrumors.com/microsoft-begins-distributing-windows-8-developer-preview-updates/&#34;&gt;Microsoft begins distributing Windows 8 developer preview updates&lt;/a&gt; (winrumors.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://plavc.wordpress.com/2011/10/19/windows-8-developer-preview/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Windows 8 Developer Preview « Memory leak&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-10-19 06:27:33&#34;&gt;Oct 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Windows 8 Developer Preview (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Discovery_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Discovery Protocol&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt;. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;router&lt;/a&gt; or switch is set up correctly  at least up to layer two in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt;. This also helps us discover &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; devices that are in are network and which &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interface_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Interface (computing)&#34;&gt;interfaces&lt;/a&gt; these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary  and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information&#34; title=&#34;Information&#34;&gt;information&lt;/a&gt; CDP gives out which helps you has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_administrator&#34; title=&#34;Network administrator&#34;&gt;network administrator&lt;/a&gt; build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet. So what is the purpose of CDP? CDP can gather device information from neighboring switches and routers without the need for a password. Like mentioned before this is great for troubleshooting a problem, discovering new devices that are not documented in your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_topology&#34; title=&#34;Network topology&#34;&gt;network topology&lt;/a&gt;, and verifying that each device is physically connected to the correct interfaces according to network documentation. CDP can discover the following details from neighboring devices that support CDP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Identifier: The hostname of the device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address List: Network and data-link addresses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local Interface: The interface on the switch or router issuing the command &lt;em&gt;Show CDP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port Identifier: Identifies the port used by the device to send CDP messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capabilities List: Information on what the device is like a router or a switch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platform: The model and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating_system&#34; title=&#34;Operating system&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/a&gt; running on the device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since CDP is enabled by default it does create a security risk, Cisco recommends that CDP be disabled on all interfaces that do not have need for it. You can disable CDP in two ways, by each interface with the sub-command &lt;em&gt;no cdp enable&lt;/em&gt; under the interface you wish to disable CDP. Or you can also disable CDP globally within the router or switch with the command &lt;em&gt;no cdp run&lt;/em&gt; under the configuration mode. That&#39;s just some general information about CDP and why CDP is useful. Although CDP could be a security risk it&#39;s still a helpful protocol to get some detailed information about your Cisco devices for inventory or to update your network topology. It can also be useful to just verify that the physical layer and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Link_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Data Link Layer&#34;&gt;data-link layer&lt;/a&gt; are working correctly for troubleshooting purposes. Like always I hope this information is informative and if you have an idea on the next topic that deals with wither ICND1 or ICND2 let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS Commands&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/&#34;&gt;Distance Vector Routing&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/ar/cisco-again-makes-ip-ngns-simpler-more-capable-less-costly/&#34;&gt;Cisco Again Makes IP NGNs Simpler, More Capable, Less Costly&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Process</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/thinking.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/thinking.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today&#39;s post is going to be talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Troubleshooting&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting&#34;&gt;troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; and where to start the troubleshooting process. Yes there is an actual process that every technician should be aware of. You can also use this troubleshooting process at home, you may not know how to fix it but at least you know where the issue is and find someone who can.  Before we begin if you haven&#39;t seen yet, let me introduce to you the troubleshooting process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to gather information about the problem. (What happened?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep it simple, verify the obvious issues FIRST! (Is the device powered on?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try some quick solutions first (restart, reinstall, verify connections)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gather information from the device (Device Manger, if you are in routers or switches use &amp;quot;Show&amp;quot; commands and &amp;quot;Debug&amp;quot; commands)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your research skills! Evaluate the problem and try possible solutions. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet&#34; title=&#34;Internet&#34;&gt;Internet&lt;/a&gt; searches, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_forum&#34; title=&#34;Internet forum&#34;&gt;Online Forums&lt;/a&gt;, past experiences etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally keep note of what you did even if you did not fix the issue. (Keep an engineer notebook!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may look simple, and it is! This is the exact method I use when troubleshooting a problem. Troubleshooting is a hard skill to have, as you really can&#39;t learn from it in a book. You have to have experience with the type of technology you&#39;re working with. One thing I use all the time is my research skills this can be a life saver if you know what to look for, use key details! The internet can be helpful but putting generic terms like &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_XP&#34; title=&#34;Windows XP&#34;&gt;windows XP&lt;/a&gt; is not working&amp;quot; will not help you but instead waste your time. Use the key terms when have an issue like an error code, type the error message, describe what you can&#39;t do, etc. Chances are somebody somewhere has had the same problem or at least something like it and decided to post it. Another thing I like to do when checking on a problem is going to the source! Although there are helpful places around web like forums, and chat systems I usually use this last. If I am having a problem with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Windows&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Windows&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; for example I&#39;ll go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; Support. Same thing if I have an issue with a Cisco product I&#39;ll go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; Support webpage before I go and search my problem around the web. Finally remember ask other technicians if they have seen the problem. By using these steps and guidelines will be able to become better at troubleshooting like before it&#39;s something you can&#39;t learn from a book you must have experience with technology before you can even start troubleshooting. My last word of advice is keeping a record! Write down the steps you did, why did them and what where the solutions to the problem? If you couldn&#39;t figure it still write it down. That way if the issue occurs again you and other people know exactly how to fix the problem or also know what solutions not work last time and not waste any of your time, like always I hope this information was informative and if you have an idea about the next ICND1 or ICND2 topic comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install BackTrack</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 18:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp3/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is a full install of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34; title=&#34;BackTrack&#34;&gt;BackTrack&lt;/a&gt; 4 this can be in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_machine&#34; title=&#34;Virtual machine&#34;&gt;virtual machine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi_boot&#34; title=&#34;Multi boot&#34;&gt;dual-boot&lt;/a&gt;, or the main &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating_system&#34; title=&#34;Operating system&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/a&gt;. So you burned the image that you downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&lt;/a&gt;  and are ready to go! If not I would recommend you do that first. BackTrack is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kernel.org/&#34; title=&#34;Linux&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; penetration testing for network security. This is a free tool that IT administrators can use to audit their network.   First put the disk into the tray and restart your computer. This depends on your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BIOS&#34; title=&#34;BIOS&#34;&gt;BIOS setup&lt;/a&gt; but you can either set the boot order or go into a boot menu and select the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compact_Disc&#34; title=&#34;Compact Disc&#34;&gt;CD&lt;/a&gt; tray as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Booting&#34; title=&#34;Booting&#34;&gt;boot device&lt;/a&gt;.  This is the first thing you will see when you boot into BackTrack you can play around with the different options later but select the screen resolution that is close to your screen size.   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/backtrack-1/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/backtrack-1.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrack Main&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Once you select the option you want you will see a loading page, this can take some time so be patient!   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/backtrack-load/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/backtrack-load.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrackLoad&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Once backtrack is done loading then you can start from there and have fun with command-line but if your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Command-line_interface&#34; title=&#34;Command-line interface&#34;&gt;CLI&lt;/a&gt; skills are a little rusty then you can go into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface&#34; title=&#34;Graphical user interface&#34;&gt;GUI&lt;/a&gt; by typing &lt;em&gt;startx&lt;/em&gt; and hit enter. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/backtrack-loadst/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/backtrack-loadst.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrack loadst&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; From here you can run BackTrack now (it’s called a Live CD) &lt;em&gt;this could be useful if you just want to look at it and play around with settings that you have no idea what they are or do. That why if you mess something up you can always restart and go back into it without it saving anything!&lt;/em&gt; But let’s install this thing! Click on the Install.sh icon.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/install-shell/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/install-shell.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;install shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  This next window is the installer, it is pretty simple to understand, you want to select your location that is in the same time-zone as you.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp1/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp1.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Install Page 1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  This next window is the keyboard layout, Usually USA works for me. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp2/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp2.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;install page 2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  This next page is the partition manager thing, from here you can dual-boot if you have another OS. (You want to be careful if you do have another OS on the hardrive because you can wipe your other OS from here) For this example I am taking the whole drive.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp3.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;install page 3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  The next page gives you a review before you start installing BackTrack this is also a good time to make sure everything is set up properly before you install BackTrack &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp4/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp4.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;installpage 4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  After you click install the installer will start installing!! (amazing! right!) Here you can watch the bar go across the screen or do something productive in this timeframe it takes about 20 to 30 minutes but this also depends on the hardware you have.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp5/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp5.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;installpage 5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  After it finishes it gives you two options, stay on the live CD or reboot to start BackTrack. &lt;em&gt;(Hint: reboot)&lt;/em&gt;   Once the machine is rebooting it will take some time so be patient as it is loading. Once it is ready it will ask you for your username and password. The username is &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt; and the password is &lt;em&gt;toor .&lt;/em&gt; Once you type that you&#39;re in CLI again, if you want to go to the GUI just type &lt;em&gt;startx&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btstart/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btstart.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrack start&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   Once you type &lt;em&gt;startx&lt;/em&gt; it will load the GUI and you now have a full install of BackTrack! From here you can go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to audit your network.&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btstartdesk/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btstartdesk.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrackdesk&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I hope this tutorial was helpful&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
