<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ASDM on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/asdm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ASDM on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 01:20:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/asdm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2012/06/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 01:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2012/06/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In this short but helpful post, I&#39;ll go through the process of upgrading the ASA IOS via the ASDM. This is a pretty painless method if all goes well the only thing you have to do schedule downtime if this box is in production, and grab the ASA IOS image from Cisco. For this post all have been covered let&#39;s get started! First things first is always backup your configuration before upgrading and I always read the release notes that Cisco provides when I download the IOS image, it&#39;s good reading and important because usually new features are introduced and sometime the ASDM can&#39;t paraphrase and parse the new configuration which way I usually upgrade the ASDM first. There are couple ways of backing the configuration this example is with the ASDM. In this example open up the ASDM client and go to file and select &amp;quot;Show Running Configuration in New Window&amp;quot; this will open up the current running-config in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_browser&#34; title=&#34;Web browser&#34;&gt;browser window&lt;/a&gt; and from there you can either save the page or copy it to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_editor&#34; title=&#34;Text editor&#34;&gt;text editor&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-run-config.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-run-config.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Show Running-Config in ASDM&#34; title=&#34;ASDM-Run-Config&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Once the configuration is saved you are ready to go for the upgrade. Select &amp;quot;Tools&amp;quot; and you have two options. If this ASA can go online you can select the first option (Check for ASA/ASDM Updates)  which will ask for your Cisco account that is tied with SmartNet,  which downloads the IOS or ASDM or both images automatically and installs them with very little effort on your part. For this post we have to one more extra setup to install this IOS we&#39;ll select the &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Upgrade&#34; title=&#34;Upgrade&#34;&gt;Upgrade&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_software&#34; title=&#34;Application software&#34;&gt;Software&lt;/a&gt; from Local Computer&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-tools.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-tools.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;The ASDM Tools File Menu&#34; title=&#34;ASDM-Tools&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A window comes select what image you are uploading the to the ASA, notice this is also the same method of installing/upgrading the ASDM along with helpful tools like the Cisco AnyConnect &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network&#34; title=&#34;Virtual private network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/a&gt; Client. This example we selected the ASA image and have browsed our local computer to the ASA image that we downloaded from Cisco our next move is to uploading the image.&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-upload-ios.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-upload-ios.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;ASDM-Upload-IOS&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/uploading.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/uploading.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;uploading&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Finally another window will show letting you know that the image is setup and goes through the process of telling you how to reload the ASA. Also it reminds you to make sure the ASDM version will work with this new IOS image which would be in the release notes Cisco puts out, from there reload the ASA. Once the ASA reboots open up the ASDM and you&#39;ll notice that we now have the ASA version of 8.4(3)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asa-uploaded.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asa-uploaded.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;ASA-uploaded&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asa-version.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asa-version.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;ASA-version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping up with versions of the ASA is important but you have to weigh the risks of updating, take this upgrade for example from 8.2 to 8.4 a lot of configurations have changed which is why it is really important to look at the release notes. I hope this information is helpful and if you have any questions or comments let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/&#34;&gt;Basic Cisco ASA Overview&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/&#34;&gt;CCNA Security - 640-554&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ethernuno.wordpress.com/2012/04/05/auto-backup-cisco-routerswitch-using-kron-and-vsftpd-ftp/&#34;&gt;Auto Backup Cisco router/switch using Kron and vsftpd FTP.&lt;/a&gt; (ethernuno.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/07/21/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Password Recovery – Cisco IOS Routers | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-07-21 11:04:27&#34;&gt;Jul 6, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Cisco ASA Overview</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2012/06/basic-cisco-asa-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2012/06/basic-cisco-asa-overview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/firewall.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/firewall.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Firewall&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Cisco 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliances are of course an excellent firewall but the ASA also offers (depending on the model) other security services as well, like IPS systems, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network&#34; title=&#34;Virtual private network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/a&gt;, content security, unified communications and remote access. These ASA&#39;s can be used as a standalone appliance&#39; that can handle the need for branch offices to enterprise data centers. Or they can be included in high-performance blades that work together with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Catalyst&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Catalyst&#34;&gt;Cisco Catalyst&lt;/a&gt; 6500 Series, and recently new they can also run in a virtual instance which provides tenant isolation for public and private clouds! For now let&#39;s focus on the basics of the ASA like the ASDM. The ASDM is a pretty good &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface&#34; title=&#34;Graphical user interface&#34;&gt;GUI&lt;/a&gt; tool that helps make the ASA a simpler process of maintaining and configuring the device, instead of doing &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Command-line_interface&#34; title=&#34;Command-line interface&#34;&gt;CLI&lt;/a&gt; commando style. In this example I have an ASA 5505 with default configuration (I did a &amp;quot;write erase&amp;quot; to clear the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34; title=&#34;IP address&#34;&gt;IP addressing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic_Host_Configuration_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol&#34;&gt;DHCP&lt;/a&gt; settings) when you reload the device I decided to use the ASA&#39;s pre-configure wizard which really just makes the ASA useable by giving the inside interface an IP address along with the correct time and the &amp;quot;enable password&amp;quot; Here are the current settings: [code]The following configuration will be used: Enable password: cisco Allow password recovery: yes Clock (UTC): 11:04:11 Jun 23 2012 Firewall Mode: Routed Inside IP address: 192.168.5.1 Inside network mask: 255.255.255.0 Host name: ASA Domain name: ciscoskills.net IP address of host running Device Manager: 192.168.5.10 Use this configuration and write to flash? yes INFO: Security level for &amp;quot;inside&amp;quot; set to 100 by default. WARNING: http server is not yet enabled to allow ASDM access. Cryptochecksum: a2692f1b 31b2d847 6abf71e4 b9c1bcfb 1641 bytes copied in 1.730 secs (1641 bytes/sec) Type help or &#39;?&#39; for a list of available commands. ASA&amp;gt;en ASA#config t ASA(config)#http server enable[/code] Notice to use the ASDM you must put it one more command for the ASA to listen on port 443 which is &amp;quot;http server enable&amp;quot; from that open up your browser and type the IP address of the ASA in this example it is &amp;quot;192.168.5.1&amp;quot; you can either run the ASDM from the ASA or install it on your system for a faster experience it&#39;s your choice, but it does add additional memory and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_processing_unit&#34; title=&#34;Central processing unit&#34;&gt;CPU&lt;/a&gt; if the ASDM runs on the ASA. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-main.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-main.png&#34; alt=&#34;Browser Page for ASA&#34; title=&#34;ASDM-BROWSER&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; For this example I installed the ASDM on my system and by default the username is blank and the password is &amp;quot;cisco&amp;quot; which is what I configured in the beginning. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-login.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;The ASDM Login Screen&#34; title=&#34;ASDM-LOGIN&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; From there opens up the ASDM the home page displays some device information like the hostname, ASA version and ASADM version, the runtime, total RAM and flash. It also gives you some traffic stats along with CPU and memory from there to configure the device you would click the configuration button and configure a way! &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-home.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-home.png&#34; alt=&#34;The ASDM Home Page&#34; title=&#34;ASDM-HOME&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You have to have some hands-on experience with this product to really understand it and get the overall feeling of where things in the ASDM. Cisco does offer some ASDM demos that can be searchable on the internet and you can download directly from Cisco however you must have a Cisco ID to use it. If you &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mediafire.com/download.php?rwfhxjdy9zznan3&#34; title=&#34;ASDM 6.4(9) Install and Demo Files&#34;&gt;download this link&lt;/a&gt; it will install the latest (May 2012) ASDM demo settings so you can at least get a feeling of the ASDM. I hope this information is helpful and if you have any questions are comments be sure to post them below, also check back often I&#39;ll see if I can post some additional content about the ASA like &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/29/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/&#34; title=&#34;Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM&#34;&gt;upgrading the ASA IOS version with the ASDM&lt;/a&gt;. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/&#34;&gt;CCNA Security - 640-554&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/258103/cisco_patches_vulnerabilities_in_vpn_client_security_appliances.html&#34;&gt;Cisco Patches Vulnerabilities in VPN Client, Security Appliances&lt;/a&gt; (pcworld.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prweb.com/releases/prweb2010/10/prweb4598974.htm&#34;&gt;New Cisco ASA Step-by-Step Guide Simplifies Configuration&lt;/a&gt; (prweb.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/28/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-28 19:25:03&#34;&gt;Jun 4, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Password Recovery – Cisco IOS Routers | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2012/07/21/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-07-21 11:04:27&#34;&gt;Jul 6, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Basic Cisco ASA Overview (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
