<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SSH on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/ssh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SSH on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 02:43:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/ssh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rancid can’t SSH to older ISRs?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/03/03/rancid-cant-ssh-to-older-isrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 02:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/03/03/rancid-cant-ssh-to-older-isrs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Well its 2016 and you still have that one-of-kind Cisco ISR 2811 or 3845 running in the environment? You followed and installed Rancid, all the new stuff works like it should but when you try to connect to that “one-of-kind” 2811 with Rancid it closes the connection... :/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple fix and the bug is reported here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=740307&#34;&gt;LINK.&lt;/a&gt; The bug is something with OpenSSH which is installed on your Linux operating system and Rancid rides on top of it. You would have the same issue if you just tried SSH to thing directly from your Rancid machine. The bug looked to be fixed starting OpenSSH 6.9 but as right now at least in Centos 7 the version it goes up to is OpenSSH 6.6. You can verify this by using sshd -V to output the OpenSSH version you are using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple fix is to modify the ssh_config file usually located at &lt;strong&gt;/etc/ssh/ssh_config&lt;/strong&gt; and at the bottom of the file put the host you are connecting to. Copy what you have in your router.db file meaning if you are using DNS names put DNS names of the devices that won’t connect into this file. If you are using IP address use IP address in this file. In this example I’m using IP addresses and DNS names, the following is at the bottom of the ssh_config file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt;# Custom Rancid Configuration (Issues with Connecting SSH with Older Devices)
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;# Bug Report 740307 https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=740307
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;#
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;Host 192.168.3.1
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;    KexAlgorithms=diffie-hellman-group14-sha1
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;#
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;Host Router03.example.com
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;    KexAlgorithms=diffie-hellman-group14-sha1
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt;#
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;Host Router02.example.com
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;    KexAlgorithms=diffie-hellman-group14-sha1
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;#
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should be good to go after that. You can test this by using clogin or by connecting directly. If you noticed on the bug report you could also up the Diffie-Hellman size to 4096 on the router itself by using the &lt;strong&gt;ip ssh dh min size 4096&lt;/strong&gt; command as well. I hope this helps if you ever need it :)&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy Running-Config From PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/08/16/copy-running-config-from-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 03:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/08/16/copy-running-config-from-powershell/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/logo-powershell.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/logo-powershell.png&#34; alt=&#34;powershell-logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I will be up front on this I really never had that much experience with power-shell scripts but I wanted a quick way to connect to routers and switches and issue the show run command and have that script output everything into one file. So some searching around I decided to drive into power-shell to see if I could get something to work. One of my first problems was to find a way to have power-shell &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell&#34; title=&#34;Secure Shell&#34;&gt;SSH&lt;/a&gt; into my devices I found out about SharpSSH which look interesting but I also found SSH.NET. So I went with my second choice and decided to try the SSH.NET module. I would not of went to far if I did not stumble across this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powershelladmin.com/wiki/Main_Page&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; which helped out a lot. Here is the direct &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powershelladmin.com/wiki/SSH_from_PowerShell_using_the_SSH.NET_library&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; of the Wiki page I was referring to. Also here is the code I quickly put together and I can bet there is a better way to setup this script but since I am pretty green when it comes to scripting this is what I could come up with. Feel free to edit and use, if you have suggestions on how to improve this script let me know by commenting below. [code language=&amp;quot;powershell&amp;quot;] #--------------------------------------------------------------------------- # PowerShell Script for Connecting using SSH to Network Devices and to # issue one or multiple commands. # RECOMMENDED USE: Automating Backups # ATTENTION: Module SSH-Sessions must be in the Default System32 # Location: Windows\system32\WindowsPowerShell\v1.0\Modules # MORE INFORMATION: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powershelladmin.com/wiki/SSH&#34;&gt;http://www.powershelladmin.com/wiki/SSH&lt;/a&gt;_from_PowerShell_using_the_SSH.NET_library #--------------------------------------------------------------------------- # Settings below should not need to be changed, however feel free to add-on! # Lets run by some house rules like asking what to do if an error occurs. $ErrorActionPreference =&amp;quot;Inquire&amp;quot; # Do you even have the SSH-Sessions Module? Let’s check before we continue. Import-Module SSH-Sessions # With the output file that is created by this script lets timestamp # the current Year, Month and Day and put it as part of the filename. $time =&amp;quot;$(get-date -f yyyy-MM-dd)&amp;quot; # Let&#39;s put in something in front of the date timestamp of the soon to be # created file defualt is &amp;quot;config&amp;quot; $filename =&amp;quot;config&amp;quot; # By default the type of file created is a text file. $ext =&amp;quot;.txt&amp;quot; #--------------------------------------------------------------------------- # START WITH CUSTOM CONFIGURATION # Where do you want the created file to be placed? The current user running # this script will need # access to that location. Also this script will not create folders if the # path does not exist expect an error # A good example to place the created files would be &amp;quot;C:\Cisco-Backups&amp;quot; $filepath =&amp;quot;&amp;quot; # Depending on the amount of devices you want to connect, this part of the # script could be lengthy. # To set this up follow the example. # $d1 =&amp;quot;192.168.1.1&amp;quot; # This is setting up a variable called &amp;quot;d1&amp;quot; followed by the IP address of # the device you would connect with SSH. # Each device will have a different variable if you have five devices it # would look like the following: # $d2 =&amp;quot;192.168.2.1&amp;quot; # $d3 =&amp;quot;192.168.3.1&amp;quot; # $d4 =&amp;quot;192.168.4.1&amp;quot; # $d5 =&amp;quot;192.168.5.1&amp;quot; # $d6 =&amp;quot;192.168.6.1&amp;quot; # Below is your custom list of devices that you want to connect with SSH. $d1 =&amp;quot;&amp;quot; # Depending on the environment each device may have a different account to # log in. # For simplicity&#39;s sake it is recommended to use one custom account for # all logins. # However you can specify different account logins per device. Follow the example. # $u1 =&amp;quot;admin&amp;quot; # $u2 =&amp;quot;bob&amp;quot; # This example shows two different username accounts it recommended to # match these up with the device you would be connecting to, # for example &amp;quot;d1&amp;quot; uses &amp;quot;u1&amp;quot;, etc. # Below is your custom list of login account names that each device # will use, if all devices use the same account just specify one variable. $u1 =&amp;quot;&amp;quot; # Depending on the environment each device may have a different password # to log in. For simplicity&#39;s sake it is recommended to use one password # for all logins. However you can specify different passwords per device. # Follow the example. # $p1 =&amp;quot;password123&amp;quot; # $p2 =&amp;quot;P@$$w0rd987&amp;quot; # This example shows two different passwords it recommended to match # these up with the device and username you would be connecting to, # for example &amp;quot;d1&amp;quot; uses &amp;quot;u1&amp;quot; which use &amp;quot;p1&amp;quot; etc. # Below is your custom list of passwords that each device will use, # if all devices use the same password just specify one variable. $p1 =&amp;quot;&amp;quot; # Depending on the amount of devices you want to connect, this part # of the script could be lengthy. The command to connect with SSH is # &amp;quot;New-SshSession&amp;quot; We have to specify the device to connect, the username # to use along with the password. Follow the example. # New-SshSession $d1 -Username $u1 -Password &amp;quot;$p1&amp;quot; # New-SshSession $d2 -Username $u2 -Password &amp;quot;$p2&amp;quot; # This example shows that we are going to be connecting with two devices, # with two different usernames and passwords. # If you are using the same username and password on all devices it would # follow this example which is using the same # variable for the username and password. # New-SshSession $d1 -Username $u1 -Password &amp;quot;$p1&amp;quot; # New-SshSession $d2 -Username $u1 -Password &amp;quot;$p1&amp;quot; # Below is your custom list that specifies the device to connect to, the # username and password. If all devices use the same username and password # just speifiy the same variable. New-SshSession $d1 -Username $u1 -Password &amp;quot;$p1&amp;quot; # DONE WITH CUSTOM CONFIGURATION #--------------------------------------------------------------------------- # What command to you want to run on all devices defualt is the &#39;show run&#39; # command. $c1 =&amp;quot;show run&amp;quot; # Lets run the command that we configured and output all of that into one # file. $Results = Invoke-Sshcommand -InvokeOnAll -Command &amp;quot;$c1&amp;quot; | Out-File &amp;quot;$filepath$filename-$time$ext&amp;quot; # We are done running commands on these devices lets close the connection. Remove-SshSession -RemoveAll # Close out of PowerShell exit [/code] I have tested this out and it works pretty good, I was able to test up to 12 devices at the same time. Since this script does not have any &amp;quot;if&amp;quot; statements and other smarts to it you do have to change a configuration option on your router or switch to go right into Privileged EXEC when the account logs in. This is done by usually saying privilege level 15 when setting up a user account on the router or switch. I hope this information is helpful and I will see if I can re-work this script as it is a work in progress with power-shell :) What are other ways to backup your configuration, what tools and or scripts have you used in the past?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://reviews.cnet.com/8301-13727_7-57524257-263/ssh-tip-send-commands-remotely/?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&#34;&gt;SSH tip: Send commands remotely&lt;/a&gt; (reviews.cnet.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://community.spiceworks.com/topic/370296-what-actually-is-required-to-get-the-configuration-from-a-cisco-device&#34;&gt;What actually is required to get the configuration from a Cisco device?&lt;/a&gt; (community.spiceworks.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://myvirtualife.net/2013/08/07/how-to-enable-ssh-root-access-in-horizon-workspace-virtual-machines/&#34;&gt;How to enable SSH root access in Horizon Workspace Virtual Machines&lt;/a&gt; (myvirtualife.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure SSH on Dell Power-Connect</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/26/how-to-configure-ssh-on-dell-power-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 15:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/26/how-to-configure-ssh-on-dell-power-connect/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/keys.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/keys.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;keys&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Although not dealing with Cisco directly Dell switches are around in network closets and with my limited experience with them I thought this would be a perfect blog post to show the differences between Dell and Cisco. I like to think of Dell CLI like a dumb downed version of the Cisco CLI so I had some time to play around with a Dell 6248P switch and wanted to figure out how to get SSH working in the thing. Couple searches around the web and some guess and check methods I was able to get SSH working and disable telnet sessions from connecting to the switch. Compared to a Cisco switch dell has few commands when configuring SSH. This switch was configured with an IP address and user name and passwords before I touched it but I don&#39;t think would too hard to figure out. :) So if you never touched a Dell switch like I have but worked with Cisco CLI you&#39;ll find that it is similar which is nice feature, I used telnet to remote into the switch which is insecure and sends information in plain text, which is why we are moving to SSH. So after typing the username and password I was prompted a familiar sign. I typed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;enable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to get into privilege EXEC mode. [code]EdgeSW0D&amp;gt;enable[/code] From there I found a command that will display your public keys on the device that is if you have any. The command was &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;show crypto key mypubkey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Notice how no keys have been configured yet) [code]EdgeSW0D#show crypto key mypubkey RSA Key is not Generated yet ! DSA Key is not Generated yet ![/code] From privilege EXEC mode I typed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;configure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the prompt, once I was in there I found the crypto command and generated some DSA keys with the following command: **&lt;em&gt;crypto key generate dsa&lt;/em&gt; ** [code]EdgeSW0D#configure EdgeSW0D(config)#crypto key generate dsa DSA key generation started, this may take a few minutes................ DSA key generation complete.[/code] Under the configuration mode I also noticed the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ip ssh server&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; command but once I hit enter I got the following error: [code]EdgeSW0D(config)#ip ssh server SSH could not be enabled.[/code] It took me awhile to figure this issue out, I played around with a another Dell switch and at least to what I found out online and my guess and check methods I noticed that the command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ip ssh server&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; works only when both DSA and RSA keys are configured. It does not matter that order as long as switch has both of them and the version of the Dell switch I used when writing post this was the latest version 3.3. Once I created RSA keys with the already created DSA keys the command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ip ssh server&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; went through. To create RSA keys it is the same command but substitute DSA with RSA. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;crypto key generate rsa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [code]EdgeSW0D(config)#crypto key generate rsa RSA key generation started, this may take a few minutes..... RSA key generation complete. EdgeSW0D(config)#ip ssh server[/code] Go ahead and leave the telnet session open and connect to the switch via SSH to verify SSH is working so you don&#39;t lock yourself out. I issued the command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;show sessions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to see that I have two sessions with this switch Telnet and SSH. [code]EdgeSW0D#show sessions Connection Host Address Port ---------- ----------------------- ----------------------- ----------- 0 172.27.227.67 172.27.227.67 Telnet 1 172.27.227.67 172.27.227.67 SSH [/code] Once I verified that SSH is working I can disable telnet so only SSH connections are allowed and accepted, with the following command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ip telnet server disable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. [code]EdgeSW0D#configure EdgeSW0D(config)#ip telnet server disable[/code] That&#39;s it! If you want a refresh on how Cisco does it check the blog post I posted back in March &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/29/configuring-ssh/&#34; title=&#34;Configuring SSH&#34;&gt;Configuring SSH&lt;/a&gt;. Like always I hope this information is helpful and if you have an idea of the next topic let me know by posting below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pauldotcom.com/2011/08/how-a-week-old-privilege-escal.html&#34;&gt;What do you mean privilege escalation is not HIGH RISK?&lt;/a&gt; (pauldotcom.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tychoish.com/rhizome/9-awesome-ssh-tricks/&#34;&gt;9 Awesome SSH Tricks&lt;/a&gt; (tychoish.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://moocode.com/posts/5-simple-two-factor-ssh-authentication&#34;&gt;Simple Two-Factor SSH Authentication&lt;/a&gt; (moocode.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symkat.com/ssh-tips-and-tricks-you-need&#34;&gt;imabonehead: Symkat - SSH: Tips And Tricks You Need&lt;/a&gt; (symkat.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring SSH</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/29/configuring-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 15:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/29/configuring-ssh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Today this tutorial is going be talking about how to configure SSH on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/&#34; title=&#34;Cisco&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; router or switch. SSH or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell&#34; title=&#34;Secure Shell&#34;&gt;Secure Shell&lt;/a&gt; encrypts the data that is sent from the terminal application to the device. Making if far more safer when it is compared to telnet which sends the data in plain text. To add support for SSH to a Cisco router or switch, the device needs some added information then just &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Password&#34; title=&#34;Password&#34;&gt;passwords&lt;/a&gt;. The device will need a username and password, this can be configured on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RADIUS&#34; title=&#34;RADIUS&#34;&gt;AAA server&lt;/a&gt; (Authentication Authorization and Accounting) or on the device locally this tutorial will focus on locally configured &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;User (computing)&#34;&gt;usernames&lt;/a&gt; and passwords. To set up SSH you need to configure that following information for the purpose of this tutorial the username will be &lt;em&gt;ciscoskills&lt;/em&gt; and the password will be &lt;em&gt;cisco&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first thing you need to do is change the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telnet&#34; title=&#34;Telnet&#34;&gt;vty&lt;/a&gt; lines in the device (router/switch) depending on the device you will have more vty lines. This command will check its local database for usernames and passwords. The command is entered under (config-line)# prompt with &lt;strong&gt;login local.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next step depends if you want to still allow telnet connections to the device (router/switch). This command is entered under (config-line)# prompt which is &lt;strong&gt;transport input telnet ssh.&lt;/strong&gt; If you only want ssh connections then type the following in &lt;strong&gt;transport input ssh&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must enter an at least one username and password for the device (router/switch). This command is entered in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;global configuration mode&lt;/a&gt; (config)# which for this example the username will be &lt;em&gt;ciscoskills&lt;/em&gt; and the password will be &lt;em&gt;cisco&lt;/em&gt;. The command would be &lt;strong&gt;username ciscoskills password cisco&lt;/strong&gt; in global configuration mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You also must configure a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name&#34; title=&#34;Domain name&#34;&gt;DNS domain&lt;/a&gt; name for this example the domain will be ciscoskills.net. This command is entered in global configuration mode (config)# which for this example is &lt;strong&gt;ip domain-name ciscoskills.net&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The final command to configure SSH is generate a key pair, This command Is entered in global configuration mode (config)# which is &lt;strong&gt;crypto key generate rsa&lt;/strong&gt;. When asked the question how many bits in the modulus? Cisco documentation likes 1024. The more bits you have the longer the key and harder to crack. The default is 512, and probaly best to go for 2048.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what the follow commands would look like in the below output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt;Router_or_Switch#
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;Router_or_Switch#configure terminal
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z.
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;Router_or_Switch(config)#line vty 0 4
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;Router_or_Switch(config-line)#login local
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;Router_or_Switch(config-line)#transport input telnet ssh
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;Router_or_Switch(config-line)#exit
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;Router_or_Switch(config)#username ciscoskills&amp;amp;nbsp;password cisco
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt;Router_or_Switch(config)#ip domain-name ciscoskills.net
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;Router_or_Switch(config)#crypto key generate rsa
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;The name for the keys will be: Router_or_Switch.ciscoskills.net
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;Choose the size of the key modulus in the range of 360 to 2048 for your
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;General Purpose Keys. Choosing a key modulus greater than 512 may take
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;a few minutes.
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;How many bits in the modulus \[512\]: 1024
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;% Generating 1024 bit RSA keys, keys will be non-exportable...\[OK\]
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;Router_or_Switch(config)#exit
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;*Mar 1 0:4:8.988: %SSH-5-ENABLED: SSH 1.99 has been enabled
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;21&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;%SYS-5-CONFIG\_I: Configured from console by console
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it! This guide is meant for Cisco labs, but you would follow this information to set up a SSH connection with in a production network. It you would like more information a simple web search would work. You can also find more documentation at Cisco.com. I hope this information was helpful and if you have suggestions or comments? Let me hear them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.azoft.com/spotlight/2011/04/18/ssh-ubuntu-100.html&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;How to speed up the login via SSH in Ubuntu by 100 times | Azoft Spotlight&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-04-18 02:07:04&#34;&gt;Apr 1, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configuring SSH (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-04-18 10:28:12&#34;&gt;Apr 1, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configuring SSH (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
