<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CCNA on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/ccna/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CCNA on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 12:30:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/ccna/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuring EIGRP - Named Mode</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2017/05/25/configuring-eigrp-named-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 12:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2017/05/25/configuring-eigrp-named-mode/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From its older brother IGRP which was developed in 1980s to overcome the limitations of RIP, EIGRP was an &amp;quot;Enhanced&amp;quot; IGRP protocol. The main purpose of EIGRP was to overcome the limitations of classful networks and make EIGRP a classless routing protocol. During designing of this protocol a different convergence algorithm was used making EIGRP that &amp;quot;hybrid&amp;quot; between distance-vector and link-state routing protocols. In this post we&#39;ll go over a basic design and setup for EIGRP, however instead of using the &amp;quot;classic way&amp;quot; let&#39;s look at configuring EIGRP using named mode which is available in Cisco IOS starting in version 15.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring OSPF - The Basics</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/08/13/configuring-ospf-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/08/13/configuring-ospf-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have to start somewhere so let’s look at the basics of configuring OSPF. Remember OSPF is an IGP (Interior Gateway Protocol) and allows packet authentication as well as IP multicast when sending and receiving updates. In this post we are configuring OSPF in a single area. In this topology we have four routers and two PCs. The PCs subnet are 172.30.2.0/24 and 172.30.3.0/24. We have point to point connections between each router.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Rancid and ViewVC on Centos 7</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/01/03/install-rancid-and-viewvc-on-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/01/03/install-rancid-and-viewvc-on-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I want to walk though the steps to install Rancid on CentOS 7 minimal. Rancid is a great tool to help monitor a device configuration for any changes. It also keeps track of them by using CVS (Concurrent Version System) for backups, so you can go back and compare versions or revert to a previous configuration. Rancid supports multiple hardware from Cisco, HP, Dell, Juniper and more. This is all open-source so you can create custom scripts or add commands to really make this a personal repository that fits your company.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up GNS3 1.1 on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/10/28/setting-up-gns3-1.1-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 12:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/10/28/setting-up-gns3-1.1-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s only been a week since GNS3 1.0 was released and it&#39;s already been updated to 1.1 so in this post I have Ubuntu 14.04 LTS with the latest updates and its time to set up GNS3. GNS3 is an open source tool that helps network professionals run a virtual network right on their computer, GNS3 is not a simulation program but rather an emulation program. So if you wanted to test a configuration change but did not want to run it on production you can run it in GNS3 instead.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 1.0 Public is Out</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/10/21/gns3-1.0-public-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 20:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/10/21/gns3-1.0-public-is-out/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get your IOS, IOU, XRV, 1000v, HP, Juniper, Arista, and other images ready because that&#39;s the beauty of GNS3, it&#39;s here and ready to download. I&#39;m excited for this release although the last post I did was In May of 2014, which was about getting GNS3 Alpha 3 working on Windows, you can see the full post here: GNS3 Alpha – Install and Setup. I have followed the GNS3 releases throughout the six months of them releasing Alpha and beta releases, as well as looking at changlogs of each release.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some QoS Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/08/05/some-qos-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 02:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/08/05/some-qos-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When I started taking classes from the Cisco CCNA Discover books years ago, I remember for the first part of the book it talked about QoS and the theory behind it. To me QoS was a very interesting but after a chapter or two we never mentioned it again or really knew how to configure it. It seemed like it disappeared but it always something being tested on so we know it was there, somewhere… QoS can be a little boring and it does get a reputation of being difficult to understand, like where and how do I implement QoS?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 1.0 Campaign</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/11/21/gns3-1.0-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 06:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/11/21/gns3-1.0-campaign/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s been almost 24 hours since GNS3 launched a campaign to bring in funds to support the open source network simulator and bring it up to version 1.0. A lot of new features are on the list, like switching, cloud processing, hassle free configuration, labs/training materials and 3rd party integrations. All of which are in the works for this new version added along with some pretty cool plug-ins. As of writing this post they are at $106,973 dollars which is 300 percent over funded!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring EtherChannel (PAgb)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 15:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bundling physical links into one logical link is a common practice to up the bandwidth between switches, you may have this also configured on a server to bundle connections as well. In this tutorial I have two 2960 switches both of them trunking all VLANs on two gigabit ports. So in the end game is get 2gbps instead of 1gbps between switches while using Cisco’s proprietary protocol PAgb. It is important to remember that both of these protocols (PAgb and LACP) are link aggregation protocols only, their job is to make sure that EtherChannel is setup correctly by negotiating.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA 2-0 What&#39;s New?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/09/30/ccna-2-0-whats-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/09/30/ccna-2-0-whats-new/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I brought this topic up in March of this year (See original post) but I wanted to re-post it to add some information because as of today this was your last day to pass the older CCNA exams. Cisco has a refreshed all the CCNA Routing and Switching exams. That includes the ICND1 (640-822), the ICND2 (640-816), and the all in wonder exam (640-816). You will notice some old references no longer mentioned on this refresh, so let&#39;s go over the differences and some of the changes Cisco has made to the associate-level certification track.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Go Professional with Cisco Certs?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/09/14/why-go-professional-with-cisco-certs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 18:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/09/14/why-go-professional-with-cisco-certs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I have had the opportunity to take and thankfully pass Cisco certifications at the associate levels and there is one more associate exam, the CCNA Data Center which hopefully I will get later next year. While looking at the CCNA Data Center exam I also glanced over the professional arena that Cisco offers and if you’re like me I always like learning new things especially in technical field. Getting those “aha moments” once in a while makes it worth it, but beyond just over all knowledge of additional technologies why would you go on taking a professional Cisco cert?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy Running-Config From PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/08/16/copy-running-config-from-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 03:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/08/16/copy-running-config-from-powershell/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I will be up front on this I really never had that much experience with power-shell scripts but I wanted a quick way to connect to routers and switches and issue the show run command and have that script output everything into one file. So some searching around I decided to drive into power-shell to see if I could get something to work. One of my first problems was to find a way to have power-shell SSH into my devices I found out about SharpSSH which look interesting but I also found SSH.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Version 2.0 Refresh</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/03/26/ccna-version-2.0-refresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 05:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/03/26/ccna-version-2.0-refresh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I think we knew it was coming at some point and Cisco has recently announced a refresh for the 640-822 (ICND1), 640-816 (ICND2) and the all in one 640-802 (CCNA) the last day to take these tests and get certified are September 30th of 2013. You will notice some old references no longer mentioned on this refresh, so let&#39;s go over the differences and some of the changes Cisco has made to the associate-level certification track.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive your Configuration</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/01/22/archive-your-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 05:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/01/22/archive-your-configuration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It is important to save your router and switch configuration but what happens if the device fails or if you saved a configuration mistake, without having to manually worry about it? Well if your Cisco router or switch has Cisco IOS 12.3T and higher you would be able to set up an auto archive within the flash memory of the unit or you can send that configuration file to a server that does either FTP, HTTP, SCP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure DHCP on a Cisco Router</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/12/01/configure-dhcp-on-a-cisco-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 16:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/12/01/configure-dhcp-on-a-cisco-router/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Data-connect-computer In this short tutorial let&#39;s configure a DHCP server on a Cisco Router. Why would we want to do that? Well configuring a basic DHCP server on a router is a good idea if this is a branch/satellite office or just a small business. There are some pros and cons of configuring DHCP on a Cisco Router so let&#39;s briefly discuss them and then start configuring. Putting DHCP on a router is pretty easy and that&#39;s one advantage of setting up DHCP no need to setup a Linux or Windows server.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Data Center</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 02:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco has now introduced another associate level exam, the CCNA Data Center exam. Like the name suggests this exam focuses on the Data Center and if passed you can continue up the stack by also taking the CCNP Data Center exam which was also recently introduced as well. Still want more a little more, if you are up for the challenge you can also tackle the CCIE Data Center which is an exam that was introduced in March of 2012.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 01:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Cisco Lab When it comes to learning and getting started with Cisco there are some tools that will help out a lot like Packet Tracer, GNS3 and other emulators. These are great tools for that &amp;quot;simulation&amp;quot; of hands on learning, but you can&#39;t always stay in that area. I find it best to get hands on with &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; Cisco Gear and so with this post I&#39;ll go through my current setup of what I have and ask that question when it is a good time to get a lab?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why IPv6?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/08/22/why-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 01:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/08/22/why-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although this protocol has been around since 1996 it has been anticipated that IPv4 would one day be exhausted. In February 2011 the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA) assigned the last /8 address blocks to the Regional Internet Registries so time is getting close but you have heard this warning before right? Let&#39;s go over IPv6 at least just an overview some the features and changes compared to IPv4 because one day it will happen it&#39;s just a matter of when.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password Recovery – Cisco IOS Routers</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/07/21/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/07/21/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure In this post I want to cover how to recover passwords on a Cisco IOS Router. This is helpful in lab environments as well as production environments. Although this method can be used the correct &amp;quot;legal&amp;quot; way you can also use this method to break into these devices &amp;quot;illegally&amp;quot; if you have physical console access to the device. However to get into it physical power must be turned off first causing a disruption in the environment, let get started!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICND2 - Passed!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 16:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I just passed my ICND2 exam, I&#39;m now CCNA certified!
This was a long road to travel over a year ago I passed ICND1 which I recived the CCENT certification but with just general life getting in the way I also saw my chance of getting CCNA status stepping further in the distance. If you read how I passed ICND1 will find that the way I studied for this exam was totally different from studying for the ICND1.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2 – The Joys of Subnetttting – VLSM!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 02:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So here we are on Part 2 of subnetting. What makes me laugh is that I really think a lot of people over think this stuff, and the fact that I mispelled subnetting! (Really? 4Ts) It&#39;s really not the complicated and it should not scare you. Another thing to mention is that usually in the real world you usually have calculators and another pair of eyes to double-check your work unlike the exam you will need to fully understand it if you would like to pass the ICND2 or the CCNA test.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1 - The Joys of Subnetting!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 20:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since network technicians work with IP addressing, it is hugely important to understand subnetting. I remember back when I started to learn subnetting it was confusing and I wanted nothing to do with it. The thing that made me change my mind was after I understood it and how important it is. In the &amp;quot;Cisco world&amp;quot; they don&#39;t cover useless topics...right? ;) there is always a reason why they expect you to know this and it&#39;s not just for the exams.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIGRP… The Basics</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/29/eigrp-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 02:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/29/eigrp-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Routing_Updates Enhanced Interior Gateway Routing Protocol (EIGRP) is an impressive set of features for IP Routing, which converges quickly and is on par and sometimes faster than OSPF. This routing protocol requires less processing time, less memory, and less network design than compared to OSPF. What&#39;s the catch? This protocol is Cisco proprietary, if you have a network that uses non-Cisco routers, EIGRP will not and cannot be used on those routers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HDLC vs. PPP</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/22/hdlc-vs.-ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 03:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/22/hdlc-vs.-ppp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HDLC and PPP are considered to be in layer 2 of the OSI model. There are some differences between which will be describe in this post, If you would like to learn more about at least the basic configuration of PPP including PAP and CHAP check out the post I wrote about year ago. (Basic PPP Configuration) HDLC was first developed by the ISO Cisco tweaked the protocol sometimes called cHDLC and because of this it only works with Cisco equipment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trunking Administrative Modes</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/11/trunking-administrative-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 22:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/11/trunking-administrative-modes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            cisco-switch-blade When looking at the CCNA it is good idea to get a hold of trunking between switches along with that there are a couple of administrative modes that each physical interface on Cisco switch can be when you are trunking between them. Remember that when we are trunking it usually carries all VLANs (This can be changed) but there are different ways to make trunking between links happen. When you are in an interface on a Cisco switch you can change the operational mode of that interface by issuing the switchport mode command.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Tiers</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/21/the-three-tiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 19:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/21/the-three-tiers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network_switch Working towards the CCNA Cisco talks about a hierarchical network there are three layers to this design. Access Layer, distribution layer and the core layer. Each of them have their own set of functions and is also considered to be a best practice when the network continues to grow and for redundancy along with just a better way to manage it. The Access layer is the layer that devices connect to, such as PCs, printers, and IP Phones.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Understanding of EtherChannel</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/04/basic-understanding-of-etherchannel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/04/basic-understanding-of-etherchannel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network cables Let&#39;s start the New Year with understanding EtherChannel which is having more than one link connected to a server, switch, or router and treating it like one logical link. This is a fault-tolerant technique that is becoming a common setup in highly available, core devices. Cisco has come up with their own proprietary version call EtherChannel. The open standard that IEEE approved is 802.3ad which works with other venders and is often called LAG for short.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSPF...What a Protocol!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/11/02/ospf...what-a-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 18:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/11/02/ospf...what-a-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For today let&#39;s discuss a routing protocol that was being thought of in 1987 by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF). OSPF currently has three versions and the first version was in the 1980s when the internet was still being used for research. What is interesting about the first version of OSPF is although one version ran on routers the other type of version ran on UNIX computers. When OSPFv2 come out in the 1990s the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) was working on another routing protocol called IS-IS (Intermediate System-to-Intermediate System).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of WAN Links</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/19/types-of-wan-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 16:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/19/types-of-wan-links/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve found this table that I created a while ago and it lists common WAN connections that businesses use. I have used this table like a reference guide to familiar myself into other protocols. People don&#39;t think of it much but the WAN is a different beast compared the LAN as it uses different protocols besides Ethernet. The WAN or wide area network is what connects us to remote locations within a organization.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Store-and-Forward vs. Cut-Through Switching</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/05/store-and-forward-vs.-cut-through-switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/05/store-and-forward-vs.-cut-through-switching/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network-Cable-Color Switching in the network can happen in two ways, these layer-two devices send frames but they can forward them in different ways. These different modes have positive and negative effects which depend on the type of network environment that runs through them! Store-and-forward is just like the name suggests, the switch receives a frame on a port and stores the frame in it&#39;s memory buffer until the frame has been completely received.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome CCT (Cisco Certified Technician Certification)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/21/welcome-cct-cisco-certified-technician-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/21/welcome-cct-cisco-certified-technician-certification/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Switching gears for today, Cisco has introduced a certification for onsite support technicians, who need product-specific technical skills to diagnose, restore, repair, and replace critical Cisco equipment. This certification which was introduced this summer now has questions about it from CLN (Cisco Learning Network) and other Cisco sites. So what is this new cert and any changes to ICND1 or ICND2? Short answer is no, this certification is on par with ICND1 or CCENT according to Cisco but is focused on support groups like TAC (Technical Assistance Center), NOC (Network Operations Centers) and 3rd party support.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the month of August I talked about the &amp;quot;beginnings&amp;quot; of layer two redundancy mainly looking at the basic foundations and fundamentals of having layer two redundancy. Let&#39;s continue are discussion about redundancy in the layer two environment. To review what STP does (Spanning Tree Protocol) it works at layer two of the OSI model. If more than one path is available in the network the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until the active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link-State Protocols</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/31/link-state-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/31/link-state-protocols/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network-Cables Weeks ago and maybe months :), I talked about distance vector protocols and with that you probably got the feeling that when using a distance vector protocol it does not give a full network graphical representation of the entire network. Only the directly connected routes can&#39;t remember? Check out this post Distance Vector Routing. Link state protocols are faster to converge network changes compared to distance vector however when compared to distance vector setup they can be harder to set up, maintain, and troubleshoot when problems arise.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Codes of ICMP</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post I wanted to talk about the widely used Ping command. Which is one of the best methods (I think) to begin network troubleshooting. When part of the network goes down it is sometimes hard to figure out why? When you issue the ping command or the extended ping command in a Cisco router several ICMP codes can come up on the router. Let&#39;s discuss them! The first status code &amp;quot;!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network-diagram In a perfect world we would never need redundancy on a network infrastructure, but as you know as well as I know we don&#39;t live in a perfect world. Hardware will eventually fail, bottlenecks will appear, and the speed of our network will become slower when we max the bandwidth on links. So having redundancy in routers, connections, and having a hierarchy network is one of best choices to make when improving the efficiently of the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the Cisco Discovery Protocol. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between router or switch is set up correctly at least up to layer two in the OSI model. This also helps us discover Cisco devices that are in are network and which interfaces these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed information CDP gives out which helps you has a network administrator build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Vector Routing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 16:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Couple weeks ago I talked about routing protocols and in the post I mentioned two routing protocol features distance vector and link state. Although these protocols fundamentally do the same thing by getting information on remote networks they get this information in a different way. For today let&#39;s introduce distance vector routing. With a distance vector routing protocol, a router learns about a route to a different network (that&#39;s the purpose of a routing protocol) the router only knows the &amp;quot;distance&amp;quot; to get there this is usually called the metric.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classful vs. Classless Routing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 16:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud-Computing-icon Before the internet and general networking become popular into what it is now, there were and still are routing protocols that only do classful routing. What is classful routing? When I was talking about Dynamic Routing earlier (See the post Dynamic Routing Protocols) I mentioned there was a difference between classful routing and classless routing. So in today&#39;s post let&#39;s focus on these two but important topics when using routing protocols.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS Commands</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 17:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the master list of some of the many Cisco IOS Commands that go with the CCNA track. This list also talks about what each command does in brief detail. You may also find that some commands may or may not be used for a CCNA level but offer some important information. If you don&#39;t know what a command does or understand it, I would look at Cisco documentation. Since this is a pretty big list of commands you can see the links to move to the different sections within this page.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Wireless LAN Security</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/18/basic-wireless-lan-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 16:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/18/basic-wireless-lan-security/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wireless-Security-Icon Although having a wireless LAN sounds like a wonderful idea, there are things that need to be implemented like security. A wireless LAN can be uncontrollable has it is just radio waves and anybody can receive them. Having and using good security practices can help you be under control of your wireless LAN. Not having any security in a wireless LAN environment will cause anybody to have access to the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VTP</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some people hate it, some people love it. It&#39;s the Cisco proprietary VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) which in short means that Cisco switches can exchange VLAN configuration, instead of manually configuring each switch with the same VLANs. I also suggest if you don&#39;t know what a VLAN is check out the post Creating VLANs Let&#39;s get right into understanding VTP. The thing that makes VTP shine is what it does, although simple to understand it saves time by automatically distributing VLAN information.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Routing Protocols</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 16:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dynamic Routing If you ever wanted to set up a network manually, you will quickly find how much overhead is required to get PCs, printers, and other network equipment. That&#39;s where dynamic routing protocols come into play although they are helpful I strongly urge you to understand static routing first. (See the post Configure Static Routing) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s get the foundation of understanding dynamic routing protocols. By definition a routing protocol is a set of messages, rules and algorithms used by routers for the overall purpose of learning routes to other networks not physically connected to it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Static Routing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plugging Cisco routers together and hoping they work out of the box is not something you should hope for. A router can learn about networks in two ways, manually from configured static routers which we will talk about today and dynamic routing protocols which will talk about on Wednesday. Let&#39;s get started! Static routes are not that uncommon they at first need some attention to get set up but after it is working nothing needs to change.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding AAA</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/29/understanding-aaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/29/understanding-aaa/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            User The wonderful AAA which in the Cisco world means, Authentication, Authorization, and Accounting but what does that really mean? In today&#39;s post that&#39;s what we are going to be talking about. What is AAA and what are the benefits of using it along with what is it? The first &amp;quot;A&amp;quot; of AAA is Authentication which provides the method of identifying users, including login and password dialog, challenge and response, messaging support, and, depending on the security protocol you select, encryption.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Zone Based Firewalls via SDM</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 15:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last month I talked about the fundamentals for understanding zone based firewalls (See the post Understanding Zone Based Firewalls). So for today&#39;s post I want to go ahead and talk about configuring the zone based firewalls but with the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and reduce ownership costs. (See the post Configure Cisco SDM) Instead of talking about what is zone based firewalls lets jump into the configuration of them.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Cisco SDM</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we will be going over the steps that are required to set up the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger) The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. SDM is fairly easy to set up but you still need at least some experience in the router command-line to get SDM working. This tutorial is already assuming that the Cisco SDM program has been installed on the PC.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Learning Labs is Live!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/13/cisco-learning-labs-is-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/13/cisco-learning-labs-is-live/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday was kind of exciting at least for me when I got an e-mail in the morning about Cisco Learning Labs. Studying for the CCNA, CCNP or CCIP is in itself changeling, but getting that hands-on experience is a another problem! When money is short that last thing you want to do is spend it on routers and switches, and most of them on eBay are used and the risk of failing devices makes it a scary choice.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11n</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/11/802.11n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/11/802.11n/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On this Monday let&#39;s wrap up the 802.11 wireless standards, Friday I talked about the 802.11g (See the post 802.11g) and before that I talked about the 802.11b (See the post 802.11b ) I also talked about 802.11a, (See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of last week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So let&#39;s end the discussion and talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11g</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/08/802.11g/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/08/802.11g/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well again we are continuing the discussion about the wireless standards. Yesterday I talked about 802.11b (See the post 802.11b), and before that I talked about 802.11a,(See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Standards) So on this Friday let&#39;s talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11b</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/07/802.11b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 17:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/07/802.11b/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off the discussion, todays post will be talking about 802.11b wireless standard that was developed by IEEE. Yesterday&#39;s post we talked about the 802.11a standard. (See the post 802.11a) We also we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I went over some Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So now that we are up to speed lets learn about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11a</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/06/802.11a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/06/802.11a/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing the discussion about wireless standards we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) Today&#39;s post will be talking about the IEEE 802.11a standard. On Monday I talked about the Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post will be going over the second standard 802.11a out of the five standards that make up the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11 - Legacy</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/05/802.11-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 15:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/05/802.11-legacy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday we talked about the wireless concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post one of the five standards that make up the 802.11. The 802.11 – Legacy has its called now and is not in use anymore by manufactures and is now obsolete was the first wireless standard available for consumer laptops. When the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Wireless Concepts</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/04/basic-wireless-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 15:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/04/basic-wireless-concepts/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            wireless-connection-icon Mobility is now a common thing in a business environment, you no longer are fixed to specific cubicle in the work place anymore. What is also amazing is it will continue to change and become easier for employees to get work done, with their phone, tablet, and laptop computer. But what makes this possible? What is the underlying component? The internet is becoming more available in more locations, coffee shops, airports, and your cell phone service provider, with 3G and 4G speeds.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating VLANs</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today this tutorial is going to be talking about creating VLANs (Virtual Local Area Networks) with a Cisco Catalyst switch. By creating a VLAN you are separating the network, why would you do this? There are some several reasons, like separating your production network from a guest network, and separating a test environment from a production network. This all adds security to your network. You can separate core critical network components from the rest of the production network for added security, easier troubleshooting along with separating or segmenting your network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Port Security</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/31/configuring-port-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/31/configuring-port-security/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure Today this tutorial is going to be talking about how to configure port security on a Cisco Catalyst switch. Port security is one of the first things you can do to keep your network secure from unauthorized access. Port security can restrict devices so only devices you allow are granted access to network resources. If and when an unauthorized device is connected to a port you can decide what you want the switch to do.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collision Domains vs Broadcast Domains</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These different types of domains mean different things and when designing a LAN both of these domains can harm the performance of your network. If you are not aware of the difference between these two, this tutorial should help you out. If you have a small network at your home there is usually the router/modem that is connected via phone line or cable to the ISP that router/modem is then connected to a switch or they even have a switch built into the device.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring SSH</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/29/configuring-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 15:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/29/configuring-ssh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today this tutorial is going be talking about how to configure SSH on a Cisco router or switch. SSH or Secure Shell encrypts the data that is sent from the terminal application to the device. Making if far more safer when it is compared to telnet which sends the data in plain text. To add support for SSH to a Cisco router or switch, the device needs some added information then just passwords.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding UDP</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 16:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Forever ago I talked about TCP (Understanding TCP) and I said that in that post that UDP would be another day, well this is the day where we get to understand UDP, which stands for User Datagram Protocol. UDP is the total opposite of the TCP communication. UDP in short sends information or data without notifying the receiver that its sending data. UDP is considered a connectionless protocol, and does not guarantee the reliability or order the packets like TCP does.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Network Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/17/common-network-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 16:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/17/common-network-attacks/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network attacks have always been around but they are getting more advanced every day. These attacks are also easy to set up and use. In the past these types of attacks would have to be pulled off by someone who really knew about computers and to know what they are doing. That&#39;s a true hacker, now there are programs that do the same damage and sometimes more with a couple clicks of a mouse, so now anybody can bring down a network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a Router Routes</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 17:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial will be going over the basic information of how a router routes IP packets. Routers are used in the OSI layer three or the network layer. These routers have IP addresses and forward IP packets to the proper destination. This guide is somewhat basic and is assuming you have some information of how IP addressing works and along with what routing protocols are. So let&#39;s focus first on how a host or a computer forwards traffic and then look at how a router forwards traffic.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telecommuting Services</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/11/telecommuting-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 17:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/11/telecommuting-services/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is going to talk about the major technologies that make Teleworking or also called telecommuting possible. This is when an employee performs his or her job away from the office, usually from their home office. By doing this it allows personal convenience, less travel to and from the workplace. At an Organization level it provides continuity of operations, Secure, reliable and manageable access to information, cost-effective integration of data, voice, video and applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossover or Straight through?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 18:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The EIA/TIA puts the standards in UTP cable, and when cabling a network there are two standards. T568A and T568B these standards are important when deciding to put a crossover cable or straight through cable This tutorial is going to be talking about when and where to apply these different standards. We are going to be focusing on the UTP cable and with the RJ-45 connectors; in order for the communication to work properly we need to make sure we understand where to put these cables.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding TCP</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/25/understanding-tcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 18:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/25/understanding-tcp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial is going to be talking about the TCP protocol. Every time you connect to a website you are using the HTTP protocol, but below that you are also using a TCP protocol. The nature of TCP is to provide error recovery; there are other services or applications that use TCP. HTTP however is a common protocol that is used in online applications. Remember TCP is not the only protocol in the transport layer of the OSI model, there is another called UDP but that&#39;s another day.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS Routers: Auto Secure</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/17/cisco-ios-routers-auto-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 17:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/17/cisco-ios-routers-auto-secure/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Auto Secure is good for small business or IT administrators that may know how to configure a router with networking protocols, setting up IP interfaces, and networks but really don&#39;t have an understanding of the security aspect of the router. So what Cisco has done is implemented a script called Auto Secure. Auto Secure is based on the questions you answer from the prompt usually &amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;no&amp;quot; answers. Sometimes the script wants a little more information depending on your network configuration.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wonders of Binary</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/15/the-wonders-of-binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 17:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/15/the-wonders-of-binary/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working with IP addresses and subnet masks you need to have an understanding of how binary works. Binary is still used in computers today, when computers use numbers and letters they use them in a binary format. This guide will be going over numbers, and focusing on the IP addresses in how a computer sees that decimal number. Binary is a relatively easy in understanding and is just another way of looking at numbers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TACACS Plus and RADIUS</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/10/tacacs-plus-and-radius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 15:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/10/tacacs-plus-and-radius/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TACACS+ and RADIUS are both used to control access to network resources, but both of these protocols are different in how they operate depending how you want to secure your network. These protocols need to have (AAA) authentication, authorization, and accounting setup on the routers before you can set up these access server protocols. First let&#39;s get some information on why we would need this type of access server protocol setup.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Control Lists</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/07/access-control-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 18:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/07/access-control-lists/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding Access Control Lists is an important role for moving up into the CCNA area. ACLs can get confusing and cause network problems if not implemented correctly. I think what I outlined below explains in a nutshell of what you can expect from ACLs.
I would still read and find more information about ACLs on the web and or reading material (becuase I don&#39;t trust myself!). By securing networks with ACLs you are adding another barrier to your network although ACLs can&#39;t fool-proof your network they add additional level of security from the outside world.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Router Configuration</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/26/basic-router-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 14:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/26/basic-router-configuration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the things you do first when setting up a Cisco router in lab environments and production environments is basic router configuration. By having a good understanding of basic router configuration you will have the essential building blocks and be able to apply additional knowledge upon router configuration. This tutorial is assuming that you are in a lab environment, additional security measures for production environments are recommended and are not discussed in this tutorial.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring NAT (One to One Mapping)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/21/configuring-nat-one-to-one-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 16:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/21/configuring-nat-one-to-one-mapping/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this simple tutorial we are going to be configuring a static NAT which is a one-to-one mapping between an inside IP address and an outside IP address. (One private to one permanent address) Using this type of NAT would be helpful for outside devices accessing your inside devices. (Like a web server) Let&#39;s get started!!
Looking at the topology above you can see that we have a server inside of are network and want people to access this server outside of are network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring PAT</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/19/configuring-pat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 15:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/19/configuring-pat/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial will help you configure PAT (Port Address Translation), or sometimes called NAT (Network Address Translation) with overload on a Cisco router. PAT uses multiple private IP addresses and translates them into a single or very few public IP addresses. This is possible because the private IP addresses are mapped to the port number of the PC. Let&#39;s get started!!!
With the above shown topology we see that we are using two routers called ISP and R1 we also have one switch (default configuration) and a PC connected to R1&#39;s Fa0/0 interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic PPP Configuration</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/18/basic-ppp-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 21:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/18/basic-ppp-configuration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial will be going over Basic Configuration of PPP (Point-to-Point Protocol). This tutorial includes Basic Configuration tasks on a router, Configuring OSPF routing protocol, and Configuring PPP PAP and CHAP authentication. Let&#39;s get started!
We can see in the above diagram we will be using three routers, a loop back connection, two switches (which we will leave them at their default configuration) and two PCs If you are using packet tracer or using real devices than cable the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OSI Layer</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/17/the-osi-layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 20:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/17/the-osi-layer/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It is the foundation that makes understanding networks possible the wonderful OSI layer. While studying for the CCENT exam I had a basic understanding of the OSI Model but when reviewing the material I found myself saying over and over, &amp;quot;Oh ya I remember that&amp;quot;! meaning I totally forgot about a certain protocol or how and what services where in each layer. So I wrote down the basics on the ITS forum and decided why not post it here as well.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
