<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>firewall on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/firewall/</link>
    <description>Recent content in firewall on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 14:00:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/firewall/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Verifying DNS Lists - FMC</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2018/09/07/verifying-dns-lists-fmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2018/09/07/verifying-dns-lists-fmc/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;We are back with another post about Cisco&#39;s Firepower Management Center and this time we are working with the DNS list which if you have a protect license you can have your Firepower modules or your FTD (Firepower Threat Defense) devices look at DNS requests and deny the requests if they are malicious. These have to be applied on your access control policy to be able to use it and in this post we are going verify some of the domain names that are in this lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this post is already assuming that you have an Access Control Policy deployed on a Firepower Module (ASA) or a FTD. We also are assuming that you have a DNS policy applied to the FM/FTD. These lists get downloaded about every two hours from Cisco and are updated regularly, best to keep it that way. :) However like everything there is always someone, some system, some program that fails to connect and more often than not it&#39;s usually this critical process that worked yesterday but doesn&#39;t today, so how do we check if we are hitting this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to check this we can look at the connection events (if you are logging which by default is yes) it will show DNS the events and depending on your policy you&#39;ll see the action taken. In this example we selected to use Domain Not Found for the action. In this example we can see Domain Not Found and we can also see the DNS category its hitting which is DNS Dga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/images/2018/07/fmc-dnfee.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; I have edited this screenshot to show example.com instead of the malicious domain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can verify the domain is in this list DNS Dga by connecting to the FMC via SSH and browse to the actual list which is located at /var/sf/sidns_download. When you browse to this location you&#39;ll see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt;admin@FMC:/var/sf/sidns_download$ 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;admin@FMC:/var/sf/sidns_download$ ls
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;032ba433-c295-11e4-a919-d4ae5275b77b  Cisco_DNS_Intelligence_Feed
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;1b117672-7453-478c-be31-b72e89ca2dde  IPRVersion.dat
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;23f2a124-8278-4c03-8c9d-d28fe08b71ab  abdc925f-4f85-4504-90a7-c891979ad82a
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;2CCDA18E-DDFF-4F5C-AF9A-F00985219707  b1df3aa8-2841-4c88-8e64-bfaacec7111f
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;2b15cb6f-a3fc-4e0e-a342-ccc5e5804576  d7d996a6-6b92-4a56-8f10-e8506e432fb8
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;30f9e69c-d64c-479c-821d-0e4edab8348d  health
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt;3e2af68e-5fc8-4b1c-b5bc-b4e7cab5abcd  health_status
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;5a0b6d6b-e2c3-436f-b4a1-48248b331d39  health_statuslock
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;5f8148f1-e5e4-427a-aa3b-ee1c2745d663  peers
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;60f4e2ab-d96c-44a0-bd38-830252b65259  rep_dd.yaml
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;6ba968f4-7a25-4793-a2c8-7cc77f1f1074  tmp
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;A27C6AAE-8E52-4174-A81A-47C59FECd3a5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of these UIDs correspond to DNS feed. For example &lt;strong&gt;b1df3aa8-2841-4c88-8e64-bfaacec7111f&lt;/strong&gt; is for DNS Dga category. You can easily figure out which UID is tied to which DNS category by using the more command, notice the top of the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; I have replaced these domains with examples instead of the malicious domains&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;admin@FMC:/var/sf/sidns_download$ more b1df3aa8-2841-4c88-8e64-bfaacec7111f
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;#Cisco DNS and URL intelligence feed: DNS Dga
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;example.info
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;example.com
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;example.net
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can see in this example that the domain we where trying to resolve is in this blacklist. Usually you&#39;ll have to grep the file to find the domain as these lists can be big, to find a domain follow this command, I&#39;m looking in the DNS Dga category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;admin@FMC:/var/sf/sidns_download$ more b1df3aa8-2841-4c88-8e64-bfaacec7111f |grep example.com
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;example.com
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;admin@FMC:/var/sf/sidns_download$
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This confirms it and we can can either whitelist it or drop the category and then redeploy polices, unless you run into a bug, which I have ran into with whitelisting as it does not seem to work with some older firepower code. Another upgrade is in the works, in the meantime I dropped the DNS category,  I hope this information is helpful, - Ryan&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Many TCP Resets</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2018/06/20/too-many-tcp-resets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2018/06/20/too-many-tcp-resets/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;So, recently we enforced some firewall rules on a new environment, we did testing of the environment and everything was working as expected. In about 24 hours a lot of traffic from the web infrastructure was being denied and it continued, at first glance it looked like return traffic was being dropped, the web servers were sourcing at port 443 and the destination ports were using dynamic ports (RFC 6335) No user or application problems were reported when we enforced rules, and we waited additional days to see if anything came up. Nothing came up, the only thing was a spike in amount of syslog messages of dropped traffic coming from the web servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So from that point it really wasn’t an issue, but I thought it would be interesting to see what was going on. I started to look at the firewall logs and enabled debugging to syslog, and as you can see the TCP session is being built and we can also see the TCP Teardown, which should be the end of it, something else was happening instead and it was unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wed Jun 20 11:58:46 2018;172.17.70.1; &amp;lt;167&amp;gt;Jun 20 2018 11:58:45 172.17.70.1 : %ASA-7-302013: &lt;code&gt;Built inbound TCP connection 47772320 for OUTSIDE:203.0.113.147/43918 (203.0.113.147/43918) to INSIDE:172.17.77.250/443 (172.17.77.250/443)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wed Jun 20 12:00:51 2018;172.17.70.1; &amp;lt;167&amp;gt;Jun 20 2018 12:00:50 172.17.70.1 : %ASA-7-302014: &lt;code&gt;Teardown TCP connection 47772320 for OUTSIDE:203.0.113.147/43918 to INSIDE:172.17.77.250/443 duration 0:02:05 bytes 107244 TCP FINs from INSIDE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wed Jun 20 12:00:51 2018;172.17.70.1; &amp;lt;167&amp;gt;Jun 20 2018 12:00:50 172.17.70.1 : %ASA-7-106015: &lt;code&gt;Deny TCP (no connection) from 172.17.77.250/443 to 203.0.113.147/43918 flags RST  on interface INSIDE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web servers (172.17.77.250) are sending a RST (Reset) Flag back out the firewall which gets denied. This deny action generates the log message that I was seeing, but why would server 172.17.77.250 be sending a rest flag when the connection was already completed?  To investigate this further I needed to do a packet capture to be able to determine what else is going on, maybe we where loosing traffic upstream and this was just a dirty TCP session I really couldn’t tell, so I started to capture the inside and outside interfaces on this firewall and here are the results:
&lt;strong&gt;Inside Interface Capture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;33437: 12:00:47.907301       &lt;code&gt;172.17.77.250.443 &amp;gt; 203.0.113.147.43918: F&lt;/code&gt; 2320205170:2320205170(0) ack 991843171 win 65535&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;33438: 12:00:47.952480       &lt;code&gt;203.0.113.147.43918 &amp;gt; 172.17.77.250.443: . ack&lt;/code&gt; 2320205171 win 65535&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;33748: 12:00:50.443687       &lt;code&gt;203.0.113.147.43918 &amp;gt; 172.17.77.250.443: F&lt;/code&gt; 991843171:991843171(0) ack 2320205171 win 65535&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;33749: 12:00:50.443687       &lt;code&gt;203.0.113.147.43918 &amp;gt; 172.17.77.250.443: R&lt;/code&gt; 991843172:991843172(0) ack 2320205171 win 0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;33750: 12:00:50.443748       &lt;code&gt;172.17.77.250.443 &amp;gt; 203.0.113.147.43918: R&lt;/code&gt; 2320205171:2320205171(0) win 0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first capture we can see the server 172.17.77.250 sending a FIN as noted with the letter “F”, so the server starts to end the connection. Following that we can see the client sending an acknowledgment as noted with the “. Ack”. We can also see that the client sends a FIN to finish up the connection. What’s interesting is at the same time the FIN is sent from the client a TCP Reset is also sent from the client. Normally we should have just ended the connection with a FIN and one more acknowledgment (ACK) from 172.17.77.250 since it started the TCP termination process. This would have end the connection peacefully, however in this example the client seems to send a FIN and a RST at the same time which causes 172.17.77.250 to also send a TCP RST back to the client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we looked at the outside interface capture, we pretty much see the same thing we can see the FIN being sent from 172.17.77.250 and acknowledgment from the client. The client sends the FIN and the reset flags back to 172.17.77.250 which ultimately should have just been a FIN, instead its FIN and RST. Notice we did not see 172.17.77.250 TCP RST across, this was because that packet was already denied from the inside interface.
&lt;strong&gt;Outside Interface Capture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;32158: 12:00:47.907316       &lt;code&gt;172.17.77.250.443 &amp;gt; 203.0.113.147.43918: F&lt;/code&gt; 3349673389:3349673389(0) ack 965033113 win 65535&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;32159: 12:00:47.952480       &lt;code&gt;203.0.113.147.43918 &amp;gt; 172.17.77.250.443: . ack&lt;/code&gt; 3349673390 win 65535&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;32468: 12:00:50.443672       &lt;code&gt;203.0.113.147.43918 &amp;gt; 172.17.77.250.443: F&lt;/code&gt; 965033113:965033113(0) ack 3349673390 win 65535&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;32469: 12:00:50.443687       &lt;code&gt;203.0.113.147.43918 &amp;gt; 172.17.77.250.443: R&lt;/code&gt; 965033114:965033114(0) ack 3349673390 win 0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not seeing this on every connection that was being made and the fact that this client was sending TCP RST at the end of the FIN tell us that it’s something the client is doing. I was able to run a test on my own against this to see what a good “peaceful” connection looks like to compare the results. I ran the same functions as what this client would be doing. In this example my IP address is 192.0.2.167, here are the results. From the firewall debugging logs we can see the TCP session being built for 192.0.2.167 and the TCP teardown, also notice we don’t see any denied TCP connections from 172.17.77.250, so that’s a good start!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wed Jun 20 14:22:39 2018;172.17.70.1; &amp;lt;167&amp;gt;Jun 20 2018 14:22:34 172.17.70.1 : %ASA-7-609001: &lt;code&gt;Built local-host OUTSIDE:192.0.2.167&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wed Jun 20 14:22:39 2018;172.17.70.1; &amp;lt;167&amp;gt;Jun 20 2018 14:22:34 172.17.70.1 : %ASA-7-302013: &lt;code&gt;Built inbound TCP connection 49008818 for OUTSIDE:192.0.2.167/3954 (192.0.2.167/3954) to INSIDE:172.17.77.250/443 (172.17.77.250/443)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wed Jun 20 14:22:55 2018;172.17.70.1; &amp;lt;167&amp;gt;Jun 20 2018 14:22:51 172.17.70.1 : %ASA-7-302014: &lt;code&gt;Teardown TCP connection 49008818 for OUTSIDE:192.0.2.167/3954 to INSIDE:172.17.77.250/443 duration 0:00:16 bytes 1051013 TCP FINs from OUTSIDE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wed Jun 20 14:22:55 2018;172.17.70.1; &amp;lt;167&amp;gt;Jun 20 2018 14:22:51 172.17.70.1 : %ASA-7-609002: &lt;code&gt;Teardown local-host OUTSIDE:192.0.2.167 duration 0:00:16&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the packet capture we can also see peaceful TCP sessions closing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;544: 14:22:51.372035       &lt;code&gt;192.0.2.167.3954 &amp;gt; 172.17.77.250.443: F&lt;/code&gt; 221753878:221753878(0) ack 2290377569 win 64296 &amp;lt;nop,nop,timestamp 1618672784 1798676063&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;545: 14:22:51.372218       &lt;code&gt;172.17.77.250.443 &amp;gt; 192.0.2.167.3954: P 2290377569:2290377600(31)&lt;/code&gt; ack 221753879 win 64296 &amp;lt;nop,nop,timestamp 1798678251 1618672784&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;546: 14:22:51.372234       &lt;code&gt;172.17.77.250.443 &amp;gt; 192.0.2.167.3954: F&lt;/code&gt; 2290377600:2290377600(0) ack 221753879 win 64296 &amp;lt;nop,nop,timestamp 1798678251 1618672784&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;547: 14:22:51.397608       &lt;code&gt;192.0.2.167.3954 &amp;gt; 172.17.77.250.443: . ack 2290377600&lt;/code&gt; win 64296 &amp;lt;nop,nop,timestamp 1618672790 1798678251&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;548: 14:22:51.397699       &lt;code&gt;192.0.2.167.3954 &amp;gt; 172.17.77.250.443: . ack&lt;/code&gt; 2290377601 win 64296 &amp;lt;nop,nop,timestamp 1618672790 1798678251&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The client (me) requested to finish up the connection, 172.17.77.250 is doing a TCP Push back to us we wait for the FIN from 172.17.77.250 which comes to us shortly. After that you can see two acknowledgments both are from me. The first ACK is for that TCP Push packet that was created by 172.17.77.250, the second ACK from the client (me) is acknowledgment of the FIN. We have ended the connection peacefully and that’s how it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the Internet is a weird place and that’s not what’s happening, so what’s the issue? Well that really was hardest part of this problem and here’s my theory, 172.17.77.250 is sending a TCP RST back to the client is because 172.17.77.250 wasn’t expecting it in the first place. It was finishing up the connection between the client and because of this unexpected TCP packet from the client 172.17.77.250 sends a TCP RST. The connection is not valid, and our server wants to start over. In the meantime, the TCP session was already closed by the firewall because it saw that last FIN from the client. That last TCP RST packet from the server gets denied and never reaches the client, but that still does not answer our question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are seeing a FIN and RST from the client in the first place? This TCP connection is using TLS, so I started to look at how TLS functions in a TCP connection. When communication starts, and we finish our TCP handshake, then if the connection is over TLS we do a TLS handshake-&amp;gt; After the two hosts agree on the ciphers and TLS settings data is exchanged encrypted-&amp;gt;After TLS is done with the data TLS &lt;strong&gt;should&lt;/strong&gt; send a close notify to “peacefully” end the TLS session-&amp;gt;Following that TCP closes with a FIN and it is peaceful. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t investigate the TLS packet because it was encrypted however I think it had something to do with the close notify action of TLS. Not all implementations of SSL/TLS follow that rule even through RFC 5246 seems to imply that a close notify is required. I think this would explain the reason why the server sends RST when it receives both a FIN and RST at the same time from the client, it was unexpected, and we did not close the TLS session properly. When I did the test, I didn’t get any TCP resets. Although we where not seeing any disruptions from this it was helpful to at least figure out what the problem is and then being able to theorize what we could do to fix that problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example its related to the client so we can’t do anything on our end. The fact that this is happening at the end of the TCP connection, you are not going to notice anyway because you already have data you requested. We don&#39;t really care how the connection closes. I hope this post was helpful in understanding how to dig in the weeds and even through the connection worked, its helpful to understand any anomalies because those could turn into problems in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco FTDv in Cisco VIRL</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2017/06/14/cisco-ftdv-in-cisco-virl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 13:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2017/06/14/cisco-ftdv-in-cisco-virl/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Cisco is actively pushing their Firepower Threat Defense software with the new Firepower 2100 units on their way this summer in effort to eventually replace the ASA5525-X, ASA5545-X and ASA5555-X platforms. When using FTD you must also have the Firepower Management Center (FMC) available to manage and configure these devices. This gets difficult especially if you want to test things out because not everyone has Cisco Firepower lying around unused. How are you supposed to test and learn the depths of this product? &lt;em&gt;(Hint: Cisco VIRL)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; There is a catch to this, as of this post Cisco does not included the FMC or FTDv images with Cisco VIRL by itself. You’ll have to be with a company or organization that has already purchased this product. Keep in mind during the initial configuration of FMC there will be a spot to install some licensing but you can skip this step as it&#39;s not required to get to the initial login screen. The images I’m working with in this post are the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FMC: 6.2.0.2 (updated from 6.2.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FTDv: 6.2.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand how this is works, you must setup the FMC as a separate virtual machine in VMware Workstation and configure a static IP address for the FMC. You’ll want to use an IP address that is in VIRL’s shared flat network. This is usually the 172.16.1.0/24 network. In this example, I configured the FMC with the IP address of 172.16.1.15. If you have installed VIRL in VMware Workstation and followed the VIRL installation guide you’ll want to put the FMC in VMnet 1. Basically, you’ll want the FMC and FTDv to be on the same broadcast domain in the management network within VIRL for your FMC to be able to manage the FTDv image. If you are using VIRL on a bare metal server and have VMware Workstation installed on a different system use VIRL’s OpenVPN connection settings. To understand how this works you can reference the following video (Credit goes to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC41WuzXlJCGY5qLsuZ8aHkQ&#34;&gt;Cisco VIRL Youtube Channel&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your computer has the OpenVPN client installed and you can successfully connect to VIRL, you also can map VMware Workstation to the OpenVPN network adapter under the virtual network editor.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/images/2017/06/virl-openvpn.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives your FMC direct access to VIRL’s shared flat network while using the OpenVPN client.
Please reference the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/firepower/quick_start/vmware/fmcv/FMCv-quick/setup-mcvirtual.html&#34;&gt;Cisco Firepower Management Center Virtual for VMware Deployment Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process in pretty simple login into the FMC CLI and run the following command and follow the prompts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;sudo /usr/local/sf/bin/configure-network
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If all is well you should see the initial configuration wizard, and once you have completed the initial setup wizard you should be able to login using the password you recently created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/images/2017/06/virl-fmc-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;FMC Login Page&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You now have a FMC ready and primed to manage FTDv devices, like I mention earlier you can enable the evaluation license which is only available in the 6.2.0 or higher releases. Go to System-&amp;gt;Licenses-&amp;gt;Smart Licenses which gives you 90 days to kick in the tires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/images/2017/06/fmc-eval.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You also could use VMware snapshots to set up a vanilla FMC with no devices, and no evaluation license enabled, that way you could always revert to that FMC you originally started with, also helps if you really got carried away :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now need a FTDv image to install within VIRL. When you look at Cisco&#39;s support &lt;a href=&#34;https://software.cisco.com/download/release.html?mdfid=286306503&amp;amp;softwareid=286306337&amp;amp;release=6.2.0&amp;amp;relind=AVAILABLE&amp;amp;rellifecycle=&amp;amp;reltype=latest&#34;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt; you&#39;ll want to use the QEMU format (qcow2) if you are importing this into Cisco VIRL. A couple of house keeping items first before we can import this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a flavor to specify run time parameters in VIRL, you can find this under Node Resources-&amp;gt;Flavors. &lt;strong&gt;FTDv requires 8GB of RAM, 4 virtual CPU cores and 4 interfaces to run, this includes the Management and Diagnostic ports that VIRL puts in automatically. You can also leave disk space at 0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a copy of the ASAv subtype, under Node Resources-&amp;gt;Subtypes, find the ASAv subtype and click on the “stethoscope” icon also called specialize and fill in the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name of plugin - FTDv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description of plugin - Firepower Threat Defense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name of management interface - Management0/0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Names of dummy interfaces - Diagnostic0/0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pattern for data interface names - GigabitEthernet0/{0}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First data interface number - 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max count of data interfaces - 10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of interfaces per LC - 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of serial interfaces - 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protocol for network CLI - telnet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make VNC access available - True&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name of icon for GUI - asav&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show subtype on GUI palette - True&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configuration disk type - cdrom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ISO 9660 level in cdrom disk - 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name of file for config drive - /day0-config&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual interface model - virtio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main disk bus model - virtio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAM (MB) allocated per node - 8192&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of CPUs allocated per node - 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Require HW acceleration in kvm - True&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name of default image - FTDv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third:&lt;/strong&gt; Import the image, Node Resources-&amp;gt;Images-&amp;gt;Add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find and select the FTDv Subtype&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name/Version – 6.2 (I just picked the main version)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release - 6.2.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source – File on server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image path – /home/virl/VMs/&lt;em&gt;image of FTDv image&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save the image. We are almost there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To review we have a FMC ready, we have the evaluation license enabled so that we can manage FTDv devices and this FMC is statically configured to use an IP address that is in VIRL&#39;s shared flat network. We just went over the settings required to get the FTDv to boot up in Cisco VIRL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&#39;s next? Well if you wanted to register and configure the FTDv manually you are all set to go just start-up the device and you can walk through the initial prompts to get it registered to the FMC and start deploying your configurations. However one the neat features that VIRL offers is pre-configuration of the device while the device starts up, also called Day0 configuration. That way you can to skip all of those initial prompts and just register the device from FMC when the FTDv image is fully booted. To do that you will be using the AutoNetKit in VM Maestro, use the following Day0 configuration before starting your FTDv image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34; data-lang=&#34;json&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;EULA&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;accept&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Hostname&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;ftdv-VIRL&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;AdminPassword&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Admin123&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;FirewallMode&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;routed&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;DNS1&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;none&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;DNS2&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;none&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;DNS3&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;none&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;IPv4Mode&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;dhcp&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;IPv4Addr&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;IPv4Mask&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;IPv4Gw&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;IPv6Mode&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;disabled&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;IPv6Addr&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;IPv6Mask&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;IPv6Gw&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;FmcIp&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;172.16.1.15&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;FmcRegKey&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;cisco1234&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;FmcNatId&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fields are pretty self-explanatory the only thing that could be different is if you used a different FMC IP and registration key. When the image boots it will grab an IP address from VIRL&#39;s shared network and already be pending a registration. The only thing you have to do is register your device from FMC and deploy your configuration. This now makes it pretty easy and quickly to test deployments and configuration within VIRL. In my testing it took about 15 to 20 minutes for the FTDv device to become online and to be registered within FMC. That&#39;s all I got for now like always I hope this information helpful as alawys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22aisforabbott@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Shaun&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2017-07-06 22:21:45&#34;&gt;Jul 4, 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figured it out, just needed to select the topology management network to be in the Shared Flat network. This has helped me out tremendously, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22aisforabbott@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Shaun&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2017-07-05 08:30:04&#34;&gt;Jul 3, 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How and which interface did you use to get the FTDv working on the FLAT network? Can you show a working sample topology you used?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://karmicgeezer.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;andy.taylor@mail.com&#34;&gt;karmicgeezer&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2018-01-08 09:22:27&#34;&gt;Jan 8, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks for the tutorial - when I follow this I consistently get the same issue: Virtual FTD requires at least 4 network interfaces to complete system initialization. System initialization in progress. Please stand by. The bar turns but will sit there indefinitely. Any ideas?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2018-01-08 19:04:47&#34;&gt;Jan 9, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Karmicgeezer, That is expected. You can&#39;t just run the VM without it connected to anything in VIRL. Make sure your subtype in VIRL has a management and diagnostic interface. You also have to connect up to two interfaces on the FTDv in VIRL in order for it to start correctly. Hope that Helps, Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://karmicgeezer.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;andy.taylor@mail.com&#34;&gt;karmicgeezer&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2018-01-09 10:37:38&#34;&gt;Jan 9, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryan, Fantastic, this would explain why it works natively in ESXi but not deployed in VIRL without sufficient interfaces. Much appreciated!! All the best, Andy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2018-01-09 21:05:28&#34;&gt;Jan 9, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glad I could help Andy! Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factory Reset Firepower 4100 &amp; 9300</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/10/19/factory-reset-firepower-4100-9300/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/10/19/factory-reset-firepower-4100-9300/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;I got my hands on some Cisco Firepower 4100 units and after playing around with them I wanted to reset them to factory settings, essentially erase the &amp;quot;startup-config&amp;quot; on the FXOS. The Firepower units act a little differently than your normal Cisco IOS or ASA and you can&#39;t just erase startup-config and reload the device, that would be too easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Edit: 7-21-17) After Gabriele made this comment - &amp;quot;connect local-mgmt&amp;quot; and then &amp;quot;erase configuration&amp;quot; it looks like you can. Thanks Gabriele&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also can follow the  password recovery on this post which will also erases the configuration. You have to be physically at the device with a console cable, plug into the console port to begin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power off the system, and then power it back on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the system is booting, you have go into ROMMON mode to do that press ESC or CTRL+L. You&#39;ll see a message confirming that you are going to ROMMON&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt;!!  Rommon image verified successfully  !! 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;Cisco System ROMMON, Version 1.0.10, RELEASE SOFTWARE 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;Copyright (c) 1994-2015  by Cisco Systems, Inc. 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;Compiled Mon 11/30/2015 15:23:18.60 by builder 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt;Current image running: Boot ROM0 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;Last reset cause: PowerCycleRequest 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;DIMM Slot 0 : Present 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;DIMM Slot 1 : Present 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;No USB drive !! 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;BIOS has been locked !! 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;21&lt;/span&gt;Platform FPR-4110-SUP with 8192 Mbytes of main memory
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make note of the kickstart and FXOS system image as you need these names to be able to boot to the correct image. In this example under ROMMON the following appeared on-screen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;boot bootflash:/installables/switch/fxos-k9-kickstart.5.0.3.N2.3.14.69.SPA bootflash:/installables/switch/fxos-k9-system.5.0.3.N2.3.14.69.SPA
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load the kickstart image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;rommon 1 &amp;gt; boot bootflash:/installables/switch/fxos-k9-kickstart.5.0.3.N2.3.14.69.SPA 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;  !!   Kickstart Image verified successfully   !!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When kickstart loads you&#39;ll be at the switch(boot)# prompt, enter configuration mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;switch(boot)#
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;switch(boot)# config t
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the configuration mode, type admin-password erase, this will erase everything and bring the system back to factory defaults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;switch(boot)(config)# admin-password erase
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;Your password and configuration will be erased!
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;Do you want to continue? (y/n)  [n] y
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;switch(boot)(config)# exit
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load the system image to startup the FXOS, once the image has been loaded you&#39;ll be prompted to enter the setup wizard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;switch(boot)# load bootflash:/installables/switch/fxos-k9-system.5.0.3.N2.3.14.69.SPA
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;Uncompressing system image: bootflash:/installables/switch/fxos-k9-system.5.0.3.N2.3.14.69.SPA
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;You have chosen to setup a new Security Appliance. Continue? (y/n):
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this information is helpful, the information I was referencing is located here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/docs/security/firepower-9300-security-appliance/200491-Password-Recovery-Procedure-For-FirePOWE.html&#34;&gt;Password Recovery Procedure For Firepower 9300/4100 Series Appliances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22228496698@qq.com%22&#34;&gt;Jimmy&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-11-07 21:54:51&#34;&gt;Nov 1, 2016&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi :Ryan ,I got several devices like ASA 5525x with firepower mode ,i want to reinstall the whole system from ASA(firepower software ) to firepower system complete(called FTD system) ,Do you have similar experence ? Also i purchase (Protection,Control,Malware,URL Filtering) licence ,i find the the firepower mode didnt filter locker virus (like CryptoLocker,CBT locker),Can you give me some suggestion ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/&#34; title=&#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2017-04-29 19:40:22&#34;&gt;Apr 6, 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Gabriele, Never tried that command, that&#39;s a lot easier than what I was doing :) Thanks. Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/&#34; title=&#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-11-09 21:24:39&#34;&gt;Nov 3, 2016&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Jimmy, I have not had experience upgrading to the FTD image for the ASAs and from what I can tell you may have to upgrade/download several things. I found this on Cisco website which may be a good starting point: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/firepower/quick&#34;&gt;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/firepower/quick&lt;/a&gt;_start/reimage/asa-ftd-reimage.html I have worked with the Firepower 4100 units which give you the option to use either ASA or an FTD image. I have been playing around with the FTD image and the ASA SFR module, they are different you really don&#39;t manage the device directly, it all works through the Firepower Management Center. Its interesting you&#39;re not having any luck with the filtering make sure if you are using the ASA image that you set up a service policy under the global policy to inspect all traffic with the SFR module and its not in monitor mode. You will also need to setup policies and rules in the FMC to block this type of traffic. Hope that helps :) Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22aasdsadf@asdfasfafds.com%22&#34;&gt;anon&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2017-07-19 20:56:08&#34;&gt;Jul 3, 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should update your post at the top with this advice. I almost took the long path as well. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/&#34; title=&#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2017-07-21 18:51:16&#34;&gt;Jul 5, 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated, thanks Anon :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22ferrarigabriele84@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Gabriele&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2017-04-26 09:08:26&#34;&gt;Apr 3, 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try with the commands &amp;quot;connect local-mgmt&amp;quot; and then &amp;quot;erase configuration&amp;quot;. It should work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Cisco ASA Overview</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/firewall.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/firewall.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Firewall&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Cisco 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliances are of course an excellent firewall but the ASA also offers (depending on the model) other security services as well, like IPS systems, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network&#34; title=&#34;Virtual private network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/a&gt;, content security, unified communications and remote access. These ASA&#39;s can be used as a standalone appliance&#39; that can handle the need for branch offices to enterprise data centers. Or they can be included in high-performance blades that work together with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Catalyst&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Catalyst&#34;&gt;Cisco Catalyst&lt;/a&gt; 6500 Series, and recently new they can also run in a virtual instance which provides tenant isolation for public and private clouds! For now let&#39;s focus on the basics of the ASA like the ASDM. The ASDM is a pretty good &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface&#34; title=&#34;Graphical user interface&#34;&gt;GUI&lt;/a&gt; tool that helps make the ASA a simpler process of maintaining and configuring the device, instead of doing &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Command-line_interface&#34; title=&#34;Command-line interface&#34;&gt;CLI&lt;/a&gt; commando style. In this example I have an ASA 5505 with default configuration (I did a &amp;quot;write erase&amp;quot; to clear the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34; title=&#34;IP address&#34;&gt;IP addressing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic_Host_Configuration_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol&#34;&gt;DHCP&lt;/a&gt; settings) when you reload the device I decided to use the ASA&#39;s pre-configure wizard which really just makes the ASA useable by giving the inside interface an IP address along with the correct time and the &amp;quot;enable password&amp;quot; Here are the current settings: [code]The following configuration will be used: Enable password: cisco Allow password recovery: yes Clock (UTC): 11:04:11 Jun 23 2012 Firewall Mode: Routed Inside IP address: 192.168.5.1 Inside network mask: 255.255.255.0 Host name: ASA Domain name: ciscoskills.net IP address of host running Device Manager: 192.168.5.10 Use this configuration and write to flash? yes INFO: Security level for &amp;quot;inside&amp;quot; set to 100 by default. WARNING: http server is not yet enabled to allow ASDM access. Cryptochecksum: a2692f1b 31b2d847 6abf71e4 b9c1bcfb 1641 bytes copied in 1.730 secs (1641 bytes/sec) Type help or &#39;?&#39; for a list of available commands. ASA&amp;gt;en ASA#config t ASA(config)#http server enable[/code] Notice to use the ASDM you must put it one more command for the ASA to listen on port 443 which is &amp;quot;http server enable&amp;quot; from that open up your browser and type the IP address of the ASA in this example it is &amp;quot;192.168.5.1&amp;quot; you can either run the ASDM from the ASA or install it on your system for a faster experience it&#39;s your choice, but it does add additional memory and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_processing_unit&#34; title=&#34;Central processing unit&#34;&gt;CPU&lt;/a&gt; if the ASDM runs on the ASA. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-main.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-main.png&#34; alt=&#34;Browser Page for ASA&#34; title=&#34;ASDM-BROWSER&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; For this example I installed the ASDM on my system and by default the username is blank and the password is &amp;quot;cisco&amp;quot; which is what I configured in the beginning. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-login.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;The ASDM Login Screen&#34; title=&#34;ASDM-LOGIN&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; From there opens up the ASDM the home page displays some device information like the hostname, ASA version and ASADM version, the runtime, total RAM and flash. It also gives you some traffic stats along with CPU and memory from there to configure the device you would click the configuration button and configure a way! &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-home.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/asdm-home.png&#34; alt=&#34;The ASDM Home Page&#34; title=&#34;ASDM-HOME&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You have to have some hands-on experience with this product to really understand it and get the overall feeling of where things in the ASDM. Cisco does offer some ASDM demos that can be searchable on the internet and you can download directly from Cisco however you must have a Cisco ID to use it. If you &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mediafire.com/download.php?rwfhxjdy9zznan3&#34; title=&#34;ASDM 6.4(9) Install and Demo Files&#34;&gt;download this link&lt;/a&gt; it will install the latest (May 2012) ASDM demo settings so you can at least get a feeling of the ASDM. I hope this information is helpful and if you have any questions are comments be sure to post them below, also check back often I&#39;ll see if I can post some additional content about the ASA like &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/29/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/&#34; title=&#34;Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM&#34;&gt;upgrading the ASA IOS version with the ASDM&lt;/a&gt;. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/&#34;&gt;CCNA Security - 640-554&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/258103/cisco_patches_vulnerabilities_in_vpn_client_security_appliances.html&#34;&gt;Cisco Patches Vulnerabilities in VPN Client, Security Appliances&lt;/a&gt; (pcworld.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prweb.com/releases/prweb2010/10/prweb4598974.htm&#34;&gt;New Cisco ASA Step-by-Step Guide Simplifies Configuration&lt;/a&gt; (prweb.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/28/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-28 19:25:03&#34;&gt;Jun 4, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Password Recovery – Cisco IOS Routers | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2012/07/21/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-07-21 11:04:27&#34;&gt;Jul 6, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Basic Cisco ASA Overview (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Zone Based Firewalls via SDM</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 15:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Last month I talked about the fundamentals for understanding zone based &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firewall_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Firewall (computing)&#34;&gt;firewalls&lt;/a&gt; (See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/&#34; title=&#34;Understanding Zone Based Firewalls&#34;&gt;Understanding Zone Based Firewalls&lt;/a&gt;). So for today&#39;s post I want to go ahead and talk about configuring the zone based firewalls but with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web&#34; title=&#34;World Wide Web&#34;&gt;Web&lt;/a&gt;-based device management tool a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface&#34; title=&#34;Graphical user interface&#34;&gt;GUI&lt;/a&gt; for Cisco &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;routers&lt;/a&gt; this can simplify router deployments and reduce ownership costs. (See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/14/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34; title=&#34;Configure Cisco SDM&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM&lt;/a&gt;) Instead of talking about what is zone based firewalls lets jump into the configuration of them. This &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tutorial&#34; title=&#34;Tutorial&#34;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; is assuming that the configurations to set up Cisco SDM have already been completed. For this tutorial all we want to focus on is configuring zone based firewalls. Since this using Cisco SDM the firewall wizard is pretty effortless. Before we get started I like to have the Cisco SDM preview the commands before I deliver them to the router. To do that at the top of the menu bar click &lt;em&gt;Edit&lt;/em&gt; and select &lt;em&gt;Preferences&lt;/em&gt; a new window will appear (Like below) and verify that the &lt;em&gt;Preview commands before delivering to the router&lt;/em&gt; is checked.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/preview_commandse.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/preview_commandse.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM Preferences&#34; title=&#34;Preview_Commands&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Now that we are ready to go, the first thing we need to do is select the Configure button at the top, and to the left hand-side under tasks select the Firewall and ACL option. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall-acle/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall-acle.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Firewall and ACL Page&#34; title=&#34;Firewall ACL&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You now have to decide what type of firewall you want to configure and launch the wizard, the main difference between the basic firewall option and the advanced firewall option is you have the option to support a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DMZ_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;DMZ (computing)&#34;&gt;DMZ&lt;/a&gt; zone. The basic firewall set up does not support DMZ. (For this tutorial we are going to be using the basic firewall option) &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall_wizarde/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall_wizarde.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Basic Firewall Wizard&#34; title=&#34;Firewall_Wizard&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A new window will show, the Firewall Wizard and will explain what the selected firewall option will do. Click on the next button. The next area is going to be asking what interface is considered to be the outside (untrusted network) and the inside (trusted network). In the advanced firewall wizard you have an extra option the DMZ. For this tutorial we are using the basic firewall wizard and are selecting the serial interface has the untrusted (outside) network. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_Ethernet&#34; title=&#34;Fast Ethernet&#34;&gt;Fast-Ethernet&lt;/a&gt; interface has the trusted (inside) network. Click Next. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall_wizard_interfacee/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall_wizard_interfacee.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Basic Firewall Interface Wizard&#34; title=&#34;Firewall_Wizard_Interface&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; In the basic firewall wizard the nest section is the security configuration, depending on your type of security. Move the slider to the choice that best fits, you can also preview the commands by selecting the Preview Commands button to verify the commands before choosing them. (For this tutorial I selected the Low Security option) Click Next &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall_wizard_securitye/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall_wizard_securitye.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Basic Firewall Wizard Security&#34; title=&#34;Firewall_Wizard_Security&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The final section is the summary for the basic firewall configuration, here you can look over the summary to verify the configuration. Click Finish. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall_wizard_summarye/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall_wizard_summarye.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Basic Firewall Summary&#34; title=&#34;Firewall_Wizard_Summary&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; If you&#39;ve selected the option to preview commands before delivering them to the router, a final window will appear. In this window you can see the real commands the SDM program will attempt to deliver. You have the option to save the running-configuration to the startup-configuration after the commands complete. You also have the option to save the configuration as a file and finally you can deliver them to the router.&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall_wizard_deliverye/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall_wizard_deliverye.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Firewall Delivery&#34; title=&#34;Firewall_Wizard_Delivery&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Believe it or not that&#39;s the SDM configuration of a zone-based firewall you can get more information at Cisco&#39;s website about SDM and the configuration settings. Like always I hope this tutorial was informative and if you have a suggestion on the next topic that relates to ICND1 or ICND2 and even some &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Career_Certifications&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Career Certifications&#34;&gt;CCNA Security&lt;/a&gt; comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/&#34;&gt;Understanding Zone Based Firewalls&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brighthub.com/computing/smb-security/articles/63980.aspx&#34;&gt;Configuring Cisco Router Firewall through Command Prompt&lt;/a&gt; (brighthub.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcworld.com/article/225115/firewall_vendors_challenge_findings_of_nss_labs_report.html&#34;&gt;Firewall Vendors Challenge Findings of NSS Labs Report&lt;/a&gt; (pcworld.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nsslabs.blogspot.com/2011/04/enterprise-network-firewalls-leak.html&#34;&gt;Enterprise Network Firewalls Leak&lt;/a&gt; (nsslabs.blogspot.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcworld.com/article/225136/firewall_security_issue_raised_in_report_ignites_vendors_ire.html&#34;&gt;Firewall Security Issue Raised in Report Angers Vendors&lt;/a&gt; (pcworld.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firemon.com/blog/security-management&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Security Needs Management | FireMon Blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-04-21 12:35:30&#34;&gt;Apr 4, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configuring Zone Based Firewalls via SDM (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Zone Based Firewalls</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Earlier we talked about using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context-based_access_control&#34; title=&#34;Context-based access control&#34;&gt;CBAC&lt;/a&gt; (See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/&#34; title=&#34;Understanding CBAC&#34;&gt;Understanding CBAC&lt;/a&gt;) the &amp;quot;classic firewall&amp;quot; and we mention some information about zone based &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firewall_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Firewall (computing)&#34;&gt;firewalls&lt;/a&gt; but not nearly enough. So today we will be talking about zone based firewalls. Why are they different? We also will learn the basics about what is zone based and what are the advantages compared to CBAC. You can think of zone based has making &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interface_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Interface (computing)&#34;&gt;interfaces&lt;/a&gt; in a quarantine zone, each interface by default if set up in a zone is denied access to any other interface. This helps isolate networks that have private and or secure information that does not need the public network to have access to it. The firewall policies are configured using the Cisco Common Classification Policy Language (C3PL), this uses a hierarchical structure to define &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communications_protocol&#34; title=&#34;Communications protocol&#34;&gt;network protocol&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inspection&#34; title=&#34;Inspection&#34;&gt;inspection&lt;/a&gt; and allows network devices to be grouped under one inspection policy. Believe it or not it should be easier to configure zone based firewall compared to CBAC Remember that CBAC has these limitations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By having multiple inspection policies and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control_list&#34; title=&#34;Access control list&#34;&gt;ACLs&lt;/a&gt; on several interfaces on a router makes it difficult and sometimes overwhelming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All traffic through a given interface is subject to the same inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CBAC relies too heavily on ACLs, which can only do so much!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using zones that borders a network the traffic is inspected by the policy restrictions. These restrictions can be different in each zone or interface. Using the zone based approach does have its benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Zone Based firewall is not dependent on ACLs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The router security posture is to block unless explicitly allowed. CBAC allows everything unless explicitly denied or checked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Policies are easy to read and troubleshoot with C3PL. (Cisco Common Classification Policy Language)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One policy affects any given traffic, instead of needing multiple ACLs, inspection actions and rules that CBAC would need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important note when deciding to implement CBAC or Zone based is that either models can be enabled on the router simultaneously. They however cannot be used on the same interface as a router. There are three actions the zone based firewall can take when looking at traffic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect - This action is like the CBAC ip inspect command. It automatically allows for return traffic and potential &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Control_Message_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Control Message Protocol&#34;&gt;ICMP&lt;/a&gt; messages. For protocols requiring multiple parallel signaling and data sessions (such as, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;File Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;FTP&lt;/a&gt; or H.323), the inspect action also handles the proper establishment of data sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drop - To a deny statement in an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anterior_cruciate_ligament&#34; title=&#34;Anterior cruciate ligament&#34;&gt;ACL&lt;/a&gt;. A log option is also available to log the rejected packets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pass - To a permit statement in an ACL. The pass action does not track the state of connections or sessions within the traffic. Pass allows the traffic only in one direction. A corresponding policy must be applied to allow return traffic to pass in the opposite direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When determining how to set up zone-based firewalls the first thing you need to think of is the different zones that need to be implemented. The infrastructure must be split into separate zones with different security levels. Example the public network or internet to the inside network would be split into two zones. Create the zones for the firewall with the &lt;em&gt;zone security&lt;/em&gt; command.&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/zone-based/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/zone-based.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Zone Based Firewall&#34; title=&#34;zone-based&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You also have to set up policies between the zones. Remember by default when zones are configured they deny all access to any other zone as well has non-zone interfaces. You must define the type of traffic that will be allowed on the zone. Example would be &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transmission_Control_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Transmission Control Protocol&#34;&gt;TCP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_Datagram_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;User Datagram Protocol&#34;&gt;UDP&lt;/a&gt; sessions which are the most common, but there is also ICMP and others that can be defined. You want to define the traffic classes with the &lt;em&gt;class-map type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command.  After the zones have been identified along with the traffic requirements between them, the next thing to do is design the physical infrastructure and policies this would be stating the number of devices between the mission-critical devices and least critical devices and determining redundant routes and devices if any. You would specify the firewall policies with the &lt;em&gt;policy-map type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command. Define the class-map name and you want that policy to do? Do you want the policy to pass, inspect or drop the traffic specified by the class-map?  You want to apply the firewall policies the source and destination zones, by using the &lt;em&gt;zone-pair security&lt;/em&gt; command. What zone is the source? What zone is the destination? What policy-map are you going to use by using the &lt;em&gt;service-policy type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command.  The last setup is to identify a subset within zones and merge the traffic; the technician must identify the connected interfaces and apply that zone to the interface, by using the &lt;em&gt;zone-member security&lt;/em&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To recap, you must create a zone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then define the type of traffic that will be checked by the policy by using the &lt;em&gt;class-map type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, is define the firewall policies by using the &lt;em&gt;policy-map type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command. You what do you want to do with that traffic that you specified earlier with the class-maps (Pass, inspect or drop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign the policy-maps to the zone pairs, tell the router which policy is the source and destination by using the &lt;em&gt;zone-pair security&lt;/em&gt; command. Tell the router which policy to use by using the &lt;em&gt;service-policy type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally apply that zone-pair to the interface by using the &lt;em&gt;zone-member security&lt;/em&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the rundown of zone-based firewalls! Look complex? If you start to understand it you will find it easier to carry out than CBAC. Zone-based helps keep interfaces apart by blocking all traffic unless allowed by the policies. Like before you can always find more information online. I recommend Cisco.com for a full understanding of zone-based policy firewall, I hope this tutorial was helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IDS vs. IPS</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 15:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;There are tons of network attacks out there. Using a firewall helps but does look for signature based attacks. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control_list&#34; title=&#34;Access control list&#34;&gt;Access Control Lists&lt;/a&gt; are like firewalls and only look at the protocols like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypertext_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Hypertext Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;File Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;FTP&lt;/a&gt; POP, etc. Cisco has developed some tools that will help &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_administrator&#34; title=&#34;Network administrator&#34;&gt;network administrators&lt;/a&gt; combat the issue; IDS, (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intrusion_detection_system&#34; title=&#34;Intrusion detection system&#34;&gt;Intrusion Detection System&lt;/a&gt;) and IPS. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intrusion_prevention_system&#34; title=&#34;Intrusion prevention system&#34;&gt;Intrusion Prevention System&lt;/a&gt;) Let&#39;s go into IDS first, Cisco IDS is a physical device and is like an alarm system it will alert you when an attack happens but that&#39;s it, the system won&#39;t block the connection. The IDS system is deployed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Promiscuous_mode&#34; title=&#34;Promiscuous mode&#34;&gt;promiscuous mode&lt;/a&gt; meaning the sensor is placed where it can hear all the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_traffic_control&#34; title=&#34;Network traffic control&#34;&gt;network traffic&lt;/a&gt; but is not in direct connect with the network making it an advantage when using an IDS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No network impact, latency, or jitters etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No network impact if there is a sensor failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No network impact if there is a sensor overloaded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However the IDS does have some disadvantages compared to IPS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If packets trigger an alarm that&#39;s all it does is tell us that an attack is happening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correct tuning is required for valid and invalid packets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company must have a well thought-out security policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks that are vulnerable must have evasion techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what can IPS do that IDS can&#39;t? Well the IPS system can alert just like IDS but the IPS system can also block the attack. Remember that the IDS system can only alert. IPS works inline with the network it is a physical device just like IDS but is directly connected to the network. So what are the advantages to IPS compared to IDS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stops packets that trigger an alert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can use stream normalization techniques (since the IPS sensor is inline with the traffic it can reduce many network attacks that exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the IDS the IPS does have disadvantage when compared to IDS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the sensor is connected directly (inline) with the network it might affect network traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the sensor is overloaded that will also impact the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A company must have a thought-out security policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There can be some latency, jitter etc. with the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why use IPS instead of IDS? Well IDS is an older technology and like mentioned before IDS only alerts you that an attack is happening, it logs the attack and that&#39;s it. Network attacks can happen fast and some of them only need a small amount of time to complete the attack. So once a network technician gets into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Networking_hardware&#34; title=&#34;Networking hardware&#34;&gt;network equipment&lt;/a&gt; the attacker could be long gone and got what he/she needed. Sure you can now fix the problem but it might be little too late. IPS is able to load signature files this is like the definitions on your anti-virus software which it looks for patterns based on the attack. Which IPS can take that same style and block those attacks based on the security policies you implement, along with alerting you of what happened. That&#39;s my brief rundown of what these two technologies do  there is a lot more information you will be able to find on the web. But both have their places in the networking environment and it all depends on the money the company wants to spend to keep their networks secure. You can find more information at Cisco.com and or other places, I hope this information was informative.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding CBAC</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Although using hardware firewalls are an excellent step forward when securing your network. They can cost money and are not cheap to set up and configure. Using CBAC is built-into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/en/US/products/ps6537/products_ios_sub_category_home.html&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; router and helps filter those unwanted protocols that are in your network. When setting up routers as firewalls you have some choices like using CBAC the &amp;quot;Classic&amp;quot; firewall, or zone based policy (ZBF). Today we will talk about CBAC and how to understand the core components of what make &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context-based_access_control&#34; title=&#34;Context-based access control&#34;&gt;CBAC&lt;/a&gt; possible. CBAC stands for Content-Base-&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control&#34; title=&#34;Access control&#34;&gt;Access-Control&lt;/a&gt; and uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control_list&#34; title=&#34;Access control list&#34;&gt;ACLs&lt;/a&gt;. (Access Control Lists) Unlike the established TCP session and reflexive ACLs CBAC has several advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitors TCP connections, (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transmission_Control_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Transmission Control Protocol&#34;&gt;Three-way handshake&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintains &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_Datagram_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;User Datagram Protocol&#34;&gt;UDP&lt;/a&gt; session information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracks TCP sequence numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspects DNS queries and replies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inspection&#34; title=&#34;Inspection&#34;&gt;Inspect&lt;/a&gt; common &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Control_Message_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Control Message Protocol&#34;&gt;ICMP&lt;/a&gt; messages types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports applications that rely on multiple connections (FTP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspects embedded address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspects &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Application Layer&#34;&gt;Application Layer&lt;/a&gt; information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACLs only look at the network layer and sometimes the transport layer. CBAC is application aware, meaning CBAC is a stateful firewall which keeps track of the state of network connections such as TCP streams, and UDP communication travelling across it. The firewall is programmed to distinguish legitimate packets for different types of connections. Only packets matching a known connection state will be allowed by the firewall; others will be rejected. Because CBAC only matches packets (TCP, UDP and other protocols) it was specified to look at, it will then depend on the ACL if that packet is allowed access or denied. CBAC creates openings in ACLs at the interfaces that inspect the traffic by adding a temporary ACL entry for a specific session. The openings are created when the internal network starts a session with the outside network that would normally be denied. The traffic is only allowed back through the firewall if it is part of the same session and has the correct properties that CBAC is looking for. For example let&#39;s say a user starts an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Session_management&#34; title=&#34;Session management&#34;&gt;http session&lt;/a&gt; in the protected network and the packet moves to the outside or unprotected network. CBAC is configured to inspect http traffic and there is an ACL on the inbound (outside interface) blocking http traffic from the unprotected network to the protected network. So the packet is allowed access to the unprotected network because the ACL is on the inbound interface and not the outbound interface. So the ACL does not look at the packet, CBAC however looks at the packet and in the inspection rules the packet is allowed access to the unprotected network, CBAC adds an entry in its state table. Because a new entry is added a dynamic ACL is created on the external interface to the protected network. This dynamic ACL will allow http traffic back into the protected network. This opening is only active it the session is open, once the session closes the ACL is removed. Once removed any traffic that starts from the unprotected network will be denied access to the protected network. This depends on the ACL which checks inbound connections from the unprotected network.&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/cbac-firewall-config/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/cbac-firewall-config.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;CBAC Firewall&#34; title=&#34;CBAC Firewall-config&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/cbac-firewall-config.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; To configure CBAC there are four steps to set up CBAC efficiently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick an interface of where you want CBAC to be inspecting; this depends on the flow of your network and the amount of interfaces you have installed on your router. (DMZ, Web server, E-mail servers, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure IP ACLs at the interface. The network technician must define what type of traffic is allowed and will not be inspected by CBAC and which traffic is blocked and will be inspected by CBAC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define inspection rules. The network technician should specify each desired application layer to inspect along with generic TCP, ICMP and or UDP fields. Inspection rules are configured by statements each listing a protocol and specifying the inspection rule name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally apply the inspection rule to an interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBAC is considered the &amp;quot;classic&amp;quot; firewall compared to zone based, it is relatively simple to configure and understand. However unlike zone based CBAC can get complex when multiple CBAC configurations on a router exists. Remember CBAC also uses ACLs if configured and implemented poorly these ACLs can block traffic even when CBAC allows them. I hope this tutorial was helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
