<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nexus on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/nexus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nexus on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 13:18:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/nexus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enable the NX-OS API</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/10/18/enable-the-nx-os-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 13:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/10/18/enable-the-nx-os-api/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So what has changed in the past 20 years? Take for example the network equipment that was manufactured in 1997, how did you configure that equipment? I would imagine it involved a serial port, HyperTerminal and trusty command line. Was API even a thing back in 1997, was it common to have an API interface in network equipment like today? Why do we even need an API on the equipment in the first place?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t get stuck with &#34;speed-groups&#34;</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/12/21/dont-get-stuck-with-speed-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 03:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/12/21/dont-get-stuck-with-speed-groups/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was working with a Cisco 9372TX switch, and on it I had two 40Gbps uplinks that we where using out of the available four. Talking with our VAR because we where planning on connecting in additional equipment that only supported SFP+ interfaces. So the solution was to connect to this switch with QSFP to SFP+ adapters.
Thinking this would be a simple change because we are just plugging in additional adapters on the QSFP ports we planned our maintenance window and rollback plans but I wasn&#39;t expecting a rollback for this one :) The interfaces were configured in a shutdown status before we plugged in the adapters and cables so didn&#39;t see anything out of the ordinary, when it was time to do the maintenance let&#39;s bring up the interfaces with the command of no shutdown and we should be up.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed the 640-911 DCICN</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/05/14/passed-the-640-911-dcicn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 01:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/05/14/passed-the-640-911-dcicn/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco started this exam back in 2012 and I have thought/semi-studied about this test for about over a year now, just did not feel comfy about it until recently. I took the test last week and passed, however there were some questions on the exam I noticed that weren&#39;t on the exam blueprint so that kind of surprised me. I was happy to still be able to pass the exam but I was caught off guard.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Enhanced vPC on Nexus 5600</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/09/10/setting-up-enhanced-vpc-on-nexus-5600/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/09/10/setting-up-enhanced-vpc-on-nexus-5600/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I&#39;ve played around with two Cisco Nexus 5672UP switches which will be in production soon but before that I wanted to see what it took to get enhanced vPC online. Along the way I was into some new territory as I never stood up vPC before, so in this post I have posted some things to keep in mind and running-config examples, all of which I hope is helpful for a reference.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 12 &amp; 13)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/19/640-911-chapter-12-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 16:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/19/640-911-chapter-12-13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are at the last chapters of the CCNA Data Center 640-911 by Todd Lammle. Chapter 12 talks about redundant switched technologies and chapter 13 talks about security. Just like before I will go over the high-points, so let’s get started!
Chapter 12 Overview: In this chapter we get to learn about Spanning Tree Protocol and some history with it. With networks we like multiple ways to a destination however in the layer two area redundancy does not play well and that’s where spanning tree can help us.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 10 &amp; 11)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 01:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just like before if you have followed, I have gone over the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle and in this post we cover two chapters. Feel free to comment below if you have any questions on either of these two chapters.
Chapter 10 Overview: Chapter 10 starts us back in the book, before we do any configuring and we learn about routing protocols, and remember the difference between static and dynamic routing (name implies it) Also know the default administrate distances of the different routing protocols (starts on page 297).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter-VLAN Routing on the Nexus 5k</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 15:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I previously had the chance to play around with the 5596UP switch, and made some notes on how to configure inter-vlan routing. Since this was a 5596UP switch I needed a layer 3 card to take advantage of it. The next-generation units the 5600 include layer 3 without a card required along with introducing 40GB uplinks! However in this post let&#39;s go back to the basics and configure inter-vlan routing on a nexus switch and in this case I am using a 5596UP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 6)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/20/640-911-chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 19:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/20/640-911-chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s start chapter six of the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle, feel free to post questions if you have any. Like before I have covered the topics of the each chapter. Last week we learned about the different IP classes and today we get a course in subnetting. Let&#39;s go over what you should know if you want to pass the exam.
Overview: It seems I have talked subnetting to death on this blog, repetition, repetition, repetition.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting FEX (5k to 2k)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/12/01/connecting-fex-5k-to-2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 15:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/12/01/connecting-fex-5k-to-2k/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was pretty excited to get my hands on some of the Cisco Nexus product line which focuses on switching in the data center. The gear I have is an evaluation unit so I made some notes and one thing I was impressed is how easy it is to connect a Nexus 5K to a Nexus 2k also known as a fabric extender. I have kept it simple as the gear I have is a single Nexus 5596 along with a single Nexus 224TP-E who needs redundancy right?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Nexus 1000v?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/03/17/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 17:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/03/17/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network_cloud I have worked with the Nexus 1000v product and wanted to share my thoughts on it. I want to explain in this blog what this product is and what it does. The Nexus 1000v can be virtual or a hardware appliance and is considered to be a virtual switch that runs in VMware. The major benefit to this product is the visibly you get when running in a virtual environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
