<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GNS3 Jungle on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/gns3-jungle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GNS3 Jungle on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 20:31:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/gns3-jungle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 1.0 Public is Out</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/10/gns3-1.0-public-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 20:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/10/gns3-1.0-public-is-out/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/gns3_logo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/gns3_logo.png?w=119&#34; alt=&#34;gns3_logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Get your IOS, IOU, XRV, 1000v, HP, Juniper, Arista, and other images ready because that&#39;s the beauty of GNS3, it&#39;s here and ready to download. I&#39;m excited for this release although the last post I did was In May of 2014, which was about getting GNS3 Alpha 3 working on Windows, you can see the full post here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2014/05/09/gns3-alpha-install-and-setup/&#34; title=&#34;GNS3 Alpha – Install and Setup&#34;&gt;GNS3 Alpha – Install and Setup&lt;/a&gt;. I have followed the GNS3 releases throughout the six months of them releasing Alpha and beta releases, as well as looking at changlogs of each release. So over the past six months we have seen some changes with the GNS3 team. The new logo, the new website, and of course the new 1.0 version of GNS3. They have also done a good job of setting up a new portal called the GNS3 Jungle which is for the community to ask all things networking all of which is available now. Check out all of it at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gns3.com&#34; title=&#34;GNS3&#34;&gt;http://www.gns3.com/&lt;/a&gt;. Currently the GNS3 website is a little slow because I think we are all excited for the new software and can&#39;t wait to get our hands on it but I was able to register so I&#39;ll be posting more about the new version of GNS3 so keep that in mind, and check me out the GNS3 Jungle &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.gns3.com/people/lewiryan&#34;&gt;lewiryan.&lt;/a&gt;  Thanks again Stephen and Jeremy and the entire GNS3 team for building a great piece of software with the help of an awesome community. Another interesting read that I found was a post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://networkcanuck.com/&#34;&gt;NetworkCanuck&lt;/a&gt; about an Interview with Steven from GNS3, read it here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://networkcanuck.com/2014/10/20/gns3/&#34; title=&#34;GNS3 - An Interview&#34;&gt;GNS3 - An Interview&lt;/a&gt;. So I&#39;ll end this post with what are you loading into GNS3?&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
