<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Subnetwork on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/subnetwork/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Subnetwork on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 02:06:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/subnetwork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 2 – The Joys of Subnetttting – VLSM!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 02:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;So here we are on Part 2 of subnetting. What makes me laugh is that I really think a lot of people over think this stuff, and the fact that I mispelled subnetting! (Really? 4Ts) It&#39;s really not the complicated and it should not scare you. Another thing to mention is that usually in the real world you usually have calculators and another pair of eyes to double-check your work unlike the exam you will need to fully understand it if you would like to pass the ICND2 or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CCNA&#34; title=&#34;CCNA&#34;&gt;CCNA&lt;/a&gt; test. So let&#39;s get started! On Part 1 of my subnetting post I was spiting up networks into equal parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: If I took an original Class C address of 192.168.5.X (Subnet 255.255.255.0) in broke it up into four parts, each part would be equal. I would use a /26 or a 255.255.255.192. Each network would hold 62 hosts and I would have four of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;192.168.5.1 – 192.168.5.62&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;192.168.5.65 – 192.168.5.90&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;192.168.5.93 – 192.168.5.126&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;192.168.5.129 – 192.168.5.254&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example is standard subnetting if this loses you go back and check out my post of Part 1. Also check out this subnetting workbook (which is in Part 1) this workbook will help you to continue to practice subnetting, there are easier ways to get the answers but you have to start at the beginning and really have an understanding of it, once you got it you&#39;ll find the shortcuts everyone finds different ways to break this down :) -- &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/&#34; title=&#34;Part 1 – The Joys of Subnetting!&#34;&gt;Part 1 – The Joys of Subnetting!&lt;/a&gt; -- Subnetting Workbook --&lt;a href=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/files/2012/04/ip-subnetting-workbook.pdf&#34;&gt;IP-Subnetting-Workbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classless_Inter-Domain_Routing&#34; title=&#34;Classless Inter-Domain Routing&#34;&gt;VLSM&lt;/a&gt; it&#39;s basically the same method but a better way to conserve addresses, instead of having equal parts of the Class address why can&#39;t we divide it up and different size pieces? Take a look at the picture below one link requires 111 hosts another only needs 25 hosts and the last one needs 50 hosts. With standard subnetting you would not be able to fulfill this goal. However with VLSM you would let&#39;s go through the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/images/2012/04/vlsm-diagram.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So our corporation Acme wants to expand departments to three different buildings instead of one building. These buildings are connected via a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wide_area_network&#34; title=&#34;Wide area network&#34;&gt;WAN&lt;/a&gt; Link to each other. We are handed one &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34; title=&#34;IP address&#34;&gt;IP address&lt;/a&gt; class which is a class C from Acme&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tier_3&#34; title=&#34;Tier 3&#34;&gt;Tier 3&lt;/a&gt; support. No Problem let&#39;s break this down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is always best to take the biggest number of hosts required in this case it is the Finance department which requires 111 hosts. What is the next step? We can&#39;t give a whole class C address because we have two other departments so let&#39;s divide it into two. The subnet mask would be 255.255.255.128 and or a /25. These two networks would be able to hold 126 hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;192.168.16.1 - 192.168.16.126&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;192.168.16.129 – 192.168.16.254&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this look familiar? So far we are just doing standard subnettng, The Finance department will use the first range. What about the second one let&#39;s break it down even further! I would then choose the next biggest subnet which is the IT department which requires 50 hosts. So the range we can work with is 192.168.16.129 – 192.168.16.254. The subnet mask is 255.255.255.128 or a /25. This range is too big still because we still have one more department to work with. So let&#39;s break this down to a /26.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;192.168.16.129 – 192.168.16.190&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;192.168.16.193 – 192.168.16.254&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I just took the original /25 and spilt it into two equal pieces which is like the standard subnettng but now that we have different size networks within the same &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classful_network&#34; title=&#34;Classful network&#34;&gt;class C network&lt;/a&gt; it&#39;s now considered VLSM! I also have an address range that can work with for the IT department we will use 192.168.16.129 – 192.168.16.190. The subnet masks of these two IP address ranges are 255.255.255.192. Each network can hold up to 62 hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could give HR the other range and that might be a good &amp;quot;real world&amp;quot; solution because this looks to perfect right? But for the sake of the exam let&#39;s continue so we have the following range left to hack and slash: (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subnetwork&#34; title=&#34;Subnetwork&#34;&gt;Subnet mask&lt;/a&gt; is 255.255.255.192)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;192.168.16.193 – 192.168.16.254&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s break this down one more click to a /27 the subnet mask will be 255.255.255.224. These ranges will be able to handle up to 30 hosts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;192.168.16.193 – 192.168.16.222&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;192.168.16.225 – 192.168.16.254&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For HR let&#39;s pick the range 192.168.16.193 – 192.168.16.222 like before the subnet mask will be 255.255.255.224. That&#39;s VLSM!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not too bad right? What happens to the other range (192.168.16.225 – 192.168.16.254) that&#39;s a spare that can be used elsewhere in the environment of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acme_Corporation&#34; title=&#34;Acme Corporation&#34;&gt;Acme Corporation&lt;/a&gt;. So let&#39;s look at the picture of our ranges and networks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finance Network --111 Hosts
Range: (192.168.16.1 – 192.168.16.128) – &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subnetwork&#34; title=&#34;Subnetwork&#34;&gt;Subnet Mask&lt;/a&gt; 255.255.255.128 &lt;strong&gt;Can support up to 126 hosts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IT Network --50 Hosts
Range: (192.168.16.129 -192.168.16.190) – Subnet Mask 255.255.255.192 &lt;strong&gt;Can support up to 62 hosts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HR Network --25 Hosts
Range: (192.168.16.193 – 192.168.16.222) – Subnet Mask  255.255.255.224 &lt;strong&gt;Can support up to 30 hosts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll let that sink in if you have a question feel free to post it, I or others would be happy to help you out :). Here is another question for you where else would you put IP addresses that the diagram doesn&#39;t say? How many would you need if any? How many networks would you have total including the three networks we did? Like always I hope this information is helpful and if you have a question post it, if you have an idea on the next topic post it!! Have an awesome day! - Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/&#34;&gt;Part 1 - The Joys of Subnetting!&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/31/configure-router-on-a-stick/&#34;&gt;Configure Router on a Stick&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gunnalag.wordpress.com/2012/04/08/configuring-dhcp-server-in-windows-server-2008-r2/&#34;&gt;Configuring DHCP Server in Windows Server 2008 R2&lt;/a&gt; (gunnalag.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gunnalag.wordpress.com/2012/04/08/subnetting-purpose-of-it-and-how-it-works/&#34;&gt;Subnetting, purpose of it and how it works&lt;/a&gt; (gunnalag.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22peter.gavin@live.com%22&#34;&gt;ITforMe&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-23 21:21:49&#34;&gt;Apr 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very nice post. Thanks for the comment about subnet calculators. Some traditionalists might flog a guy over the head for using such a thing, but as an &amp;quot;Army of One&amp;quot; IT Generalist, a subnetting calculator allows me to make better decisions more quickly. That is the least I owe to my employer. It is also usefull as a visualization tool to give some sense of sizing of address boundaries; an important component of designs. Keep up the great posts!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;ICND2 – Passed! | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-05-14 20:33:04&#34;&gt;May 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-23 21:34:54&#34;&gt;Apr 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are welcome :) I agree with your comment, in the &amp;quot;real world&amp;quot; you need to make sure that address scheme works before you deploy it. Calculators can help with that. For exams you better know it inside and out! Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1 - The Joys of Subnetting!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 20:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_network&#34; title=&#34;Computer network&#34;&gt;network&lt;/a&gt; technicians work with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34; title=&#34;IP address&#34;&gt;IP addressing&lt;/a&gt;, it is hugely important to understand subnetting. I remember back when I started to learn subnetting it was confusing and I wanted nothing to do with it. The thing that made me change my mind was after I understood it and how important it is. In the &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; world&amp;quot; they don&#39;t cover useless topics...right? ;) there is always a reason why they expect you to know this and it&#39;s not just for the exams. Subnetting has always had its moments with people and in this blog I&#39;ll do my best to show you what I have done to make subnetting an easier experience. Eons ago I talked about &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/15/the-wonders-of-binary/&#34; title=&#34;The Wonders of Binary&#34;&gt;The Wonders of Binary&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; which talked about how to convert these ones and zeros into &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decimal&#34; title=&#34;Decimal&#34;&gt;decimal value&lt;/a&gt; and is another stepping stone into understanding the subnet world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s introduce the three classes of subnet masks that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_computer&#34; title=&#34;Personal computer&#34;&gt;PCs&lt;/a&gt; can use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class A: 1-127 -- &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subnetwork&#34; title=&#34;Subnetwork&#34;&gt;Subnet Mask&lt;/a&gt;: 255.0.0.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class B: 128-191 &lt;strong&gt;Subnet Mask: 255.255.0.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class C: 192-223 &lt;strong&gt;Subnet Mask: 255.255.255.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you get it? Let me explain what is going on, back when the internet was young and just started out we had three &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classful_network&#34; title=&#34;Classful network&#34;&gt;IP classes&lt;/a&gt; you could use. These classes would be handed out depending on the size of the organization. Usually universities would get a Class B address range, big companies like GE received a class A address. The problem with this is it&#39;s a waste of addresses when would you ever have 65,534 &lt;em&gt;(Class B)&lt;/em&gt; or 16,277,214 &lt;em&gt;(Class A)&lt;/em&gt; computers on the same network? &lt;strong&gt;Nothing would work!&lt;/strong&gt; What could I do to break this down into separate networks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s where subnetting comes into play, if I had class B address range I could break it up into smaller networks, watch and be amazed. Let&#39;s say my class B range is &lt;strong&gt;134.50.0.0 – 134.50.255.255&lt;/strong&gt; in this range I have one network so I could have 65,534 computers connected to this. We already said this is stupid setup because nothing would be able talk because this network would be over saturated, remember computers are chatty fellows even when you don&#39;t use them. But what I could do is break this address into smaller ranges, instead of one big network I could break it into a Class C address. See if you follow this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;134.50.1.0 – 134.50.1.255&lt;/strong&gt; –Subnet &lt;strong&gt;255.255.255.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;134.50.2.0 – 134.50.2.255&lt;/strong&gt; – Subnet &lt;strong&gt;255.255.255.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;134.50.3.0 – 134.50.3.255&lt;/strong&gt; – Subnet &lt;strong&gt;255.255.255.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;134.50.4.0 – 134.50.5.255&lt;/strong&gt; – Subnet &lt;strong&gt;255.255.255.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;134.50.255.0 – 134.50.255.255&lt;/strong&gt; –Subnet &lt;strong&gt;255.255.255.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what did I just do? Just what I said I would do I broke up this network into smaller networks, so how many networks do I have now? Well instead of one big network I now have 256 smaller networks with each network able to handle 254 computers. Real world example is if this was a campus environment each building can have its own network. Building A can have the 134.50.1.0 network, building B can have the 134.50.2.0 network, etc. This makes the network scalable and way easier to manage, and that&#39;s the basics of how subnetting works, for now remember you can always take a bigger subnet and break it down into smaller ones. It is a little tricky to take small subnets and expand them but remember it can be done with something called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classless_Inter-Domain_Routing&#34; title=&#34;Classless Inter-Domain Routing&#34;&gt;VLSM&lt;/a&gt; and if you designed your network scheme correctly :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also check out this subnetting workbook which will help you to continue to practice subnetting, there are easier ways to get the answers but you have to start at the beginning and really have an understanding of it, once you got it you&#39;ll find the shortcuts :cool:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/files/2012/04/ip-subnetting-workbook.pdf&#34;&gt;IP-Subnetting-Workbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have used this exact one when I was studying subnetting, try it out and if you have questions feel free to post them. Also if you have other ideas of the next topic I should cover that deals with ICND1 or ICND2 let me know. As always I hope this information is helpful and since this is part 1 of subnetting check back often see if I posted part 2 which will deal with VLSM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/31/configure-router-on-a-stick/&#34;&gt;Configure Router on a Stick&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://computrnetworking.wordpress.com/2012/02/20/network-subnetting/&#34;&gt;Network Subnetting&lt;/a&gt; (computrnetworking.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ioshints.info/2012/03/stretched-layer-2-subnets-server.html&#34;&gt;Stretched Layer-2 Subnets - The Server Engineer Perspective&lt;/a&gt; (ioshints.info)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Part 2 – The Joys of Subnetttting – VLSM! | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-23 21:08:37&#34;&gt;Apr 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22winnissa92@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;winnie&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-24 08:54:18&#34;&gt;Apr 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;thanks so much for help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-24 19:15:53&#34;&gt;Apr 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re Welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22winnissa92@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;winnie&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-24 00:34:19&#34;&gt;Apr 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i need you help with this question: with a given network 192.168.50.1, create 8 subnets, how r u going to do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-24 07:51:23&#34;&gt;Apr 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, So you need 8 equal networks in a class C address, instead of looking at the number of hosts you are looking at the number of networks. To get 8 equal networks we need to subnet them down to a /27, each network would be able to hold 30 hosts and you would have 8 of them. /25 gives you two networks (255.255.255.128) /26 gives you four networks (255.255.255.192) /27 gives you eight networks (255.255.255.224) ... See a pattern here, they go by the powers of two. Here is my range: 192.168.50.1 - 192.168.50.254 - Original (255.255.255.0) Subnet Ranges all of them are equal and subnet mask is 255.255.255.224 192.168.50.1 - 192.168.50.30 192.168.50.33 - 192.168.50.62 192.168.50.65 - 192.168.50.94 192.168.50.97 - 192.168.50.126 192.168.50.129 - 192.168.50.158 192.168.50.161 - 192.168.50.191 192.168.50.193 - 192.168.50.222 192.168.50.225 - 192.168.50.254 Does that make sense of how I found them? I would also check out that subnetting workbook which is in Part 2 and Part 1 for download. Hope that Helps thanks for the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Router on a Stick</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/31/configure-router-on-a-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 10:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/31/configure-router-on-a-stick/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;A while ago I talked about putting different &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_LAN&#34; title=&#34;Virtual LAN&#34;&gt;VLANs&lt;/a&gt; on a switch, remember a VLAN is virtual network that although physically it may look like on the same network that does not always mean the case. By having VLANs you are segmenting the network and the only way to get to the other side is having a router. I have already configured the Cisco switch as posted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/&#34; title=&#34;Creating VLANs&#34;&gt;Creating VLANs&lt;/a&gt; but in summary I have three VLANs total VLAN 1 which is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Inter-Switch_Link&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Inter-Switch Link&#34;&gt;native VLAN&lt;/a&gt;, VLAN 2 and VLAN 3 (which is called support. If you like to understand how create VLANs on a switch follow the post above. If you look at the network topology below you can see where Cisco came up with the name &amp;quot;Router on Stick&amp;quot; each PC is on its own network and needs the router in order for traffic to pass between the networks. Like before I have three VLANs total. VLAN 1 which is the native VLAN, VLAN 2 and VLAN 3 (which is called &amp;quot;Support&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/images/2012/01/31/configure-router-on-a-stick/router-on-a-sticke/&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to create sub-interfaces on the router to route between different VLANs these sub-interfaces do not correspond to the VLANs so you could put any number but for manageability usually people use the same sub-interface has the VLAN ID. To create a sub-interface start typing the interface that will be physically connected to the switch at the end add a period and number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;Router#config t 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;Router(config)#interface fastEthernet 0/0.2
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;Router(config-subif)#
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You are now in the sub-interface configuration, we want to tell the router which VLAN this interface will be a part of. In this example I am typing &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;encapsulation dot1Q 2&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; dot1Q is an IEEE standard 802.1Q , the number &amp;quot;two&amp;quot; is the VLAN this interface will be a part of. Just like a real interface this interface must have an IP address for end devices to reach it. In this example we are using 192.168.2.1 with a Class C subnet mask. (i.e 255.255.255.0)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;Router(config-subif)#encapsulation dot1Q 2
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;Router(config-subif)#ip address 192.168.2.1 255.255.255.0
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;Router(config-subif)#no shut
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We do the same for VLAN 3 (Support) in which we will create a new sub-interface in this example I am using sub-interface 3, and I&#39;m going to be putting this sub-interface in VLAN 3 by using &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;encapsulation dot1Q 3&amp;quot;.&lt;/strong&gt; Remember the sub-interface number has no effect on which VLAN this interface is a part of. I&#39;m also adding a IP address of 192.168.3.1 with a Class C subnet mask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;Router#config t
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z.
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;Router(config)#interface fastEthernet 0/0.3
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;Router(config-subif)# 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;Router(config-subif)#encapsulation dot1Q 3
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;Router(config-subif)#ip address 192.168.3.1 255.255.255.0
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;Router(config-subif)#no shut
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last VLAN is the native VLAN and by default is VLAN 1, for this configuration go to the physical interface and add an IP address for this example we are using 192.168.1.1 with a Class C subnet mask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;Router#config t
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z.
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;Router(config)#interface fastEthernet 0/0
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;Router(config-if)#ip address 192.168.1.1 255.255.255.0
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;Router(config-if)#no shut
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last thing we have to setup is on the Cisco Switch in which we have to specify which interface on the switch will pass all the VLANs, this is known as the trunking port. Go into configuration mode and for this example we selected FastEthernet0/1 apply the &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;switchport mode trunk&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; command and since we are using the default native VLAN which is not always recommended that&#39;s all the configuration needed. We now have three different networks separated by VLANs, if you issue a &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;show ip route&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; on the router we will see each sub-interface and route to each of them. All devices should be able to ping each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;Switch&amp;gt;en
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;Switch#config t
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;Enter configuration commands, one per line.  End with CNTL/Z.
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;Switch(config)#interface fastEthernet 0/1
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;Switch(config-if)#switchport mode trunk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt;Router#show ip route
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;Codes: C - connected, S - static, I - IGRP, R - RIP, M - mobile, B - BGP
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;       D - EIGRP, EX - EIGRP external, O - OSPF, IA - OSPF inter area
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;       N1 - OSPF NSSA external type 1, N2 - OSPF NSSA external type 2
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;       E1 - OSPF external type 1, E2 - OSPF external type 2, E - EGP
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;       i - IS-IS, L1 - IS-IS level-1, L2 - IS-IS level-2, ia - IS-IS inter area
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;       * - candidate default, U - per-user static route, o - ODR
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;       P - periodic downloaded static route
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;Gateway of last resort is not set
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;C    192.168.1.0/24 is directly connected, FastEthernet0/0
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;C    192.168.2.0/24 is directly connected, FastEthernet0/0.2
&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;C    192.168.3.0/24 is directly connected, FastEthernet0/0.3
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this information is helpful I have also attached a PDF of the running-config of both devices to give you an example of the configuration. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/files/2012/01/router-on-stick-example-runconfig.pdf&#34;&gt;Router-On-Stick-Example-RunConfig&lt;/a&gt;) If you have any questions post them below. Like always if you an idea of the next topic let me hear it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/11/02/ospf-what-a-protocol/&#34;&gt;OSPF...What a Protocol!&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ipv6area.wordpress.com/2011/12/08/what-is-ipv6-an-introduction-to-ipv6/&#34;&gt;What is IPv6 ? An introduction to IPV6&lt;/a&gt; (ipv6area.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edugeek.net/forums/networks/89609-guest-vlans-guest-wifi-different-ip-range-out-filtered-internet.html&#34;&gt;Guest VLANS + Guest Wifi - Different IP Range, Out to Filtered Internet&lt;/a&gt; (edugeek.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mungauwamaseghe.wordpress.com/2012/01/31/journey-to-the-ccie-lab-part-44-bgp-link-bandwidth/&#34;&gt;Journey to the CCIE LAB - Part 44 - BGP Link Bandwidth&lt;/a&gt; (mungauwamaseghe.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gravatar.com/aslan77777&#34; title=&#34;ciscodaze@live.com&#34;&gt;Theophilus&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-08 17:11:20&#34;&gt;Jun 5, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw your comment on not having to use the encap command when using the actual interface (fa0/0), but I was wondering, (since you typically see books and tutorials NOT using the actual interface, but instead, typically fa0/0.1), are there any other ramifications to using one as opposed to the other?? Fa0/0 as opposed to Fa0/0.1?? Thanks, Kevin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aslan77777.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;ciscodaze@live.com&#34;&gt;Theophilus&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-08 17:17:52&#34;&gt;Jun 5, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besided the encapsulation command, are there any ramifications to using Fa0/0 for vlan 1 (instead of Fa0/0.1, as typically shown in ROAS configs)? Thanks, Kevin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-08 18:13:58&#34;&gt;Jun 5, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Kevin, The only reason this is set on the physical interface is because it is using un-tagged traffic also know as the native VLAN. You can&#39;t set the encapsulation dot1q on a physical interface only sub-interfaces. A better way to do this is use a sub-interface followed by: encapsulation dot1Q [VLAN-ID] native I don&#39;t see any problems with this method besides security and monitoring. For example If you wanted to see all traffic passing in and out of the physical interface using Netflow or SNMP you would not see that in this example, you would only see the native VLAN traffic. For security you should not use the native VLAN in production so this example it is not using best practices therefore I would not recommend it. This post goes along with another post I did about creating VLANs on a switch: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/&#34;&gt;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/&lt;/a&gt; Hope that Helps, Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Part 1 – The Joys of Subnetting! | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-01 15:03:41&#34;&gt;Apr 0, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configure Router on a Stick (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Part 2 – The Joys of Subnetttting – VLSM! | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-23 21:08:49&#34;&gt;Apr 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configure Router on a Stick (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://petespacket.com/2012/03/08/how-to-configure-a-catalyst-37503750-e3750-x-series-switches-using-lldp-link-layer-discovery-protocol/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;How to configure a Catalyst 3750/3750-E/3750-X Series Switches Using LLDP (Link Layer Discovery Protocol) « Pete�s Packet&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-03-08 14:00:56&#34;&gt;Mar 4, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configure Router on a Stick [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-01-31 22:34:25&#34;&gt;Jan 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are talking about the trunk link between the switch and the router it will pass up to the router and then be forwarded back down to the switch. So if you had a lot of traffic being forwarded between networks you could run into some bandwidth limits. To fix that you could configure a switch that does layer 3 routing and skip the router all together that way you would not be dependent on that one link to forward all of your traffic back and forth. The native VLAN by default is VLAN 1 and that can be changed. The only difference between a native VLAN and a regular VLAN is it passes un-tagged traffic. If you look at the router configuration I&#39;ve setup, the physical interface (fa0/0) notice how I don&#39;t have to put the encapsulation, because this is traffic is not tagged with a VLAN. To answer you question you can put everything on a VLAN and forget about the default/native VLAN. A good practice to use is to change it to a non-default number something other than 1 and a VLAN that you are not using in your network. However make sure every switch has the correct native VLAN or you will get messages about native VLAN mismatched. Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.studio1250.com&#34; title=&#34;philip@studio1250.com&#34;&gt;Philip&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-02-23 13:58:30&#34;&gt;Feb 4, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great article! Thanks for the info. I was talking to my friend about this last night and when I got into packet tracer I couldn&#39;t quite figure out how to assign multiple ip addresses to a single interface. I&#39;m glad you took the time to write up this example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-02-23 20:32:32&#34;&gt;Feb 4, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glad I could help. :) The configuration is pretty straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gravatar.com/aslan77777&#34; title=&#34;ciscodaze@live.com&#34;&gt;Theophilus&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-10 14:34:04&#34;&gt;Jun 0, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-10&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/11/trunking-administrative-modes/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Trunking Administrative Modes | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-02-11 16:05:33&#34;&gt;Feb 6, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-11&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/28/eigrp-the-basics/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;EIGRP… The Basics | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-02-28 19:53:58&#34;&gt;Feb 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configure Router on a Stick (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-12&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gravatar.com/pedrok00&#34; title=&#34;peter.gavin@live.com&#34;&gt;ITforMe&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-01-31 21:21:36&#34;&gt;Jan 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good post. Thanks for sharing. Can you confirm that with intervlan routing, that one would not run into the bandwidth limitations imposed by a traditional upstream router? (e.g. say, 50 ports feeding upstream to a physical router only to pipe back down into the switch). In other words, is a router on a stick configuration smart enough to know that if it needs to route across two VLANs that happen to live on the same port, that it isolates the flow of traffic to just that port? I&#39;m also interested in what your thoughts are on the default VLAN 1. It seems that it is often more than just the factory VLAN, but that it may hold special characteristics and limitations (e.g. routing, etc.). If that is the case, would you suggest taking a new stack of switches, and making all of the untagged ports to the systems/workstations on something like VLAN101, with a PVID of 101, so as to prevent any traffic from going across the default VLAN?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classful vs. Classless Routing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 16:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/cloud-computing-icon.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/cloud-computing-icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Cloud-Computing-icon&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Before the internet and general networking become popular into what it is now, there were and still are routing protocols that only do &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classful_network&#34; title=&#34;Classful network&#34;&gt;classful routing&lt;/a&gt;. What is classful routing? When I was talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adaptive_routing&#34; title=&#34;Adaptive routing&#34;&gt;Dynamic Routing&lt;/a&gt; earlier (See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/&#34; title=&#34;Dynamic Routing Protocols&#34;&gt;Dynamic Routing Protocols&lt;/a&gt;) I mentioned there was a difference between classful routing and classless routing. So in today&#39;s post let&#39;s focus on these two but important topics when using routing protocols. Let&#39;s first talk about classful routing, which is sometimes called a classful network. If you are using a classful routing protocol then all of your networks are in different classes and are separated by a router. Remember that the useable IPv4 address ranges are dived into classes. Class A 1-126, Class B 128-191, and Class C 192-223. So when we talk about a classful routing protocol it will only look at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34; title=&#34;IP address&#34;&gt;IP address&lt;/a&gt; class and not the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subnetwork&#34; title=&#34;Subnetwork&#34;&gt;subnet mask&lt;/a&gt;. This is the problem; if you are using a classful routing protocol you cannot change the subnet mask in any of these networks. You have to use the default subnet mask, so an example is if you have a 172.16.X.X network the default subnet mask is a /16 or 255.255.0.0. So in short you can&#39;t have different size networks when using the same IP address class and a classful routing protocol. Remember  that classful routing does not support subnet information, and therefore lacking support for VLSM (variable length subnet masks). With classless routing if you took a guess that it supports VLSM and different size networks within the same IP address class then you&#39;re catching on ;) Because that is exactly what a classless routing protocol does, so for example we are using a class C address of 192.168.1.0 with a standard subnet mask of 255.255.255.0 or a /24. With a classless routing protocol you can split this network even more instead of having 254 usable hosts in one network; we could have 126 usable hosts with two networks. The ranges for the first network would start at 192.168.1.1 and end at 192.168.1.126, and the second would start at 192.168.1.129 and end at 192.168.1.254. The subnet mask for both of these networks would be 255.255.255.128. With a classful routing protocol it would only look at the class of the address in this case a class &amp;quot;C&amp;quot; and not look at the subnet mask and apply a default subnet mask of 255.255.255.0 causing these addresses to be in the same network which in reality their not. &lt;em&gt;What &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Routing_protocol&#34; title=&#34;Routing protocol&#34;&gt;Routing Protocol&lt;/a&gt; uses Classful and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classless_Inter-Domain_Routing&#34; title=&#34;Classless Inter-Domain Routing&#34;&gt;Classless Routing&lt;/a&gt;? Take a guess…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Routing_Information_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Routing Information Protocol&#34;&gt;RIP&lt;/a&gt;-1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RIP-2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enhanced_Interior_Gateway_Routing_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Enhanced Interior Gateway Routing Protocol&#34;&gt;EIGRP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Shortest_Path_First&#34; title=&#34;Open Shortest Path First&#34;&gt;OSPF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IS-IS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classless&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supports VLSM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send Subnet Mask&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s my summary for classful and classless routing protocols, I wouldn&#39;t say nobody uses a classful routing protocol there&#39;s always someone but they are different and will cause connection problems if set up incorrectly. Like always I hope this information was informative and you can always find more information at Cisco or even a search of RFC 1519 and RFC 1817. Have an idea of the next topic either ICND1 or ICND2 let me know. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/&#34;&gt;How a Router Routes&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thinkup.waldenu.edu/technology/networking/item/11465-why-are-routed-protocols-important-to-networking&amp;amp;sa=U&amp;amp;ei=HYNTTYuiIpKDtgfqrMy5CQ&amp;amp;ved=0CKoBEBYwRzigBg&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFSXtq9ycdurVCAL65GXgWu2sg7BA&#34;&gt;Why Are Routed Protocols Important to Networking?&lt;/a&gt; (thinkup.waldenu.edu)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/09/configuring-ripv2/&#34; title=&#34;Configuring RIPv2&#34;&gt;Configuring RIPv2&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/&#34;&gt;Configure Static Routing&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Distance Vector Routing | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-15 10:32:46&#34;&gt;Jun 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Classful vs. Classless Routing (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Static Routing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Plugging Cisco &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;routers&lt;/a&gt; together and hoping they work out of the box is not something you should hope for. A router can learn about networks in two ways, manually from configured static routers which we will talk about today and dynamic &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Routing&#34; title=&#34;Routing&#34;&gt;routing&lt;/a&gt; protocols which will talk about on Wednesday. Let&#39;s get started! Static routes are not that uncommon they at first need some attention to get set up but after it is working nothing needs to change. A good example of using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Static_routing&#34; title=&#34;Static routing&#34;&gt;static route&lt;/a&gt; is with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stub_network&#34; title=&#34;Stub network&#34;&gt;stub network&lt;/a&gt;. A stub network is only accessed by a single router and no other routes are configured so there is only one path the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_traffic_measurement&#34; title=&#34;Network traffic measurement&#34;&gt;network traffic&lt;/a&gt; can take. Notice the picture below and how any traffic going towards the network cloud from the 192.168.1.0 network will always pass the 172.16.5.0 network. Why waste putting a routing protocol here?) &lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/static_default_route.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Stub Network&#34;&gt;In order to configure a static route you must be in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;global configuration mode&lt;/a&gt;, the ip route command complete &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntax&#34; title=&#34;Syntax&#34;&gt;syntax&lt;/a&gt; is the following: &lt;strong&gt;ip route&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;prefix mask&lt;/em&gt; {&lt;em&gt;ip-address&lt;/em&gt;} | &lt;em&gt;interface-type interface-number&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;em&gt;ip-address&lt;/em&gt;]} [&lt;strong&gt;dhcp&lt;/strong&gt;] [&lt;em&gt;distance&lt;/em&gt;] [&lt;strong&gt;name&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;next-hop-name&lt;/em&gt;] [&lt;strong&gt;permanent&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;track&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt;] [&lt;strong&gt;tag&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;tag&lt;/em&gt;] For the CCENT/CCNA the complete syntax is not relevant, let&#39;s use a simpler version of the ip route syntax: &lt;strong&gt;ip route&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;network-address&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subnetwork&#34; title=&#34;Subnetwork&#34;&gt;subnet-mask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; {&lt;em&gt;ip address&lt;/em&gt; | &lt;em&gt;exit interface&lt;/em&gt;} The &lt;em&gt;network address&lt;/em&gt; is the destination network or the remote address that will be added in the routing table. (For the complete syntax this follows on the prefix parameter) The &lt;em&gt;subnet mask&lt;/em&gt; is the subnet mask of the remote network that will be added in the routing table. (For the complete syntax this follows on the mask parameter) One or both of the following commands must be configured: The &lt;em&gt;ip-address&lt;/em&gt; in the syntax is usually called the next-hop router&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34; title=&#34;IP address&#34;&gt;IP address&lt;/a&gt; The &lt;em&gt;exit-interface&lt;/em&gt; is the outgoing interface that would be used in forwarding the packets io the destination network (For the complete syntax this follows on the &lt;strong&gt;interface-type&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;interface-number&lt;/em&gt; parameter) Looking at the picture above we need to have a static route on R2, we can do these in two ways the first example is using the next hop IP address. (For this example the next hop IP address is 172.16.5.1 R1&#39;s serial 0/0/0 interface. The next example is using the exit interface out of R2. [code]R2(config)#ip route 192.168.1.0 255.255.255.0 172.16.5.1[/code]   [code]R2(config)#ip route 192.168.1.0 255.255.255.0 serial 0/0/1[/code] The last thing we need to do in order for this stub network to work is put a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Default_route&#34; title=&#34;Default route&#34;&gt;default route&lt;/a&gt; on R1 because R2 is going to the cloud the (internet or network) any traffic like a web request going to the internet needs to be forwarded to R2. A default route is a route that will match every IP address. Remember that a router does not have every single possible route on the internet or network usually these can be summary routes and default routes. Like on R2 we can do this in two ways, the first example is using the next hop IP address. (For this example the next hop IP address is 172.16.5.2 R2&#39;s serial 0/0/1 interface. The next example is using the exit interface out of R1. [code]R1(config)#ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 172.16.5.2[/code]   [code]R1(config)#ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 serial 0/0/0[/code] That&#39;s my tutorial for configuring static routes. Static routes do need some overhead but once you get them working you don&#39;t need to even touch it again. You can find more information at Cisco.com and the Cisco Learning Network. Like always I hope this information/tutorial was informative if you have any ideas on the next topic I should cover in the ICND1 or ICND2 area let me know by commenting below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://joernfranz.net/2011/01/12/configuring-static-dynamic-ip-address-under-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;Configuring static / dynamic IP address under Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; (joernfranz.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/static-ip-address-advantages-disadvantages/&#34;&gt;What Is A Static IP Address, How Do I Get One &amp;amp; Its Advantages / Disadvantages&lt;/a&gt; (makeuseof.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brighthub.com/internet/web-development/articles/113397.aspx&#34;&gt;How to Find Your IP Address&lt;/a&gt; (brighthub.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/&#34;&gt;Configure a Site-to-Site VPN via SDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ghacks.net/2011/04/29/why-your-home-router-is-192-168-1-1/&#34;&gt;Why Your Home Router is 192.168.1.1&lt;/a&gt; (ghacks.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Dynamic Routing Protocols | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-05-04 11:07:03&#34;&gt;May 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a Router Routes</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 17:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;This tutorial will be going over the basic information of how a router routes &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Protocol&#34;&gt;IP packets&lt;/a&gt;. Routers are used in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI layer&lt;/a&gt; three or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Network Layer&#34;&gt;network layer&lt;/a&gt;. These routers have IP addresses and forward IP packets to the proper destination. This guide is somewhat basic and is assuming you have some information of how &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34; title=&#34;IP address&#34;&gt;IP addressing&lt;/a&gt; works and along with what routing protocols are. So let&#39;s focus first on how a host or a computer forwards traffic and then look at how a router forwards traffic. Computers forward or send packets based on these two steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the destination IP address is in the same network or subnet as PC-1 then send the packet directly to that host (without the routers help)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If PC-1 does not have the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MAC_address&#34; title=&#34;MAC address&#34;&gt;MAC address&lt;/a&gt; to the destination host (PC-2) then it will send an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Address_Resolution_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Address Resolution Protocol&#34;&gt;ARP&lt;/a&gt; request to get the MAC address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/arp-message/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/arp-message.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;ARP Message (Broadcast)&#34; title=&#34;ARP-Message&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/arp-message.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; For example PC-1 (192.168.1.1) is trying to send to PC-2 (192.1681.2) since both of these computers are on the same network, (PC-1 checks the destination &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subnetwork&#34; title=&#34;Subnetwork&#34;&gt;subnet mask&lt;/a&gt; and IP address to see if they are on the same network which they are) if PC-1 knows the MAC address of PC-2 it will put the IP address of PC-2 in the destination address field along with other information not related to this tutorial and forward the packet. If PC-1 does not know the MAC address it will send and ARP request, what this request does is send a broadcast message to all other &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_computer&#34; title=&#34;Personal computer&#34;&gt;PCs&lt;/a&gt; and devices connected on the 192.168.1.0 network. This message wants to find the MAC address of the host connected to 192.168.1.2, once PC-2 gets the message it will send its MAC address to PC-1. PC-1 will then forward the packet to PC-2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the destination IP address is not in the same subnet or network has PC-1 then PC-1 will send the packet to its default gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If PC-1 does not have the MAC address to the default gateway (R1) then send a ARP request to get the MAC address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example PC-1 (192.168.1.1) is trying to send to R1 (192.168.1.254) because the packet is not in the same network, PC-1&#39;s main goal is to send to a webserver (154.63.2.1) (PC-1 checks the destination subnet mask and IP address to see if they are on the same network which they are not) if PC-1 knows the MAC address of R1 it will put the IP address of R1 in the destination address field along with other information not related to this tutorial, and forward the packet. If PC-1 does not know the MAC address it will send and ARP request, what this request does is send a broadcast message to all other PCs and devices connected on the 192.168.1.0 network. This message wants to find the MAC address of the host connected to 192.168.1.254, once R1 gets the message it will send its MAC address to PC-1. PC-1 will then forward the packet/frame. Once the frame is received by R1 the router will first check the data-link FCS field. If the frame received errors the router will drop the packet. If the frame has no errors the router will rip off the old data link header and trailer and then look at the IP packet. The router then compares the IP packet&#39;s destination address. If the router has the IP address in its routing table the router will encapsulate the IP packet inside a new data link layer header and trailer and forward it out the correct interface, thus forwarding the frame. Confusued? Let&#39;s go into some more detail of what happened. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/route-example/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/route-example.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Route-Example&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Looking at the topology PC-1 wants to send a packet to the web server. Since the web server is not on PC-1&#39;s network it will need to send the packet to its default gateway which is R1. PC-1 will build an IP packet with the destination IP address of the web server (154.63.2.1). PC-1 sends this has an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethernet_frame&#34; title=&#34;Ethernet frame&#34;&gt;Ethernet frame&lt;/a&gt; with the destination IP address of R1 and has the MAC address of R1. R1 receives the frame and because the MAC address matches R1, the router will copy the frame and process it. R1 checks the FCS and no errors have occurred, next the router will then discard the old Ethernet header and trailer. R1 will compare the address and see if it has a match in its routing table; if there is not match the router will drop the frame. However the router finds an entry in its table to (154.63.2.1) the frame is forwarded out the router serial interface. The router encapsulates the packet and forwards out serial interface in an HDLC frame towards the next router. This will repeat the same steps in each router as along as the routers have a route to that destination it will then eventually be received by the router connected to the web server. This router will send an ARP message that wants to know who is 154.63.2.1? That broadcast message will be received by all devices connected to the 154.63.2.0 network. The web server will respond and send the MAC address to the router and the router will then forward the packet to the web server. That&#39;s the basic understanding of how routers forward traffic, this tutorial only scratched the surface with how routers route along with keeping it simple some things were skipped in this tutorial. If you would like to find more information take a look at Cisco.com which is a great place to get started. Questions or comments are also welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
