<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ipv6 on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/ipv6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ipv6 on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 02:22:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/ipv6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Converting Hexadecimal to Decimal and Binary</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/04/22/converting-hexadecimal-to-decimal-and-binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 02:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/04/22/converting-hexadecimal-to-decimal-and-binary/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The purpose of this post is to reference the CCNA Data Center (640-911) exam. This exam starts the conversation of IPv6 and since IPv6 is hexadecimal this post starts the talk about how we look at a hexadecimal values and learn how to convert them to binary and decimal. If you know subnetting skills then this won’t be that difficult. If you are new then check out The Wonders of Binary post as well as Part 1 and Part 2 of subnetting.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why IPv6?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/08/22/why-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 01:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/08/22/why-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although this protocol has been around since 1996 it has been anticipated that IPv4 would one day be exhausted. In February 2011 the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA) assigned the last /8 address blocks to the Regional Internet Registries so time is getting close but you have heard this warning before right? Let&#39;s go over IPv6 at least just an overview some the features and changes compared to IPv4 because one day it will happen it&#39;s just a matter of when.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World IPv6 Day!!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/08/world-ipv6-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 18:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/08/world-ipv6-day/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IPv6 So what is IPv6 day? Today major companies like Google, Facebook, Yahoo and ISPs (Internet Service Providers) test their IPv6 deployments. Why is this important? Well if you follow IPv4 news you might already know that IPv4 addresses have been exhausted and the need to move to different address space is critical, if new web services are to be deployed. The question is can we run both? Although running two different IP addressing protocols is likely, by &amp;quot;stacking&amp;quot; them that is one reason the Internet Society wanted major sites and ISPs to test out the IPv6 address space.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv4 Meet IPv6</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/03/ipv4-meet-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 13:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/03/ipv4-meet-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IPv4 maybe on its last leg with only a few blocks of IPv4 addresses available, computer estimates say that the IANA address depletion was January 27, 2011. Also the calculations for all central IPv4 pool addresses will be depleted by July 25, 2012.
These are estimates and may change as of writing this post. I&#39;ll be sure to update if needed, but the thing to understand is that IPv4 won&#39;t be available within weeks if not months.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
