<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 16:25:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configure DHCP on a Cisco Router</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/12/configure-dhcp-on-a-cisco-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 16:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/12/configure-dhcp-on-a-cisco-router/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/68573-connect-computer-small.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/68573-connect-computer-small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Data-connect-computer&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In this short tutorial let&#39;s configure a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic_Host_Configuration_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol&#34;&gt;DHCP server&lt;/a&gt; on a Cisco Router. Why would we want to do that? Well configuring a basic DHCP server on a router is a good idea if this is a branch/satellite office or just a small business. There are some pros and cons of configuring DHCP on a Cisco Router so let&#39;s briefly discuss them and then start configuring. Putting DHCP on a router is pretty easy and that&#39;s one advantage of setting up DHCP no need to setup a Linux or Windows server. However this also depends on what type of environment you are running,  if the company has an Active Directory structure that can be a showstopper if you want have DHCP on the router. There can be a problems because while your domain controller controls DNS any PC that gets an address from DHCP that the router is handing out may not be updated in DNS.  (Active Directory likes to have DNS that is current) There have been issues with Active Directory and the best solution is to setup the DHCP service on the Windows server and disable DHCP on the router. That way both DNS and DHCP is automatically added/updated when a new PC joins the network. Along with way more functionality on the server side than the router side, like such as clustering and or load balancing DHCP servers if there is ever need.  Although Cisco routers are great it&#39;s not designed for a clustering load balancing DHCP server. A router&#39;s main job is forwarding and routing data and although routers can have more than one job besides routing this also adds more load to the router if it already has big shoes to fill. ;) So now let&#39;s begin learning how to configure DHCP, listed below is the current running-config on the router called Branch-1 in which we will configure DHCP on. [code]BRANCH-1#show run Building configuration... Current configuration : 1075 bytes ! version 12.3 service timestamps debug datetime msec service timestamps log datetime msec no service password-encryption ! hostname BRANCH-1 ! boot-start-marker boot-end-marker ! ! no network-clock-participate aim 0 no network-clock-participate aim 1 no aaa new-model ip subnet-zero ! ! ip cef ! ! ip ips po max-events 100 no ftp-server write-enable ! ! ! interface FastEthernet0/0 ip address 192.168.40.1 255.255.255.0 duplex auto speed auto ! interface FastEthernet0/1 no ip address shutdown duplex auto speed auto ! ! ip classless no ip http server no ip http secure-server ! ! ! ! control-plane ! ! line con 0 logging synchronous line aux 0 line vty 0 4 login ! scheduler allocate 20000 1000 ! end [/code] This configuration is pretty basic and if &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_computer&#34; title=&#34;Personal computer&#34;&gt;PCs&lt;/a&gt; where connected to FastEthernet 0/0 they would be able to ping the gateway if they where manually setup with the correct &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34; title=&#34;IP address&#34;&gt;IP addresses&lt;/a&gt;. This maybe be ok if you only had a couple of PCs to work with but even then it is pretty simple to set up a DHCP server instead of manually configuring PCs so let&#39;s start configuring it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For this example we are going to be configuring a DHCP pool called  &lt;strong&gt;DHCP-40-POOL.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are also going to be excluding address from this pool which will be &lt;strong&gt;192.168.40.0 - 192.168.40.5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this example we don&#39;t have an internal &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Name_server&#34; title=&#34;Name server&#34;&gt;DNS server&lt;/a&gt; so we will be using one of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendns.com/&#34; title=&#34;OpenDNS&#34;&gt;OpenDNS&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s servers. That IP address is  &lt;strong&gt;208.67.222.222.&lt;/strong&gt; We will also configure a secondary DNS server, that IP address is &lt;strong&gt;8.8.8.8&lt;/strong&gt; (Thanks Google)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally are domain name for this example will be &lt;strong&gt;BRANCH1.CISCOSKILLS.NET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s get connected to Branch-1 and verify you are in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;global configuration mode&lt;/a&gt; and type the following to create a DHCP pool. (This example is using &lt;strong&gt;DHCP-40-POOL)&lt;/strong&gt; [code]BRANCH-1(config)#ip dhcp pool DHCP-40-POOL BRANCH-1(dhcp-config)#[/code] You&#39;ll notice that we are now in the DHCP-Config area. If you type a question mark we will see the available options we can configure while under this mode. [code]BRANCH-1(dhcp-config)#? DHCP pool configuration commands: accounting Send Accounting Start/Stop messages bootfile Boot file name class Specify a DHCP class client-identifier Client identifier client-name Client name default-router Default routers dns-server DNS servers domain-name Domain name exit Exit from DHCP pool configuration mode hardware-address Client hardware address host Client IP address and mask import Programatically importing DHCP option parameters lease Address lease time netbios-name-server NetBIOS (WINS) name servers netbios-node-type NetBIOS node type network Network number and mask next-server Next server in boot process no Negate a command or set its defaults option Raw DHCP options origin Configure the origin of the pool subnet Subnet allocation commands update Dynamic updates utilization Configure various utilization parameters vrf Associate this pool with a VRF [/code] So for this example we first need to type the network that will be using DHCP. (For this tutorial it&#39;s the 192.168.40.0 network so the command would look something like this: [code]BRANCH-1(dhcp-config)#network 192.168.40.0 255.255.255.0[/code] To set the default router for DHCP (This is usually the router&#39;s interface address, PCs would call this their default gateway.) [code]BRANCH-1(dhcp-config)#default-router 192.168.40.1[/code] To set the domain name of this network (This example is using &lt;strong&gt;BRANCH1.CISCOSKILLS.NET&lt;/strong&gt;) [code]BRANCH-1(dhcp-config)#domain-name BRANCH1.CISCOSKILLS.NET[/code] To set DNS servers (You can type more than one in this example I have two DNS servers 208.67.222.222 is the first DNS server followed by 8.8.8.8) [code]BRANCH-1(dhcp-config)#dns-server 208.67.222.222 8.8.8.8[/code] Our last setup is to exclude some address for this example we are going to excluding the first five address in the the 192.168.40.0/24 range. We have to exit out of the DHCP-config mode and go back to the global configuration mode: [code]BRANCH-1(dhcp-config)#exit BRANCH-1(config)#ip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.40.0 192.168.40.5[/code] Let&#39;s do a copy run start to save changes and if we now look at the running-config to verify our DHCP settings it should look something like the example below. [code]BRANCH-1#copy run startup-config Destination filename [startup-config]? Building configuration... [OK] BRANCH-1#show run Building configuration... Current configuration : 1083 bytes ! version 12.3 service timestamps debug datetime msec service timestamps log datetime msec no service password-encryption ! hostname BRANCH-1 ! -- OMITITED-- ! ip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.40.0 192.168.40.5 ! ip dhcp pool DHCP-40-POOL network 192.168.40.0 255.255.255.0 dns-server 208.67.222.222 8.8.8.8 default-router 192.168.40.1 domain-name BRANCH1.CISCOSKILLS.NET ! -- OMITITED--[/code] We should now have DHCP running on our router, if we look at a PC in command prompt and issue the ipconfig /all command all the settings we configured on the router are passing to the PC. Here is some output of the PC that is connected to Branch-1. [code]C:\Windows\system32&amp;gt;ipconfig /all -- OMITITED-- IPv4 Address. . . . . . . . . . . : 192.168.40.6(Preferred) Subnet Mask . . . . . . . . . . . : 255.255.255.0 Lease Obtained. . . . . . . . . . : Sunday, November 25, 2012 11:13:58 AM Lease Expires . . . . . . . . . . : Monday, November 26, 2012 11:13:57 AM Default Gateway . . . . . . . . . : 192.168.40.1 DHCP Server . . . . . . . . . . . : 192.168.40.1 DHCPv6 IAID . . . . . . . . . . . : 234884137 DHCPv6 Client DUID. . . . . . . . : 00-01-00-01-18-21-0E-A6-00-0C-29-22-D2-2 DNS Servers . . . . . . . . . . . : 208.67.222.222 8.8.8.8 NetBIOS over Tcpip. . . . . . . . : Enabled -- OMITITED--[/code] That&#39;s it! I hope this tutorial was helpful, to review we just configured a DHCP server on a Cisco IOS Router! As mentioned there are pros and cons when setting up DHCP on a router instead of a Windows or Linux server and the overall configuration in setting up DHCP is simple. If you noticed there are commands available while in the DHCP mode that we have not even touched and I would encourage you to either search them on the web or try them out in a lab environment. Once again I hope this information is helpful and please comment below if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ioshints.info/2012/10/coping-with-holiday-traffic-secondary.html&#34;&gt;Coping with Holiday Traffic - Secondary DHCP Subnets&lt;/a&gt; (ioshints.info)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://andiwijaya.wordpress.com/2012/11/23/top-10-important-command-prompts-commands/&#34;&gt;Top 10 Important command prompt&#39;s commands&lt;/a&gt; (andiwijaya.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/security/real-world-dns-abuse-finding-common-ground/&#34;&gt;Real World DNS Abuse: Finding Common Ground&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://diecarvi.wordpress.com/2012/11/30/cisco-ios-dhcp-server-tip/&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS DHCP Server tip&lt;/a&gt; (diecarvi.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-02 22:09:38&#34;&gt;Dec 0, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Jr Dev]( &#34;eager@student.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-01 15:29:32&#34;&gt;Dec 6, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome blog. I learned something today. Keep them coming please!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Archive your Configuration | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2013/01/21/archive-your-configuration/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-21 22:52:46&#34;&gt;Jan 1, 2013&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cracking WEP</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/cracking-wep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2011 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/cracking-wep/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BackTrack&#34; title=&#34;BackTrack&#34;&gt;BackTrack&lt;/a&gt; is Linux  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_security&#34; title=&#34;Network security&#34;&gt;network security&lt;/a&gt; audit tool for security professionals. This tool is used for testing and penetrating networks. That being said** This tutorial is for educational use only. This is meant only to teach that WEP is an insecure option, and is recommend to use a harder encryption. Using this tutorial on a network that you do not have permission to access or is not yours, could be illegal! ** This was tested on BackTrack version 4 and the steps outlined in this tutorial were successful. (this tutorial is assuming that you have BackTrack 4 installed and are ready with a shell prompt)  The first thing you want to do is start your wireless interface in most cases this is wlan0 [code]airmon-ng start wlan0[/code] In the output look for the monitor interface in most cases this is mon0   The next thing you want to do is copy down the target AP&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Service_set_%28802.11_network%29&#34; title=&#34;Service set (802.11 network)&#34;&gt;ESSID&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MAC_address&#34; title=&#34;MAC address&#34;&gt;MAC address&lt;/a&gt; of the AP,  also copy down the channel of the target AP.  [code]airodump-ng mon0[/code] There must be a client or clients using the AP if not you can&#39;t crack it. Match the MAC address of the AP to the available clients you have listed.   Next only output what you want (for example I have an AP on channel 8 and that MAC address of the AP is 00:dd:aa:cc:88:33 and it&#39;s out monitor 0) the command would be:       [code]airodump-ng --channel 8 --write output --bssid 00:dd:aa:cc:88:33 mon0[/code] (Open a new shell prompt) The next step is you want to associate your wireless card with the AP(for example I have the AP&#39;s MAC and ESSID (which is test) and my wireless MAC address (which is aa:00:55:bb:DD:FF) the command would look like:       [code]aireplay-ng -1 0 -e test -a 00:dd:aa:cc:88:33 -h aa:00:55:bb:DD:FF[/code]   (Open a new shell prompt) The next step is start the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Packet_injection&#34; title=&#34;Packet injection&#34;&gt;packet injection&lt;/a&gt; (for example you will need the target AP&#39;s MAC address (which is 00:dd:aa:cc:88:33 and my(yours) wireless MAC address (which is 00:55:bb:DD:FF) the command would look like:       [code]aireplay-ng -3 -b 00:dd:aa:cc:88:33 -h 00:55:bb:DD:FF mon0[/code]   (Open a new shell prompt) The final step depends were the outputs are saved and the name of the output (for this example they were on /root and the name of the file was output-01.cap) so the command would look like:     [code]aircrack-ng output-01.cap[/code] Again this depends were the file was saved it could be in a different location. But after that command aircrack will attempt to crack the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wired_Equivalent_Privacy&#34; title=&#34;Wired Equivalent Privacy&#34;&gt;WEP key&lt;/a&gt; it will tell you that it either failed or if it was able to find it. (If it does fail wait for more packets and try again.)   The way aircrack works is that it reads the packet injection file, (this file is continues to update as packets move across the network) aircrack then finds the common key because that key is sent back and forth in the network. Depending on how active the network is aircrack is able to find the key in less than a minute!   Keep in mind when I was setting this up on a test AP I did run into some difficulties, although cracking a WEP key is relatively easy it still took me some time in troubleshooting. I hope this tutorial is helpful, you can find more information at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&lt;/a&gt; Also check my tutorial on &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/&#34; title=&#34;Install BackTrack&#34;&gt;Installing BackTrack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install BackTrack</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/install-backtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 18:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/install-backtrack/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp3/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is a full install of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34; title=&#34;BackTrack&#34;&gt;BackTrack&lt;/a&gt; 4 this can be in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_machine&#34; title=&#34;Virtual machine&#34;&gt;virtual machine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi_boot&#34; title=&#34;Multi boot&#34;&gt;dual-boot&lt;/a&gt;, or the main &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating_system&#34; title=&#34;Operating system&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/a&gt;. So you burned the image that you downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&lt;/a&gt;  and are ready to go! If not I would recommend you do that first. BackTrack is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kernel.org/&#34; title=&#34;Linux&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; penetration testing for network security. This is a free tool that IT administrators can use to audit their network.   First put the disk into the tray and restart your computer. This depends on your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BIOS&#34; title=&#34;BIOS&#34;&gt;BIOS setup&lt;/a&gt; but you can either set the boot order or go into a boot menu and select the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compact_Disc&#34; title=&#34;Compact Disc&#34;&gt;CD&lt;/a&gt; tray as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Booting&#34; title=&#34;Booting&#34;&gt;boot device&lt;/a&gt;.  This is the first thing you will see when you boot into BackTrack you can play around with the different options later but select the screen resolution that is close to your screen size.   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/backtrack-1/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/backtrack-1.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrack Main&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Once you select the option you want you will see a loading page, this can take some time so be patient!   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/backtrack-load/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/backtrack-load.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrackLoad&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Once backtrack is done loading then you can start from there and have fun with command-line but if your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Command-line_interface&#34; title=&#34;Command-line interface&#34;&gt;CLI&lt;/a&gt; skills are a little rusty then you can go into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface&#34; title=&#34;Graphical user interface&#34;&gt;GUI&lt;/a&gt; by typing &lt;em&gt;startx&lt;/em&gt; and hit enter. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/backtrack-loadst/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/backtrack-loadst.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrack loadst&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; From here you can run BackTrack now (it’s called a Live CD) &lt;em&gt;this could be useful if you just want to look at it and play around with settings that you have no idea what they are or do. That why if you mess something up you can always restart and go back into it without it saving anything!&lt;/em&gt; But let’s install this thing! Click on the Install.sh icon.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/install-shell/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/install-shell.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;install shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  This next window is the installer, it is pretty simple to understand, you want to select your location that is in the same time-zone as you.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp1/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp1.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Install Page 1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  This next window is the keyboard layout, Usually USA works for me. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp2/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp2.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;install page 2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  This next page is the partition manager thing, from here you can dual-boot if you have another OS. (You want to be careful if you do have another OS on the hardrive because you can wipe your other OS from here) For this example I am taking the whole drive.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp3.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;install page 3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  The next page gives you a review before you start installing BackTrack this is also a good time to make sure everything is set up properly before you install BackTrack &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp4/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp4.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;installpage 4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  After you click install the installer will start installing!! (amazing! right!) Here you can watch the bar go across the screen or do something productive in this timeframe it takes about 20 to 30 minutes but this also depends on the hardware you have.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp5/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp5.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;installpage 5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  After it finishes it gives you two options, stay on the live CD or reboot to start BackTrack. &lt;em&gt;(Hint: reboot)&lt;/em&gt;   Once the machine is rebooting it will take some time so be patient as it is loading. Once it is ready it will ask you for your username and password. The username is &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt; and the password is &lt;em&gt;toor .&lt;/em&gt; Once you type that you&#39;re in CLI again, if you want to go to the GUI just type &lt;em&gt;startx&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btstart/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btstart.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrack start&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   Once you type &lt;em&gt;startx&lt;/em&gt; it will load the GUI and you now have a full install of BackTrack! From here you can go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to audit your network.&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btstartdesk/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btstartdesk.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrackdesk&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I hope this tutorial was helpful&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding CBAC</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/understanding-cbac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/understanding-cbac/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Although using hardware firewalls are an excellent step forward when securing your network. They can cost money and are not cheap to set up and configure. Using CBAC is built-into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/en/US/products/ps6537/products_ios_sub_category_home.html&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; router and helps filter those unwanted protocols that are in your network. When setting up routers as firewalls you have some choices like using CBAC the &amp;quot;Classic&amp;quot; firewall, or zone based policy (ZBF). Today we will talk about CBAC and how to understand the core components of what make &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context-based_access_control&#34; title=&#34;Context-based access control&#34;&gt;CBAC&lt;/a&gt; possible. CBAC stands for Content-Base-&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control&#34; title=&#34;Access control&#34;&gt;Access-Control&lt;/a&gt; and uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control_list&#34; title=&#34;Access control list&#34;&gt;ACLs&lt;/a&gt;. (Access Control Lists) Unlike the established TCP session and reflexive ACLs CBAC has several advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitors TCP connections, (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transmission_Control_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Transmission Control Protocol&#34;&gt;Three-way handshake&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintains &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_Datagram_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;User Datagram Protocol&#34;&gt;UDP&lt;/a&gt; session information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracks TCP sequence numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspects DNS queries and replies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inspection&#34; title=&#34;Inspection&#34;&gt;Inspect&lt;/a&gt; common &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Control_Message_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Control Message Protocol&#34;&gt;ICMP&lt;/a&gt; messages types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports applications that rely on multiple connections (FTP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspects embedded address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspects &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Application Layer&#34;&gt;Application Layer&lt;/a&gt; information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACLs only look at the network layer and sometimes the transport layer. CBAC is application aware, meaning CBAC is a stateful firewall which keeps track of the state of network connections such as TCP streams, and UDP communication travelling across it. The firewall is programmed to distinguish legitimate packets for different types of connections. Only packets matching a known connection state will be allowed by the firewall; others will be rejected. Because CBAC only matches packets (TCP, UDP and other protocols) it was specified to look at, it will then depend on the ACL if that packet is allowed access or denied. CBAC creates openings in ACLs at the interfaces that inspect the traffic by adding a temporary ACL entry for a specific session. The openings are created when the internal network starts a session with the outside network that would normally be denied. The traffic is only allowed back through the firewall if it is part of the same session and has the correct properties that CBAC is looking for. For example let&#39;s say a user starts an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Session_management&#34; title=&#34;Session management&#34;&gt;http session&lt;/a&gt; in the protected network and the packet moves to the outside or unprotected network. CBAC is configured to inspect http traffic and there is an ACL on the inbound (outside interface) blocking http traffic from the unprotected network to the protected network. So the packet is allowed access to the unprotected network because the ACL is on the inbound interface and not the outbound interface. So the ACL does not look at the packet, CBAC however looks at the packet and in the inspection rules the packet is allowed access to the unprotected network, CBAC adds an entry in its state table. Because a new entry is added a dynamic ACL is created on the external interface to the protected network. This dynamic ACL will allow http traffic back into the protected network. This opening is only active it the session is open, once the session closes the ACL is removed. Once removed any traffic that starts from the unprotected network will be denied access to the protected network. This depends on the ACL which checks inbound connections from the unprotected network.&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/cbac-firewall-config/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/cbac-firewall-config.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;CBAC Firewall&#34; title=&#34;CBAC Firewall-config&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/cbac-firewall-config.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; To configure CBAC there are four steps to set up CBAC efficiently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick an interface of where you want CBAC to be inspecting; this depends on the flow of your network and the amount of interfaces you have installed on your router. (DMZ, Web server, E-mail servers, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure IP ACLs at the interface. The network technician must define what type of traffic is allowed and will not be inspected by CBAC and which traffic is blocked and will be inspected by CBAC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define inspection rules. The network technician should specify each desired application layer to inspect along with generic TCP, ICMP and or UDP fields. Inspection rules are configured by statements each listing a protocol and specifying the inspection rule name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally apply the inspection rule to an interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBAC is considered the &amp;quot;classic&amp;quot; firewall compared to zone based, it is relatively simple to configure and understand. However unlike zone based CBAC can get complex when multiple CBAC configurations on a router exists. Remember CBAC also uses ACLs if configured and implemented poorly these ACLs can block traffic even when CBAC allows them. I hope this tutorial was helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistency on Linux</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/persistency-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 16:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/persistency-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Many popular Linux OS can be installed on USB, and have persistency (Data and or settings) saved on that USB. So in the end you have a “almost installed” OS on your USB. This tutorial focuses on BackTrack but you can put other Linux OS like, Ubuntu, Fedora, Debian, Open SUSE, and many more can be used as well. First and the easiest way I found was running a program called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxliveusb.com/&#34;&gt;Linux Live USB Creator&lt;/a&gt;. This program can put together a LiveUSB (in which data cannot be saved, like a Live CD) or also put persistency on (which allows you to save file and settings). The only thing you can’t usually do with a persistency system is update system settings, and sometimes installing additional software. This program can also put up a portable Virtual Box so you don’t have to restart your system to use it. So the first thing to do is to download and install Linux Live USB Creator, follow the simple setup information to install Linux Live After you install Linux Live you can start-up the program and choose your USB drive.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/04/persistency-on-linux/lili-usb/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/lili-usb.png?w=90&#34; alt=&#34;Linux Live USB Program&#34; title=&#34;Linux Live USB Program&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Next choose the source of the .iso file, you can even download the .iso from here as well. For this example I was trying out BackTrack 4, So I selected backtrack. (Many other Linux OS are available)   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/04/persistency-on-linux/source/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/source.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;ISO Source File&#34; title=&#34;Source&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  The next one is persistency this allows you to actually save data on the USB. You can then boot that USB from multiple machines and you settings and files should be there. Select how much space you want for persistency. If you set it to zero it will be a LiveUSB. &lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/persistence.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Persistence Level&#34; title=&#34;Persistence&#34;&gt;Next are options and are totally up to you, (what I did was select every one of them when I installed BackTrack4)   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/04/persistency-on-linux/options/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/options.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Options&#34; title=&#34;Options&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Then after all the selections have been made hit that lightning bolt!   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/04/persistency-on-linux/startnow/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/startnow.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;To Start Click the Lighting Bolt&#34; title=&#34;Start Now&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Once completed you can either start the OS within Windows from the portal VM, or reboot and select you USB drive to boot and you now should have a persistent system up and running.   (For BackTrack4 I have found that you need to select “Start Persistent Live CD” in order for the persistent mode to start and save data.)   You can find more information on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxliveusb.com/&#34;&gt;Linux Live USB Creator’s&lt;/a&gt; website. I hope this tutorial was helpful&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 10.10 Install</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/ubuntu-10.10-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 16:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/ubuntu-10.10-install/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Well a while back I went ahead and downloaded the RC version of Ubuntu 10.10 and played around with it. Yes that&#39;s right the RC version. Now there is a final version of 10.10 which was released on the 10th of October 2010. I saw that very little has changed between the RC and the final version when installing. I know this is a little late going and doing a step by step install of Ubuntu, but never seems to get old. So I took some screen shots of the install and the desktop when finished. So let’s get installing!   When you first put the disk in along with booting from the disk you are welcomed at the welcome screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_welcome/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_welcome.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Welcome Page&#34; title=&#34;Welcome Page&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There you can select your language and choose if you want to run it from the disk or install it on the hardrive. (I like how Ubuntu and other Linux software let users run the operating system from the disk that&#39;s always a helpful thing when you may have problems with your other OS) The next page if you selected install is in overview of the system requirements. This tells you that everything should go or not go as planned. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_installp1/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_installp1.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Install Page 1&#34; title=&#34;Install Page (1)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_installp2/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_installp2.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Install Page 2&#34; title=&#34;Install Page (2)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; When you click forward you then have an option to use the whole hardrive or set up a partition. For this step-by step guide I just selected the whole disk, it all depends if you have another OS on your computer or if you want to wipe your drive completely.&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_installp3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_installp3.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Install Page 3&#34; title=&#34;Install Page (3)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_installp3.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_installp3.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The next step is allocating the drive. Again this all depends on your current setup (I used the whole disk for this demo) Once you have the drives set up select install now. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_installp4/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_installp4.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Ubuntu Install Page 4&#34; title=&#34;Install Page (4)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_installp5/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_installp5.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Install Page 5&#34; title=&#34;Install Page (5)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Throughout the install process it will ask you for your current location/time format. It also asks your keyboard layout, for this demo I selected USA. (This all depends on if you have a different keyboard usually USA is the default) The next screen will want your login information this is based on how you want Ubuntu to login and the user to login as. You can select to login automatically and even encrypt your home folder for security. Type a user name (mine is Ryan) and a password. (For this demo notice how my password is weak, I would recommend using a stronger password)  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_installp6/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_installp6.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Ubuntu Install Page 6&#34; title=&#34;Install Page (6)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Also when Ubuntu installs you can click on the arrows to learn more about it while you are waiting for it to install. On the virtual PC it took about 30 minutes to install but remember this depends on hardware.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_installp7/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_installp7.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Install Page 7&#34; title=&#34;Install Page (7)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_installp7.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Once Ubuntu installs you have to restart the computer a message like this will pop up when the install is finished.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_intallp8/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_intallp8.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Install Page 8&#34; title=&#34;Install Page (8)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_intallp8.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Once restarted this is the login screen for Ubuntu. (This depends on if you selected requiring Ubuntu to show the login screen.)&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_login/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_login.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Ubuntu Login Page&#34; title=&#34;Ubuntu 10.10 Login Page&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is the Ubuntu 10.10 desktop after a clean install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_main_desktop/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_main_desktop.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Ubuntu 10.10 Main Desktop&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_main_desktop.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Update Manger provides updates for Ubuntu. (Notice how many updates I have over 150 of them! Some of them are probably not important...I hope! ) &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_update/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_update.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Ubuntu Update&#34; title=&#34;Ubuntu Update &#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_update.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This is Ubuntu&#39;s Software Center, you will find free and some paid software to download and install! There is a lot of software for just about anything out there.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_softwarecenter/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_softwarecenter.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Ubuntu Software Center&#34; title=&#34;Ubuntu 10.10 Software Center&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_softwarecenter.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This is Ubuntu&#39;s folder view or explorer window, nice and neat, organized and pretty simple to understand. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/ubuntu-10-10-install/preview_folderexplorer_view/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_folderexplorer_view.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Ubuntu (Explorer View)&#34; title=&#34;Ubuntu 10.10 folder (explorer_view)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/preview_folderexplorer_view.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Overall the Ubuntu&#39;s 10.10 version is pretty solid. Ubuntu has always had apps ready to go when it starts. Like e-mail and chat programs that work with MSN, Gmail, Yahoo and other e-mail services. Of course Ubuntu has browsers Firefox is included and Google Chrome is also supported along with flash. When using open source operating systems why not use open source office software? By using Open Office you can create professional documents and presentations and it&#39;s all included with Ubuntu. Ubuntu One which started in 9.04 is a cloud service that can help you sync your computers all together. You can buy music and have it on all computers and mobile phones that you own. Sharing files between them is also simple. Ubuntu is social friendly operating system it can access your Facebook, Twitter and Identi accounts all from one application on your computer. Ubuntu is pretty fast within 10 seconds I was at the login screen, within 5 seconds I was at my desktop and ready to go! Ubuntu has always been good to older computer platforms, they do however want Ubuntu on newer machines because of the added support of newer hardware. Games are important when you have time to burn and Ubuntu has hundreds of them. With Ubuntu creating photos and editing is easy with included software like Shotwell, Flickr, and GIMP. Support for camera and phones are legendary, all without drivers. These are some of the many features Ubuntu has, and has had for a while. Well that’s my take on the newer version of Ubuntu and looking at the release cycle the next version of Ubuntu 11.04 (Natty Narwhal) which is expected to be released April 28th 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
