<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intrusion Detection System on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/intrusion-detection-system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intrusion Detection System on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 17:30:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/intrusion-detection-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configure IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) via SDM</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/04/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 17:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/04/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Awhile back I talked about the differences between IPS and IDS. (See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs-ips/&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IDS vs. IPS&#34;&gt;Cisco IDS vs. IPS&lt;/a&gt; ) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure an IPS (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intrusion_prevention_system&#34; title=&#34;Intrusion prevention system&#34;&gt;Intrusion Prevention System&lt;/a&gt;) on a router using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface&#34; title=&#34;Graphical user interface&#34;&gt;GUI&lt;/a&gt; for Cisco &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;routers&lt;/a&gt; this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. ( See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/14/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34; title=&#34;Configure Cisco SDM&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM&lt;/a&gt;) Let&#39;s start configuring an IPS with SDM! This tutorial is assuming that the configurations to set up Cisco SDM have already been completed. For this tutorial all we want to focus on is configuring the IPS. Since this using Cisco SDM the IPS wizard is pretty easy to understand. Before we get started I like to have the Cisco SDM preview the commands before I deliver them to the router. To do that at the top of the menu bar click &lt;em&gt;Edit&lt;/em&gt; and select &lt;em&gt;Preferences&lt;/em&gt; a new window will appear (Like below) and verify that the &lt;em&gt;Preview commands before delivering to the router&lt;/em&gt; is checked.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/preview_commandse/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/preview_commandse.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM Preferences&#34; title=&#34;Preview_Commands&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Before we even jump into the IPS wizard we must verify that we have the IOS IPS signature package file and the public crypto key. If you don&#39;t have them you then must have a CCO account with Cisco to download them. Make sure that these files are available on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_computer&#34; title=&#34;Personal computer&#34;&gt;PC&lt;/a&gt; along with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trivial_File_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Trivial File Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;TFTP&lt;/a&gt; server installed and running. Put or verify that the IOS IPS signature file is in the default TFTP folder (IOS-Sxxx-CLI.pkg) Remember that the X values will vary depending on the file that was download from Cisco. Also verify that the realm-cisco.pub.key.txt file is available on the computer and note its location. This file is the public key that it used by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; IPS. Once Cisco SDM is opened click the configure button at the top of SDM screen and select &lt;em&gt;Intrusion Prevention&lt;/em&gt; on the left hand side under &lt;strong&gt;Tasks&lt;/strong&gt;. Click or verify that the &lt;em&gt;Create IPS&lt;/em&gt; tab is selected and select the &lt;em&gt;Launch IPS Rule Wizard&lt;/em&gt; button. If prompted for &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_Device_Event_Exchange&#34; title=&#34;Security Device Event Exchange&#34;&gt;SDEE&lt;/a&gt; click ok. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_maine/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_maine.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Main Screen&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Main&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  A window will show, the IPS Welcome Screen which gives the objectives the wizard will go over in helping us create an IPS system. Click Next.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_welcomee/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_welcomee.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizared Welcome Page&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Welcome&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The next screen (IPS Interface) will want us to select which interface(s) will have the IPS rules, select either inbound or outbound. (For this tutorial both &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_Ethernet&#34; title=&#34;Fast Ethernet&#34;&gt;Fast-Ethernet&lt;/a&gt; 0/0&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Serial 0/0&lt;/em&gt; will have the IPS rules inbound.) Click Next.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_interfacese/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_interfacese.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Interfaces&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Interfaces&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The next screen (Signature File and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public-key_cryptography&#34; title=&#34;Public-key cryptography&#34;&gt;Public Key&lt;/a&gt;) wants to know the following information, the location of the signature file and the public key.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_sig_pub_key/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_sig_pub_key.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Signature Public Key&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Sig_Pub_Key&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Focusing on the signature file first you want to specify the location where the signature file is. Click on the three dots button.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_sigfilee/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_sigfilee.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Signature File&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_SigFile&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Another window will open (Specify Signature File) if the signature file is already on the routers flash memory select the first radio button, if the signature file is by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Locator&#34; title=&#34;Uniform Resource Locator&#34;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; select the correct protocol and address, you can also specify the signature file on the PC. (For this tutorial we are using the TFTP server and are specifying the signature file by URL, once the location of the file has been selected click OK. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_sigfile_spe/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_sigfile_spe.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Signature File Location&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_SigFile_SP&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Now let&#39;s focus on the Public Key, in the name of the public key type realm-cisco.pub or relam-cisco.pub signature. Find and open the realm-cisco.pub.key.txt file and copy (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Control-C&#34; title=&#34;Control-C&#34;&gt;Ctrl-C&lt;/a&gt;) the text that is between the phrase key-string and the word quit. Paste the text (key) in the key field in the Configure Key section. Click Next. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_public_keye/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_public_keye.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Public Key&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Public_Key&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The next section (Config Location and Category) wants you to specify where you want the IPS configuration files click on the three dots and choose your location. (For this tutorial we are using flash to store the IPS configuration) Towards the bottom of the screen the wizard wants to choose a signature category for the router. (For this tutorial we are choosing the advanced option.) Click Next. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_config_locatione/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_config_locatione.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Config Location&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Config_Location&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The next section is the summary window for the IPS configuration, here you can look over the summary to verify the configuration. Click Finish. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_summarye/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_summarye.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Summary&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Summary&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; If you&#39;ve selected the option to preview commands before delivering them to the router, a final window will appear. In this window you can see the actual commands the SDM program will attempt to deliver. You have the option to save the running-configuration to the startup-configuration after the commands complete. You also have the option to save the configuration as a file and finally you can deliver them to the router. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_delivere/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_delivere.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Deliver&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Deliver&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; That&#39;s it! believe it or not that&#39;s the SDM configuration of IOS IPS you can get more information at Cisco&#39;s website about SDM and the configuration settings. Like always I hope this tutorial was informative and if you have a suggestion on the next topic that relates to ICND1 or ICND2 and even some CCNA Security comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/smallbusiness/help-keep-company-data-safe-on-employees-personal-devices-2/&#34;&gt;Help Keep Company Data Safe on Employees&#39; Personal Devices&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcworld.com/article/225387/digital_threats_jumped_in_2010.html&#34;&gt;Digital Threats Jumped in 2010&lt;/a&gt; (pcworld.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/security/defending-against-sql-injection-attacks-using-cisco-asa-ips-and-ios-firewall-cisco-tac-security-podcast/&#34;&gt;Defending against SQL Injection attacks using Cisco ASA, IPS, and IOS Firewall - Cisco TAC Security Podcast&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.forbes.com/andygreenberg/2011/04/12/study-finds-firewalls-from-cisco-fortinet-others-vulnerable-to-old-attack/&#34;&gt;Study Finds Firewalls From Cisco, Fortinet, Others Vulnerable To Old Attack&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.forbes.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IDS vs. IPS</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/03/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 15:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/03/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;There are tons of network attacks out there. Using a firewall helps but does look for signature based attacks. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control_list&#34; title=&#34;Access control list&#34;&gt;Access Control Lists&lt;/a&gt; are like firewalls and only look at the protocols like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypertext_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Hypertext Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;File Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;FTP&lt;/a&gt; POP, etc. Cisco has developed some tools that will help &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_administrator&#34; title=&#34;Network administrator&#34;&gt;network administrators&lt;/a&gt; combat the issue; IDS, (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intrusion_detection_system&#34; title=&#34;Intrusion detection system&#34;&gt;Intrusion Detection System&lt;/a&gt;) and IPS. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intrusion_prevention_system&#34; title=&#34;Intrusion prevention system&#34;&gt;Intrusion Prevention System&lt;/a&gt;) Let&#39;s go into IDS first, Cisco IDS is a physical device and is like an alarm system it will alert you when an attack happens but that&#39;s it, the system won&#39;t block the connection. The IDS system is deployed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Promiscuous_mode&#34; title=&#34;Promiscuous mode&#34;&gt;promiscuous mode&lt;/a&gt; meaning the sensor is placed where it can hear all the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_traffic_control&#34; title=&#34;Network traffic control&#34;&gt;network traffic&lt;/a&gt; but is not in direct connect with the network making it an advantage when using an IDS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No network impact, latency, or jitters etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No network impact if there is a sensor failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No network impact if there is a sensor overloaded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However the IDS does have some disadvantages compared to IPS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If packets trigger an alarm that&#39;s all it does is tell us that an attack is happening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correct tuning is required for valid and invalid packets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company must have a well thought-out security policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks that are vulnerable must have evasion techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what can IPS do that IDS can&#39;t? Well the IPS system can alert just like IDS but the IPS system can also block the attack. Remember that the IDS system can only alert. IPS works inline with the network it is a physical device just like IDS but is directly connected to the network. So what are the advantages to IPS compared to IDS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stops packets that trigger an alert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can use stream normalization techniques (since the IPS sensor is inline with the traffic it can reduce many network attacks that exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the IDS the IPS does have disadvantage when compared to IDS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the sensor is connected directly (inline) with the network it might affect network traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the sensor is overloaded that will also impact the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A company must have a thought-out security policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There can be some latency, jitter etc. with the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why use IPS instead of IDS? Well IDS is an older technology and like mentioned before IDS only alerts you that an attack is happening, it logs the attack and that&#39;s it. Network attacks can happen fast and some of them only need a small amount of time to complete the attack. So once a network technician gets into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Networking_hardware&#34; title=&#34;Networking hardware&#34;&gt;network equipment&lt;/a&gt; the attacker could be long gone and got what he/she needed. Sure you can now fix the problem but it might be little too late. IPS is able to load signature files this is like the definitions on your anti-virus software which it looks for patterns based on the attack. Which IPS can take that same style and block those attacks based on the security policies you implement, along with alerting you of what happened. That&#39;s my brief rundown of what these two technologies do  there is a lot more information you will be able to find on the web. But both have their places in the networking environment and it all depends on the money the company wants to spend to keep their networks secure. You can find more information at Cisco.com and or other places, I hope this information was informative.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
