<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RADIUS on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/radius/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RADIUS on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 12:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/radius/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RBAC Radius with Microsoft NPS 2012 R2</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/04/12/rbac-radius-with-microsoft-nps-2012-r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/04/12/rbac-radius-with-microsoft-nps-2012-r2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this configuration I&#39;m at looking at using Microsoft NPS 2012 R2 as radius server and I’m going to skip the installation of NPS because it really is just a next, next, finish installation. In this demo I already have this NPS system connected to a Windows domain, my goal is to create role based access on Cisco IOS routers while using radius to login. I’ll have a couple for active directory accounts each them will represent different types of allowed access to these IOS routers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding AAA</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/29/understanding-aaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/29/understanding-aaa/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            User The wonderful AAA which in the Cisco world means, Authentication, Authorization, and Accounting but what does that really mean? In today&#39;s post that&#39;s what we are going to be talking about. What is AAA and what are the benefits of using it along with what is it? The first &amp;quot;A&amp;quot; of AAA is Authentication which provides the method of identifying users, including login and password dialog, challenge and response, messaging support, and, depending on the security protocol you select, encryption.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TACACS Plus and RADIUS</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/10/tacacs-plus-and-radius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 15:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/10/tacacs-plus-and-radius/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TACACS+ and RADIUS are both used to control access to network resources, but both of these protocols are different in how they operate depending how you want to secure your network. These protocols need to have (AAA) authentication, authorization, and accounting setup on the routers before you can set up these access server protocols. First let&#39;s get some information on why we would need this type of access server protocol setup.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
