<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Static Routes on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/static-routes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Static Routes on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:15:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/static-routes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configure Static Routing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Plugging Cisco &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;routers&lt;/a&gt; together and hoping they work out of the box is not something you should hope for. A router can learn about networks in two ways, manually from configured static routers which we will talk about today and dynamic &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Routing&#34; title=&#34;Routing&#34;&gt;routing&lt;/a&gt; protocols which will talk about on Wednesday. Let&#39;s get started! Static routes are not that uncommon they at first need some attention to get set up but after it is working nothing needs to change. A good example of using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Static_routing&#34; title=&#34;Static routing&#34;&gt;static route&lt;/a&gt; is with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stub_network&#34; title=&#34;Stub network&#34;&gt;stub network&lt;/a&gt;. A stub network is only accessed by a single router and no other routes are configured so there is only one path the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_traffic_measurement&#34; title=&#34;Network traffic measurement&#34;&gt;network traffic&lt;/a&gt; can take. Notice the picture below and how any traffic going towards the network cloud from the 192.168.1.0 network will always pass the 172.16.5.0 network. Why waste putting a routing protocol here?) &lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/static_default_route.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Stub Network&#34;&gt;In order to configure a static route you must be in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;global configuration mode&lt;/a&gt;, the ip route command complete &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntax&#34; title=&#34;Syntax&#34;&gt;syntax&lt;/a&gt; is the following: &lt;strong&gt;ip route&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;prefix mask&lt;/em&gt; {&lt;em&gt;ip-address&lt;/em&gt;} | &lt;em&gt;interface-type interface-number&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;em&gt;ip-address&lt;/em&gt;]} [&lt;strong&gt;dhcp&lt;/strong&gt;] [&lt;em&gt;distance&lt;/em&gt;] [&lt;strong&gt;name&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;next-hop-name&lt;/em&gt;] [&lt;strong&gt;permanent&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;track&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt;] [&lt;strong&gt;tag&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;tag&lt;/em&gt;] For the CCENT/CCNA the complete syntax is not relevant, let&#39;s use a simpler version of the ip route syntax: &lt;strong&gt;ip route&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;network-address&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subnetwork&#34; title=&#34;Subnetwork&#34;&gt;subnet-mask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; {&lt;em&gt;ip address&lt;/em&gt; | &lt;em&gt;exit interface&lt;/em&gt;} The &lt;em&gt;network address&lt;/em&gt; is the destination network or the remote address that will be added in the routing table. (For the complete syntax this follows on the prefix parameter) The &lt;em&gt;subnet mask&lt;/em&gt; is the subnet mask of the remote network that will be added in the routing table. (For the complete syntax this follows on the mask parameter) One or both of the following commands must be configured: The &lt;em&gt;ip-address&lt;/em&gt; in the syntax is usually called the next-hop router&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34; title=&#34;IP address&#34;&gt;IP address&lt;/a&gt; The &lt;em&gt;exit-interface&lt;/em&gt; is the outgoing interface that would be used in forwarding the packets io the destination network (For the complete syntax this follows on the &lt;strong&gt;interface-type&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;interface-number&lt;/em&gt; parameter) Looking at the picture above we need to have a static route on R2, we can do these in two ways the first example is using the next hop IP address. (For this example the next hop IP address is 172.16.5.1 R1&#39;s serial 0/0/0 interface. The next example is using the exit interface out of R2. [code]R2(config)#ip route 192.168.1.0 255.255.255.0 172.16.5.1[/code]   [code]R2(config)#ip route 192.168.1.0 255.255.255.0 serial 0/0/1[/code] The last thing we need to do in order for this stub network to work is put a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Default_route&#34; title=&#34;Default route&#34;&gt;default route&lt;/a&gt; on R1 because R2 is going to the cloud the (internet or network) any traffic like a web request going to the internet needs to be forwarded to R2. A default route is a route that will match every IP address. Remember that a router does not have every single possible route on the internet or network usually these can be summary routes and default routes. Like on R2 we can do this in two ways, the first example is using the next hop IP address. (For this example the next hop IP address is 172.16.5.2 R2&#39;s serial 0/0/1 interface. The next example is using the exit interface out of R1. [code]R1(config)#ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 172.16.5.2[/code]   [code]R1(config)#ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 serial 0/0/0[/code] That&#39;s my tutorial for configuring static routes. Static routes do need some overhead but once you get them working you don&#39;t need to even touch it again. You can find more information at Cisco.com and the Cisco Learning Network. Like always I hope this information/tutorial was informative if you have any ideas on the next topic I should cover in the ICND1 or ICND2 area let me know by commenting below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://joernfranz.net/2011/01/12/configuring-static-dynamic-ip-address-under-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;Configuring static / dynamic IP address under Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; (joernfranz.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/static-ip-address-advantages-disadvantages/&#34;&gt;What Is A Static IP Address, How Do I Get One &amp;amp; Its Advantages / Disadvantages&lt;/a&gt; (makeuseof.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brighthub.com/internet/web-development/articles/113397.aspx&#34;&gt;How to Find Your IP Address&lt;/a&gt; (brighthub.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/&#34;&gt;Configure a Site-to-Site VPN via SDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ghacks.net/2011/04/29/why-your-home-router-is-192-168-1-1/&#34;&gt;Why Your Home Router is 192.168.1.1&lt;/a&gt; (ghacks.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Dynamic Routing Protocols | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-05-04 11:07:03&#34;&gt;May 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
