<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CCNA Data Center on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/ccna-data-center/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CCNA Data Center on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 01:55:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/ccna-data-center/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Passed the 640-911 DCICN</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/05/14/passed-the-640-911-dcicn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 01:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/05/14/passed-the-640-911-dcicn/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Cisco started this exam back in 2012 and I have thought/semi-studied about this test for about over a year now, just did not feel comfy about it until recently. I took the test last week and passed, however there were some questions on the exam I noticed that weren&#39;t on the exam blueprint so that kind of surprised me. I was happy to still be able to pass the exam but I was caught off guard. So with that I’ll let you know what I used to study and what areas I think might help so you won&#39;t be as &amp;quot;surprised&amp;quot; as I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall the exam did a good job of testing on the NX-OS software and the overall basic networking fundamentals (ICND1 material with touch of Nexus) which is what this test is supposed to be about. However there are questions that surprised me and was not ready because of the lack of information about the test. When I started studying for this exam I read the exam blueprint for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/community/certifications/ccna_data_center/dcicn/exam-topics&#34;&gt;640-911&lt;/a&gt; to get an idea of what to expect but I feel that some things are missing from that blueprint. What also is interesting is of all the material I read and watched there was no mention of it. So here are some areas that I think you should look at before you take the exam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know the models of all the Nexus switches like the 2000, 3000, 5000, 6000, 7000, and 9000 portfolios. Know the basics of what each offers and their limitations. It’s also helpful to know what the popular type of connections to use between servers and these switches. (&lt;strong&gt;Read the data sheets&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/switches/data-center-switches/index.html#~products-services&#34;&gt;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/switches/data-center-switches/index.html#~products-services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at buying the CCNA Data Center 640-916 Official Cert Guide, or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Center-Official-Guide-Library-Certification/dp/1587205688/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1431488432&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=ccna+data+center&#34;&gt;Cert Library&lt;/a&gt; which includes the 640-911 and 640-916 books because in chapter two of the 640-916 book it talks about the hardware of Nexus switches which is very valuable considering some this is on the 640-911 exam. I noticed this after the fact!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The material I have read/watched: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Center-DCICN-640-911-Official-Guide/dp/1587204541/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1431488432&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=ccna+data+center&#34;&gt;CCNA Data DCICT 640-911 Offical Cert Guide&lt;/a&gt; - Odom &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbtnuggets.com&#34;&gt;CBT Nuggets&lt;/a&gt; - Anthony Sequeira &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Data-Center-Introducing-Networking/dp/1118661265/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1431487215&amp;amp;sr=8-4&amp;amp;keywords=ccna+data+center&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center - Introducing Cisco Data Center Networking Study Guide&lt;/a&gt; - Todd Lammle &lt;a href=&#34;https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/groups/ccna-data-center-study-group&#34;&gt;Cisco Learning Network&lt;/a&gt; (CCNA Data Center)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this information is helpful and good luck on this exam you’ve been warned :P&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Hexadecimal to Decimal and Binary</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/04/22/converting-hexadecimal-to-decimal-and-binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 02:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/04/22/converting-hexadecimal-to-decimal-and-binary/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;The purpose of this post is to reference the CCNA Data Center (640-911) exam. This exam starts the conversation of IPv6 and since IPv6 is hexadecimal this post starts the talk about how we look at a hexadecimal values and learn how to convert them to binary and decimal. If you know subnetting skills then this won’t be that difficult. If you are new then check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/15/the-wonders-of-binary/&#34; title=&#34;The Wonders of Binary&#34;&gt;The Wonders of Binary&lt;/a&gt; post as well as &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/&#34; title=&#34;Part 1 – The Joys of Subnetting!&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/&#34; title=&#34;Part 2 – The Joys of Subnetttting – VLSM!&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; of subnetting. Let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jumping right into it if we look at this hexadecimal value 0x56A we know it’s hexadecimal because the “0x” is the prefix for a hexadecimal number so we really don’t need to do anything with the “0x”. Let’s focus on the 56A value. So where do we start? Remember that 0-9 are normal decimal values so &amp;quot;5&amp;quot; actually means &amp;quot;5&amp;quot;. We want to convert these values into binary. Followed by converting them into a decimal value. So what does the value 5 look like in binary? We then move  to the next digit &amp;quot;6&amp;quot; what does that look like in binary? Then the last value is &amp;quot;A&amp;quot;, what does that look like in binary? &lt;em&gt;Hint: A-F would be 10-15 in decimal.&lt;/em&gt; Reference chart below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HEXADECIMAL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DECIMAL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BINARY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0001&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0010&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0011&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0101&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0110&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0111&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1001&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1010&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1011&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1101&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1110&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1111&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking at the value 56A we would want to combine all the single values into one binary string. (Example 5 in binary is: &lt;strong&gt;0101&lt;/strong&gt;, 6 in binary is: &lt;strong&gt;0110&lt;/strong&gt;, A in binary is: &lt;strong&gt;1010&lt;/strong&gt;) Combine these together and the the answer would be: &lt;strong&gt;01010110101&lt;/strong&gt; (You can drop leading zeros) &lt;strong&gt;1010110101&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does that value look like in decimal? Write it out and remember the power of 2s and always start with &amp;quot;1&amp;quot;. The answer comes out as: &lt;strong&gt;1,386.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/images/2015/04/binarye.png&#34; alt=&#34;Add up the 1s&#34;&gt;
Of course you can reverse engineer this if you were given a decimal value and needed to convert it into hexadecimal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example convert the following decimal 187 into hexadecimal. Write out 187 into binary so that answer looks like: &lt;strong&gt;10111011.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/images/2015/04/dec-binary2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You also want to split the binary string into equal parts, so the answer would be: &lt;strong&gt;1011:1011&lt;/strong&gt; comparing the chart or doing this yourself convert this binary into hexadecimal. Since binary strings are the same our hexadecimal is: &lt;strong&gt;BB.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/images/2015/04/dec-to-hex2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it! Understanding how to convert hex to decimal and back starts to get important when IPv6 shows up at the door. Although this is a fundamental level topic that&#39;s exactly why its important to understand it. Just like subnetting, I would use a calculator if you ever find yourself converting these values. It&#39;s always a good idea to double-check your work. However on the exam you don&#39;t have that pleasure so learning it the manual way is this only way. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22pwgy.lhynds1@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;larry hynds&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2015-04-21 20:39:34&#34;&gt;Apr 2, 2015&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this is fantastic information and i truly thank you for this. i am planning to take my eame this summer. if you have any more suggestion dor the exm i would apprechiate it. regards, storm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://ciscoskills.net/ &#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2015-04-21 20:40:57&#34;&gt;Apr 2, 2015&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m glad this is going to help, Good Luck on the exam :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 12 &amp; 13)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/04/19/640-911-chapter-12-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 16:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/04/19/640-911-chapter-12-13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;We are at the last chapters of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Data-Center-Introducing-Networking/dp/1118661265/&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center 640-911 by Todd Lammle&lt;/a&gt;. Chapter 12 talks about redundant switched technologies and chapter 13 talks about security. Just like before I will go over the high-points, so let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 12 Overview&lt;/strong&gt;: In this chapter we get to learn about Spanning Tree Protocol and some history with it. With networks we like multiple ways to a destination however in the layer two area redundancy does not play well and that’s where spanning tree can help us. So know what spanning tree and its purpose. Spanning tree has several terms that are important to remember for the exam, I would look over page 387. For the exam know some show commands for spanning tree, like &lt;strong&gt;show spanning-tree&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;show spanning-tree summary&lt;/strong&gt;. This chapter also talked about the different types of spanning-tree but could not tell if this would be on 640-911 exam as well as port-channels which helps eliminate blocked STP ports. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 13 Overview&lt;/strong&gt;: In the last chapter of 640-911 book we get introduced to &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/07/access-control-lists/&#34; title=&#34;Access Control Lists&#34;&gt;access-control-lists&lt;/a&gt; and the types of access-lists that the NX-OS supports, know the difference as well as configuring a standard access list and extended access list also be sure to understand the implicit deny statement at end of every access-list. I would also know how wildcard masking works, (flip the subnet mask). A couple more things I thought would be important to keep an eye out is understand that once an access-list is created that does not mean its active, make you sure to understand how to apply the ACL on an interface. Finally know your show commands for access-lists, like &lt;strong&gt;show access-list&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;show access-list summary&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;: So thanks for checking out these posts about the 640-911 exam, I hope this give you an idea of what to expect on the exam and good luck, if you decide to take it. Personally I am shooting for May/June timeframe to pass at least the 640-911. I thought this book was helpful but if you went and passed the CCNA or even CCNP it does get a little dry in areas. This exam is introductory but required if you wanted to achieve the CCNA Data Center certification. Remember you need to pass two exams 640-911 and the 640-916 to become CCNA Data Center certified. Check out all the 640-911 exam topics: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/files/2014/01/640-911_dcicn.pdf&#34;&gt;640-911 Exam Topics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little off topic but interesting to note is as of this writing Todd Lammle is the only author that has published a study guide for the CCNA Data Center, a quick check on Amazon shows that Cisco Press is ready to roll out an official certification guide for the 640-911 in the end of August authored by a Wendell Odom, followed by the 640-916 in January of 2015. I’ll end it here, I hope this information is helpful and comment below if you have any questions on these chapters.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 10 &amp; 11)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 01:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Just like before if you have followed, I have gone over the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle and in this post we cover two chapters. Feel free to comment below if you have any questions on either of these two chapters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 10 Overview&lt;/strong&gt;: Chapter 10 starts us back in the book, before we do any configuring and we learn about routing protocols, and remember the difference between static and dynamic routing (name implies it) Also know the default administrate distances of the different routing protocols (starts on page 297). We also got a crash course in distance vector, link-state and hybrid routing protocols. Out of RIP, RIPv2, EIGRP and OSPF where does each protocol belong? Know the differences between RIP and RIPv2 (there is a couple of them) Know what EIGRP does and it available features it offers as well as OSPF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;: This chapter went over the dynamic routing protocols and at a fundamental level but in important one to remember not to just pass the exam but to also go further. There was a lot of good information in Chapter 10 about dynamic protocols. If you have never used/learned about dynamic routing protocols make sure you understand the chapter and go over the review questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 11 Overview&lt;/strong&gt;: Chapter 11 looks at layer two switching technologies, we get to learn about frame tagging or also called VLANs, make sure you understand how 802.1Q works. We also looked into some configuration options like learning how to set up a trunk link, VTP options and SVIs. Know what the type of modes VTP offers, and what is required when setting up VTP what needs to match? With SVIs know how to enable them and what they are used for because it’s not just a management port. (Hint: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/31/configure-router-on-a-stick/&#34; title=&#34;Configure Router on a Stick&#34;&gt;Router on a Stick&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;: We went from Layer 3 in the OSI back to Layer 2, we need to know the difference between VLANs as we start to blur the lines when using Router on a Stick configurations. This chapter covered the basics of VLANs an important step to make sure you understand the fundamentals. Same things goes with this chapter, if you have never used/learned about VLANs, VTP, SVIs make sure to go over the chapter and review questions. Short and sweet, please post any questions if you have any about this chapter, I hope this information is helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 8 &amp; 9)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/03/30/640-911-chapter-8-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 17:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/03/30/640-911-chapter-8-9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Back where we left off, if you have followed I have gone over the  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Data-Center-Introducing-Networking/dp/1118661265/&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle&lt;/a&gt; and in this post we will cover two chapters 8 and 9. Comment below if you have any questions on these two chapters let&#39;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 8 Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; We are actually making some progress, we configure the NX-OS with CLI there is not a GUI that I am aware of although SDN could be kind of in there but for this exam it does not even exist. Remember the ways to connect to the NX-OS for configuration and verification this is the same with IOS devices, Console, Telnet, SSH and Auxiliary. Just like IOS we can erase the entire NX-OS switch to factory settings by using the write erase boot, along with using the same commands available in IOS. (Copy run start, erase start config) In the exam we need to understand and add SVIs, remember to turn on that feature. The NX-OS brings two user roles out of the box without implementing any access-control when logging into the NX-OS you can have network-operators and network-admins, know the difference between these two. Just like IOS learn how to use the help functions available in the NX-OS along with knowing how to create a hostname and finally the know the advantages of using SSH and the requirements to set up SSH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;: This chapter went over how to get started in configuring and setting up the Nexus. It reminded me of on old post I did for IOS about &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/26/basic-router-configuration/&#34; title=&#34;Basic Router Configuration&#34;&gt;Basic Router Configuration&lt;/a&gt;. This chapter just got you close enough to touch the hardware and turn it on but not really run it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 9 Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;  Changing some gears in this chapter we learn about IP Routing we get a crash course in this. This chapters talks about the IP Routing process. How does the packet get from point A get to point B. Look over page 278 carefully to make sure you understand it also be sure to understand the role of the MAC address. I also thought it was interesting of how the routing table looks in NX-OS when comparing it to IOS devices on page 277, I would also study this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;: Chapter 9 had some key areas for the IP routing if you are familiar with the CCNA this would be a good refresh course, chapter 10 will get us familiar with routing protocols. Like always I hope this is helpful, comment below if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 6)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/20/640-911-chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 19:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/20/640-911-chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/640-911-todd-lammle.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/640-911-todd-lammle.jpg?w=118&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Let&#39;s start chapter six of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Data-Center-Introducing-Networking/dp/1118661265/&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle&lt;/a&gt;, feel free to post questions if you have any. Like before I have covered the topics of the each chapter. Last week we learned about the different IP classes and today we get a course in subnetting. Let&#39;s go over what you should know if you want to pass the exam. **Overview: **It seems I have talked subnetting to death on this blog, repetition, repetition, repetition. So known the advantages of subnetting why would you use it along with knowing what IP subnet zero is. You also should be able to take a classful network and break it into smaller networks some math is involved but it&#39;s not rocket science, if you get lost go over it again you&#39;ll start seeing pattern when subnetting. Since we are subnetting, know the purpose of the subnet mask that&#39;s associated with the IP address. Also be sure you can explain what CIDR is and the difference between a classful network. &lt;strong&gt;My thoughts:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have been around with subnetting you can probably glance over this chapter but I would go over the labs that start on page 190. There is also some more information about subnetting on this blog you can find &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/&#34; title=&#34;Part 1 – The Joys of Subnetting!&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/&#34; title=&#34;Part 2 – The Joys of Subnetttting – VLSM!&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;. Also another good site for sharping subneting skills is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.subnettingquestions.com/&#34;&gt;subnettingquestions.com &lt;/a&gt;. Believe it or not we have finished the back story to finally get to what we want to know which is Cisco&#39;s data center switches the NX-OS product line. I have mention this before at the start of the series, if you know the material have a CCNA or just been around routing and switching you could have glanced over these earlier chapters. This exam starts at the beginning and if you want to move into CCNP you must have passed the 640-911 and the 940-916. Let&#39;s continue to see what the 640-911 exam topics have to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 5)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 19:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Last week we covered chapter four which talked about the TCP/IP and the DoD models and what role they cover in networking as we learned that every application like FTP, DNS, DHCP depend on it. Like always post questions if you have any about the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Data-Center-Introducing-Networking/dp/1118661265/&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ll continue to cover  topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. Let&#39;s go over chapter five.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;
I think we knew it was on the way, in this chapter we opened the door to IPv4 addressing. If this is your first time understanding IP addresses go over it carefully, this exam will cover it. Know the ranges of a Class A, B and C networks, where&#39;s the loopback? Also know the private IP class ranges of A, B and C. (RFC1918) Know the difference between broadcasts, unicast, and multicast addresses. We also got introduced into IPv6, know the address format, the short hand way to write an IPv6 address as well as the types of IPv6 addresses. (link-local, unicast, global unicast addresses, and unique local address)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have been around IPv4 addresses you might be good on this chapter, towards the end of the chapter I would look at IPv6, we don&#39;t talk about subnetting yet that&#39;s next week. :) Pretty short chapter this week post questions below if you have any on this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 4)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 18:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Continuing where we left off on Chapter 3 on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Data-Center-Introducing-Networking/dp/1118661265/&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle&lt;/a&gt;. Like before feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter three we discussed about Ethernet Technologies and in chapter four we will learn about the TCP/IP protocol which is fundamentally the protocol that makes the Internet work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;: The chapter started talking about the DoD model and comparing it to the OSI model, remember this and a little history behind it as well as the layers the DoD model shows its relevance with the OSI model. We start talking about applications like Telnet, FTP, SMTP what are these? Know the common applications and their port numbers. The chapter also talked about host-to-host layer protocols like TCP and UDP, know the difference between these two, and some memorization of what the TCP and UDP header looks like. (Which one is unreliable and which one uses acknowledgments and flow control?) We also looked into the Internet layer Protocols, do you know them all and their functions? Also know what the IP header looks like. (What does it include?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Story&lt;/strong&gt;: I wanted to jump in and talk about my personal experience with TCP/IP protocol mainly the ICMP management of it. I was contracted with a company that had a Cisco Phone System and a 2900 router using SiP as well as Internet on top it. They had this time clock system that would send punches over a VPN to a corporate office and it was setup and working for a while until of course it eventually stopped sending time punches. This took about a week to figure out as the VPN was online and you could contact the device from corporate. With a SPAN port I could see traffic hitting the time clock as well as it coming back. The issue was when the 2900 router was setup, it was set to disregard ICMP (For general network security) because of the way the time clock is designed it would use ICMP to decide the acceptable MTU size before sending time punches. Since it never got a reply it would fail on sending time punches, in the end I enabled the router to accept ICMP to fix the issue. Long story short, ICMP is a management protocol for IP and although it can be used against you, it&#39;s a balancing act between security and functionally and in this case the time clock used ICMP legitimately, lesson learned. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts:&lt;/strong&gt; Personally I liked going over this chapter it starts to put some pieces together, I would read it over if you have seen this before just lock down any missing parts. Also post any questions about this chapter below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could be Helpful? &lt;a href=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/files/2014/01/640-911_dcicn.pdf&#34;&gt;640-911 Exam Topics&lt;/a&gt; (PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/25/understanding-tcp/&#34; title=&#34;Understanding TCP&#34;&gt;Understanding TCP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/&#34; title=&#34;Understanding UDP&#34;&gt;Understanding UDP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 3)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/30/640-911-chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 18:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/30/640-911-chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Picking up were we left on off on a series of blog posts that follow the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Data-Center-Introducing-Networking/dp/1118661265/&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter two we discussed about internetworking and in chapter three we will learn about Ethernet technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; 
This chapter goes over what chapter 2 started we get more information on collision domains, broadcast domains, and introductions into CSMA/CD and the familiarity link between half and full-duplex ethernet. We also looked at the sections of a MAC address and what the IEEE is involved with assignment of these address when giving them to manufactures. We learned about how to convert binary to hexadecimal as well as vice versa. We also looked at the Data link layer and the fields associated with it.(Which part of the OSI model is that?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 2 hinted on the cabling standards but we now have a list full of them starting from coaxial cable to single-mode fiber cable. (Which goes further?) We also learned which  type of cable connects to what and how they are terminated. (Like devices use a crossover cable and not a straight-through cable) We finally talked about Data encapsulation and had some good examples at the end of the chapter of how a computer sends information on the network and it looks like more information is in Chapter 9 :) .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts:&lt;/strong&gt; I would read this chapter even if you went through it before there is a lot of information that needs refreshed (at least for me) if you are going to take the exam. Go over the review questions and over the written labs for converting from decimal to binary and from binary to hexadecimal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could be helpful?: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/&#34; title=&#34;Crossover or Straight through?&#34;&gt;Crossover or Straight through?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/640-911_dcicn.pdf&#34;&gt;640-911 Exam Topics&lt;/a&gt;(PDF)&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 2)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 19:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;I am continuing the ongoing of series of blog posts that follow the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I figured that this type of post would help me and anybody else looking at studying for the exam. Feel free to post questions below as if  on a study group, In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. Continuing where we left off from &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/16/640-911-chapter-1/&#34; title=&#34;640-911 (Chapter 1)&#34;&gt;chapter one&lt;/a&gt; let’s begin chapter 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; Chapter 2 goes over the difference between a broadcast domains and collision domains and how to find them. What does the &amp;quot;Router&amp;quot; do for us when using it in a LAN? What are the advantages of it and the functions it offers? We also were introduced into the OSI model. What is it and what are the advantages of it? Todd also went over each layer of the model with more detail on the Transport layer, Network layer and the Data Link layer. For example in the Transport layer we learned about the TCP and UDP and the difference between those two protocols. Along with understanding TCP&#39;s connection-oriented process, the three-way handshake.  We also looked other features that TCP offers like what does flow control do for us? Along with understanding what windowing and acknowledgments are. Going from layer 4 to layer 3 we were introduced into the network addresses and what they do along with knowing some terminology like routing tables, interfaces, and metrics.  Going down from layer 3 to layer 2 what is a frame vs. a packet and what is the difference between the Media Access Control (802.3) and the Logical Link Control (802.2) Finally at layer 1 this chapter talked a bit about the cabling standards but it lets you know why hubs are a layer 1 device and the difference between switch and a hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;: This chapter goes over a lot of material that was somewhat introduced in chapter one but goes further into details. I would study the OSI model and its different layers if you have never used it before. Like on chapter one I would go over the review questions starting on page 54 before skipping this chapter. Like before if you have questions on chapter two comment below and the check back next week for chapter three! I have posted before on this blog some items that would go along with this chapter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/&#34; title=&#34;Collision Domains vs. Broadcast Domains&#34;&gt;Collision Domains vs. Broadcast Domains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/17/the-osi-layer/&#34; title=&#34;The OSI Layer&#34;&gt;The OSI Layer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/25/understanding-tcp/&#34; title=&#34;Understanding TCP&#34;&gt;Understanding TCP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/&#34; title=&#34;Understanding UDP&#34;&gt;Understanding UDP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 1)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/16/640-911-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 17:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/16/640-911-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;So I bought the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Data-Center-Introducing-Networking/dp/1118661265/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1389461666&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=ccna+data+center&#34; title=&#34;CCNA Data Center - Introducing Cisco Data Center Networking Study Guide: Exam 640-911&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle&lt;/a&gt;. I have decided it would be a good idea to go over the topics of each chapter of this book in series of  blog posts. The idea of this is to work together if on a study group, go over the topics in each chapter of the book, talk about examples and to get an idea of what the exam would cover. Below are my thoughts about chapter one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; So when I read chapter one I had to remind myself this is an introduction into the CCNA Data Center exam, as I have &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/&#34; title=&#34;CCNA Data Center&#34;&gt;talked before&lt;/a&gt; the 640-911 exam has no perquisites so we started at the beginning. Asking ourselves “What is a Network?” Todd does a good job in introducing us into these technologies, like understanding what a LAN, WAN is and the difference between these types of logical topologies. We also covered the most common types of network devices such as a workstations, servers, and printers and what function they do on the network. As well as understanding what a peer-to-peer network is and client/server network, when would you use these type of network architectures? We then finally jumped into the type of physical topologies like what a bus, star, ring, are and what are the pros and cons of each? At the end of this chapter you should understand the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know the types of network topologies. For example what is the difference between a logical topology and a physical topology?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know the pros and cons of each topology. For example a Mesh topology vs. a Star topology?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the difference between a LANs and WANs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts:&lt;/strong&gt; For this chapter it&#39;s a review if you went over some CCENT/CCNA study materials or have a CCENT, however don’t skip over this chapter. Instead I would check the review questions on page 23, if you do pretty well go over to chapter two. I have of hinted on this before if you have a CCNA or higher it may seem like a review but there are flakes of new material scattered into the exam and just enough to fail you if you decide to skip it. :) I hope this information will be helpful and if you have any questions on chapter one comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22chamambom@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Martin&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-01-16 13:55:08&#34;&gt;Jan 4, 2014&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;looking forward to the new cert ,im CCNA certified and didnt want to tek the steep CCNP route just yet as im too busy at work ,this will definitely work for me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/&#34; title=&#34;ryan@ciscoskills.net&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-01-16 17:52:36&#34;&gt;Jan 4, 2014&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Martin, You an me are in the same boat :) Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;640-911 (Chapter 2) « Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-01-23 12:15:53&#34;&gt;Jan 4, 2014&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. Continuing where we left off from chapter one let’s begin chapter […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting FEX (5k to 2k)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/12/01/connecting-fex-5k-to-2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 15:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/12/01/connecting-fex-5k-to-2k/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/nexus-pline.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/nexus-pline.png&#34; alt=&#34;Nexus-PLine&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I was pretty excited to get my hands on some of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Nexus_switches&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Nexus switches&#34;&gt;Cisco Nexus&lt;/a&gt; product line which focuses on switching in the data center. The gear I have is an evaluation unit so I made some notes and one thing I was impressed is how easy it is to connect a Nexus 5K to a Nexus 2k also known as a fabric extender. I have kept it simple as the gear I have is a single Nexus 5596 along with a single Nexus 224TP-E who needs redundancy right? So in this post I&#39;ll explain how to connect a 5k Nexus to a 2k extender. Let’s get started! So I needed a couple of SFPs as the only way to connect the 5k to the 2k is a FET-10G SFP along with that was some multimode fiber (OM3) with LC connectors. Looking at the simple diagram below our end goal is to be able to configure the 2k from the 5k. That is the point of the 2k extenders less switches to manage in the data center.&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/5k-to-2k.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/5k-to-2k.png&#34; alt=&#34;5k to 2k&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Once we have made the physical connections lets power both switches on, we won&#39;t need to worry about the 2k switch at all as along we have a physical connection to a parent switch the 5k in our case, but that also could be 7k switch. Just an FYI, I&#39;ve already ran through the simple CLI wizard to setup a username and password but other than that let&#39;s get configuring by entering the familiar command &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;config t&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; [code]User Access Verification demo5k login: admin Password: Cisco Nexus Operating System (NX-OS) Software TAC support: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/tac&#34;&gt;http://www.cisco.com/tac&lt;/a&gt; Copyright (c) 2002-2013, Cisco Systems, Inc. All rights reserved. The copyrights to certain works contained in this software are owned by other third parties and used and distributed under license. Certain components of this software are licensed under the GNU General Public License (GPL) version 2.0 or the GNU Lesser General Public License (LGPL) Version 2.1. A copy of each such license is available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/gpl-2.0.php&#34;&gt;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/gpl-2.0.php&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/lgpl-2.1.php&#34;&gt;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/lgpl-2.1.php&lt;/a&gt; demo5k# config t[/code] Now in configuration mode we have to turn on a feature in the NX-OS to enable FEX, we do this by issuing the &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;feature FEX&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; command. The Nexus runs on efficiency and only loads what it needs or configured. This is familiar approach that Linux uses which loads what is installed and nothing else.  In the output below we can see all the features that the NX-OS supports followed by the command to turn on FEX. [code] Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. demo5k(config)# feature ? bgp Enable/Disable Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) cts Enable/Disable CTS dhcp Enable/Disable DHCP Snooping dot1x Enable/Disable dot1x eigrp Enable/Disable Enhanced Interior Gateway Routing Protocol (EIGRP) fcoe Enable/Disable FCoE/FC feature fcoe-npv Enable/Disable FCoE NPV feature fex Enable/Disable FEX flexlink Enable/Disable Flexlink hsrp Enable/Disable Hot Standby Router Protocol (HSRP) http-server Enable/Disable http-server interface-vlan Enable/Disable interface vlan lacp Enable/Disable LACP msdp Enable/Disable Multicast Source Discovery Protocol (MSDP) ntp Enable/Disable NTP ospf Enable/Disable Open Shortest Path First Protocol (OSPF) ospfv3 Enable/Disable Open Shortest Path First Version 3 Protocol (OSPFv3) pim Enable/Disable Protocol Independent Multicast (PIM) port-security Enable/Disable port-security private-vlan Enable/Disable private-vlan privilege Enable/Disable IOS type privilege level support ptp Enable/Disable PTP rip Enable/Disable Routing Information Protocol (RIP) scp-server Enable/Disable SCP server sftp-server Enable/Disable SFTP server ssh Enable/Disable ssh tacacs+ Enable/Disable tacacs+ telnet Enable/Disable telnet udld Enable/Disable UDLD vpc Enable/Disable VPC (Virtual Port Channel) vrrp Enable/Disable Virtual Router Redundancy Protocol (VRRP) vtp Enable/Disable Vlan Trunking Protocol (VTP) demo5k(config)# feature fex demo5k(config)#[/code] Now that our FEX feature is active let&#39;s configure the port that has the 2k connected and in this example I have it as ethernet port 48 on our 5k. The commands are petty simple, I first want to go into interface followed by changing the mode of interface and finally giving the interface a FEX associate ID. :!:&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: Since this design is a single stack we need to issue the FEX associate command on the physical interface. If you want redundancy you would usually put the FEX associate command with &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2014/09/10/setting-up-enhanced-vpc-on-nexus-5600/&#34; title=&#34;Setting up Enhanced vPC on Nexus 5600&#34;&gt;channel-groups and vPCs&lt;/a&gt;. Another helpful FYI is if you have channel-groups you don&#39;t need to put the FEX associate command on the physical interface. [code]demo5k(config)# interface ethernet1/48 demo5k(config-if)# switchport mode fex-fabric demo5k(config-if)# fex associate 100 demo5k(config-if)# exit demo5k(config)#[/code] Give it a couple of minutes and you should see the 2k come online :) [code]2013 Dec 01 07:28:37 demo5k %$ VDC-1 %$ %PFMA-2-FEX_STATUS: Fex 100 is online 2013 Dec 01 07:28:37 demo5k %$ VDC-1 %$ %NOHMS-2-NOHMS_ENV_FEX_ONLINE: FEX-100 On-line 2013 Dec 01 07:28:39 demo5k %$ VDC-1 %$ %PFMA-2-FEX_STATUS: Fex 100 is online[/code] Let&#39;s verify that our FEX is all good by issuing &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;show fex 100&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; which shows the FEX and the 5k version. (Notice they match versions) You can also find the serial number, model number, the number links and the status of fabric when using this command. (The 5K) [code]demo5k# show fex 100 FEX: 100 Description: FEX0100 state: Online FEX version: 6.0(2)N1(2) [Switch version: 6.0(2)N1(2)] Extender Serial: SSI153804CQ Extender Model: N2K-C2248TP-E-1GE, Part No: 73-13671-01 Pinning-mode: static Max-links: 1 Fabric port for control traffic: Eth1/48 FCoE Admin: false FCoE Oper: true FCoE FEX AA Configured: false Fabric interface state: Eth1/48 - Interface Up. State: Active demo5k# show fex FEX FEX FEX FEX Number Description State Model Serial ------------------------------------------------------------------------ 100 FEX0100 Online N2K-C2248TP-E-1GE SSI153804CQ[/code] You can also go into detail on the FEX by issuing the &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;show fex detail&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; which shows almost the same information has &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;show fex&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; but it includes the FEX ports, the status of those FEX ports and what port the fabric is connected. (Also called the 5k) as well as helpful logs for the 2k at the end of command. [code]demo5k# show fex detail FEX: 100 Description: FEX0100 state: Online FEX version: 6.0(2)N1(2) [Switch version: 6.0(2)N1(2)] FEX Interim version: 6.0(2)N1(2) Switch Interim version: 6.0(2)N1(2) Extender Serial: SSI153804CQ Extender Model: N2K-C2248TP-E-1GE, Part No: 73-13671-01 Card Id: 149, Mac Addr: 70:81:05:00:99:42, Num Macs: 64 Module Sw Gen: 12594 [Switch Sw Gen: 21] post level: complete pinning-mode: static Max-links: 1 Fabric port for control traffic: Eth1/48 FCoE Admin: false FCoE Oper: true FCoE FEX AA Configured: false Fabric interface state: Eth1/48 - Interface Up. State: Active Fex Port State Fabric Port Eth100/1/1 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/2 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/3 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/4 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/5 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/6 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/7 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/8 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/9 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/10 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/11 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/12 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/13 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/14 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/15 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/16 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/17 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/18 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/19 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/20 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/21 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/22 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/23 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/24 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/25 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/26 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/27 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/28 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/29 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/30 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/31 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/32 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/33 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/34 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/35 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/36 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/37 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/38 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/39 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/40 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/41 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/42 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/43 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/44 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/45 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/46 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/47 Down Eth1/48 Eth100/1/48 Down Eth1/48 Logs: 12/01/2013 07:28:31.344277: Module register received 12/01/2013 07:28:31.347237: Registration response sent 12/01/2013 07:28:31.696577: create module inserted event. 12/01/2013 07:28:31.697697: Module Online Sequence 12/01/2013 07:28:37.285556: Module Online[/code] Believe it or not you now have a working 5k with a connected FEX, you could plug devices in and be ready to roll on a single stack 2k and 5k. One thing I&#39;ve been impressed with the NX-OS it&#39;s that familiar feeling of IOS with some improved differences, Cisco has good documentation on the common and different features when comparing NX-OS and IOS which is below. Like always I hope this post is helpful and I have a couple more Nexus posts in the works but other than that enjoy the remaining of 2013! &lt;a href=&#34;http://docwiki.cisco.com/wiki/Cisco_Nexus_7000_NX-OS/IOS_Comparison_Tech_Notes&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Nexus 7000 NX-OS/IOS Comparison Tech Notes&#34;&gt;Cisco Nexus 7000 NX-OS/IOS Comparison Tech Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/datacenter/exploring-the-nexus-1000-v-rest-api/&#34;&gt;Exploring the Nexus 1000 V REST API&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://brasstacksblog.typepad.com/brass-tacks/2012/02/fc-and-fcoe-versus-iscsi-network-centric-versus-end-node-centric-provisioning.html&#34;&gt;FC and FCoE versus iSCSI - &amp;quot;Network-centric&amp;quot; versus &amp;quot;End-Node-centric&amp;quot; provisioning&lt;/a&gt; (brasstacksblog.typepad.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://LinkedIn.com/farhane&#34; title=&#34;Interpreter411@gmail.com&#34;&gt;Farhan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-12-01 10:54:08&#34;&gt;Dec 0, 2013&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick question: why port 1/48 down? I thought you configured that interface/port?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://ciscoskills.net/ &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-12-01 11:25:41&#34;&gt;Dec 0, 2013&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Farhan, Port 1/48 is not down on the 5k but on the 2k port 100/1/48 is down, this is a 1GB copper port and in the example I had nothing connected to the 2k. The 2k has four FEX ports that can be connected to a 5k or a 7k, however in this example I did not issue a command that shows the FEX port status, I&#39;ll do some digging in finding an example but from what I can tell I think the &amp;quot;show interface fex-fabric&amp;quot; would show what uplink it is connected to and the status of the FEX link. Hope that Helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Inter-VLAN Routing on the Nexus 5k. &amp;laquo; Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-03-13 09:46:28&#34;&gt;Mar 4, 2014&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] this example I have already configured a FEX port with a 2k check out the my earlier post Connecting FEX (5k to 2k) so let’s start right after that and login into the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[640-911 (Chapter 7) &amp;laquo; Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-02-27 11:02:42&#34;&gt;Feb 4, 2014&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] to forwarded traffic is also very cool, thanks ISSU (No downtime around here ) I hinted on an earlier post that the Nexus runs on efficiency and only loads what it needs or configured, why load up NTP if […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Data Center</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 02:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; has now introduced another associate level &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_%28assessment%29&#34; title=&#34;Test (assessment)&#34;&gt;exam&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CCNA&#34; title=&#34;CCNA&#34;&gt;CCNA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_center&#34; title=&#34;Data center&#34;&gt;Data Center&lt;/a&gt; exam. Like the name suggests this exam focuses on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_center&#34; title=&#34;Data center&#34;&gt;Data Center&lt;/a&gt; and if passed you can continue up the stack by also taking the CCNP Data Center exam which was also recently introduced as well. Still want more a little more, if you are up for the challenge you can also tackle the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CCIE_Certification&#34; title=&#34;CCIE Certification&#34;&gt;CCIE&lt;/a&gt; Data Center which is an exam that was introduced in March of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the CCNA DC certification requirements, there is no need to get certificated in the regular CCNA &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Routing&#34; title=&#34;Routing&#34;&gt;Routing&lt;/a&gt; and Switching as it is not required but looking at the renewal options for this certification you have to either get a CCNA concentration exam like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Career_Certifications&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Career Certifications&#34;&gt;CCNA Wireless&lt;/a&gt;, Security, Voice, SP, SP Ops or a higher certification like CCNP and above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ciscoskills.net/images/2012/11/ccna-data-centere1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting thing I noticed when looking at Cisco&#39;s Career Certifications is that if you passed your CCNA Data Center exam and then later you passed the regular CCNA exam the CCNA Data Center certification would not renew. Unlike if you recived your CCNP Data Center certification and then took the CCNP exam it would renew you CCNP Data Center certification. What makes this exam so different from the rest of Cisco&#39;s certifications? Well to what I can tell this exam focuses on a specific area, meaning you don&#39;t need to have any certifications to back you up before you take the CCNA Data Center exam, and you can continue with CCNP Data Center exam without the need to have any other certifications beside CCNA DC. To pass the CCNA Data Center and receive your certification, you will need to pass two exams. The first exam (640-911 DCICN) looks at how a Data Center network works, along with configuring, verifying and troubleshooting data center switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exam also looks at implementing data center &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34; title=&#34;IP address&#34;&gt;IP address&lt;/a&gt; schemes and configuring, along with verifying and troubleshooting routing on Nexus switches. The second exam (640-916 DCICT) looks at Cisco&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fabric_computing&#34; title=&#34;Fabric computing&#34;&gt;Unified Computing&lt;/a&gt; System, and virtualization by talking about the fundamentals. Along with focusing on the data center storage switching and the unified fabric between them. Finally this exam looks at the Data Center Network Services, like such as Cisco ACS and load balancing between servers and management options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excited? You can find more information by going to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/web/learning/le3/le2/le0/ccna_dc/index.html&#34; title=&#34;CCNA Data Center Certification&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center - Career Certifications&lt;/a&gt; and check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/community/certifications/ccna_data_center&#34;&gt;The Cisco Learning Network and the section  CCNA Data Center&lt;/a&gt;. Because of this recent announcement there are limited if any Cisco Press books out there, (Let me know if you find one ;) ) but I&#39;m sure that will change within a couple months. Check back to this post to see any updates on reading material as I will be actively looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; There is a book available from Todd Lammle - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Data-Center-Introducing-Networking/dp/1118661265&#34; title=&#34;CCNA Data Center - Introducing Cisco Data Center Networking Study Guide&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center - Introducing Cisco Data Center Networking Study Guide&lt;/a&gt; This title looks like it only covers the 640-911 exam. **UPDATE 2: **Since Cisco has now re-amped the ICND1 (ICND1 100-101) and ICND2 (ICND2 200-101) you can now get the CCNA Data Center cert renewed by passing the any current Associate-level exam except for the ICND1. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/datacenter/next-generations-data-centers-need-next-generations-skills/&#34;&gt;Next Generations Data Centers Need Next Generation Skills&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thevarguy.com/2012/11/21/cisco-overhauls-data-center-certifications/&#34;&gt;Cisco Overhauls Data Center Certifications&lt;/a&gt; (thevarguy.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://networkingnerd.net/2012/11/21/vmware-certification-for-cisco-people/&#34;&gt;VMware Certification for Cisco People&lt;/a&gt; (networkingnerd.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2013/06/29/passed-640-554/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Passed 640-554! « Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-29 23:51:06&#34;&gt;Jun 6, 2013&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] what is my next plan? Not sure I might look at that new CCNA Data Center exam which was announced last fall and it also looked like they may have some study material for […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
