<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network Layer on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/network-layer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network Layer on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 19:30:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/network-layer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Three Tiers</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/the-three-tiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 19:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/the-three-tiers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/network_switch.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/network_switch.jpg?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;network_switch&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Working towards the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CCNA&#34; title=&#34;CCNA&#34;&gt;CCNA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; talks about a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_topology&#34; title=&#34;Network topology&#34;&gt;hierarchical network&lt;/a&gt; there are three layers to this design. Access Layer, distribution layer and the core layer. Each of them have their own set of functions and is also considered to be a best practice when the network continues to grow and for redundancy along with just a better way to manage it. &lt;strong&gt;The Access layer&lt;/strong&gt; is the layer that devices connect to, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_computer&#34; title=&#34;Personal computer&#34;&gt;PCs&lt;/a&gt;, printers, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VoIP_phone&#34; title=&#34;VoIP phone&#34;&gt;IP Phones&lt;/a&gt;. The access layer can include routers, switches, bridges, hubs, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wireless_access_point&#34; title=&#34;Wireless access point&#34;&gt;wireless access points&lt;/a&gt;, etc. The main purpose is providing a means of connecting devices to the network, this is also your first line of defense of controlling who is on your network. &lt;strong&gt;The Distribution Layer&lt;/strong&gt; aggregates the data received from the access layer before it is transmitted to the core for routing to its destination. The distribution layer is like a traffic cop to which it controls the flow of network traffic using policies like routing between broadcast domains by having &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_LAN&#34; title=&#34;Virtual LAN&#34;&gt;VLANs&lt;/a&gt; which are setup on the access layer. VLANs let you segment traffic on a switch into separate subnetworks. Why would you segment traffic? The main reason is for security you should not have sensitive data on a public network because anybody can reach it, by separating it you also have more control over it on who can get access to it. &lt;strong&gt;The Core Layer&lt;/strong&gt; of the hierarchical design is the high-speed backbone of the network. The core layer is critical for interconnectivity between the distribution layer devices. The core must be highly available and should be redundant. The core can also connect to internet resources, because the core aggregates the traffic from the entire distribution layer it must be able to handle high data traffic. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/21/the-three-tiers/hierarchical-layerse/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/hierarchical-layerse.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Hierarchical Layer&#34; title=&#34;Hierarchical Layers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; In small networks it is a common practice to use a collapsed core model to where the distribution layer and core are merged into one layer. If the network grows it is fairly easy to add the core layer. Because you are in hierarchical network you have many benefits which I&#39;ll hold off for another day but in summary they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scalability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Redundancy_%28engineering%29&#34; title=&#34;Redundancy (engineering)&#34;&gt;Redundancy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manageability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintainability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like always I hope this information is helpful in at least having a better idea of Cisco&#39;s hierarchical network design. One of the hardest things when designing this type of network is if you are trying to change the original one because of poor performance and degradation. Like always if you have an idea of the next topic that looks at ICND1 or ICND2 let me hear it by posting below, or if you have questions feel free to post them as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.co.uk/2011/09/21/flatter_networks/&#34;&gt;No more tiers for flatter networks&lt;/a&gt; (go.theregister.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ioshints.info/2011/10/l2-or-l3-switching-in-campus-networks.html&#34;&gt;L2 or L3 switching in campus networks?&lt;/a&gt; (ioshints.info)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/datacenter/vxlan-deep-dive-part-2-looking-at-the-options/&#34;&gt;VXLAN Deep Dive, Part 2: Looking at the Options&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/datacenter/digging-deeper-into-vxlan/&#34;&gt;Digging Deeper into VXLAN, Part 1&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In the month of August I talked about the &amp;quot;beginnings&amp;quot; of layer two &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Redundancy_%28engineering%29&#34; title=&#34;Redundancy (engineering)&#34;&gt;redundancy&lt;/a&gt; mainly looking at the basic foundations and fundamentals of having layer two redundancy. Let&#39;s continue are discussion about redundancy in the layer two environment. To review what STP does (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanning_Tree_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Spanning Tree Protocol&#34;&gt;Spanning Tree Protocol&lt;/a&gt;) it works at layer two of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt;. If more than one path is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Network Layer&#34;&gt;network&lt;/a&gt; the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until the active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.) So although there are multiple links connected physically to offer redundancy, logically the switches in the network only see one path that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethernet_frame&#34; title=&#34;Ethernet frame&#34;&gt;Ethernet frame&lt;/a&gt; can travel. Remember without STP networks would be on the fritz when we introduce redundancy in the environment. STP or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IEEE_802.1D&#34; title=&#34;IEEE 802.1D&#34;&gt;IEEE 802.1D&lt;/a&gt; is an open standard so it is not just on Cisco equipment but others as well which helps in a multivendor situation. So how does looping occur without the use STP? Looking at the picture below we can see the broadcasts frames are flooding the network which is by design but the thing that changes is these broadcasts will continue to flood the network because there is on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_to_live&#34; title=&#34;Time to live&#34;&gt;TTL&lt;/a&gt; (Time-To-Live) on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Link_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Data Link Layer&#34;&gt;data link layer&lt;/a&gt; of the OSI model. As more packets are passed and created the network will become slower and slower and eventually devices on the network will become unavailable this called a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcast_radiation&#34; title=&#34;Broadcast radiation&#34;&gt;broadcast storm&lt;/a&gt;. [caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1534&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;584&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;STP Loop Example (Broadcast Storm)&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/stpfl.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/stpfl.png&#34; alt=&#34;An example of an STP loop&#34; title=&#34;STP Loop&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] There are also more problems when not using STP besides broadcast storms like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MAC_address&#34; title=&#34;MAC address&#34;&gt;MAC address&lt;/a&gt; table becoming unstable in each switch. This causes the MAC table to be unreliable because of the looping frames in the network. These frames are usually sent to the wrong locations in the network. Multiple frames can also be a problem because of looping frames multiple frames appear on the network and if they are delivered to the intended host it can confuse the host and more likly drop the frames. So looking at the same picture but with STP enabled we can see that broadcast frame will travel the network without looping. On S1 one of the ports is in a blocking state and blocks all traffic coming into that port and traffic coming out of that port. [caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1539&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;584&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;STP Enabled&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/stp-enable/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/stp-enable.png&#34; alt=&#34;STP Enabled&#34; title=&#34;STP Enable&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] The magic about STP is when the link between S2 and S3 becomes disconnected it will bring the link between S2 and S1 online and continue to send packets! When the link becomes available again it switch back to blocking on S1. So let&#39;s stop there for now and check back next week to see the last chapter of STP, how does it calculate which switch goes to blocking? What other advantages does STP offer? That&#39;s all next week, I hope this information is helpful and if you have an idea of the next topic that deals with either ICND1 or ICND2 let me hear it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/&#34;&gt;The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.co.uk/2011/08/03/network_resiliency/&#34;&gt;Belt and braces stop the network falling down&lt;/a&gt; (go.theregister.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.avaya.com/blogs/archives/2011/08/resiliency-and-redundancy---not-the-same.html&#34;&gt;Resiliency and Redundancy - NOT the same&lt;/a&gt; (avaya.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techbookshelf.com/2011/08/31/cisco-nexus-vpc-configuration-and-spanning-tree-elimination/&#34;&gt;Cisco Nexus vPC Configuration and Spanning-Tree Elimination&lt;/a&gt; (techbookshelf.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-07 18:51:46&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve do you have any questions? Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Steve]( &#34;svu@uppertraining.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-07 12:27:32&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome Site. Ryan can you please contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Welcome CCT (Cisco Certified Technician Certification) | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/21/welcome-cct-cisco-certified-technician/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-21 20:44:38&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[The “Ending” of Layer Two Redundancy | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/14/the-%e2%80%9cending%e2%80%9d-of-layer-two-redundancy/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-14 11:17:26&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Store-and-Forward vs. Cut-Through Switching | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/05/store-and-forward-vs-cut-through-switching/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-10-05 10:16:16&#34;&gt;Oct 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/network-diagram.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/network-diagram.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;network-diagram&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In a perfect world we would never need redundancy on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Network Layer&#34;&gt;network&lt;/a&gt; infrastructure, but as you know as well as I know we don&#39;t live in a perfect world. Hardware will eventually fail, bottlenecks will appear, and the speed of our network will become slower when we max the bandwidth on links. So having redundancy in routers, connections, and having a hierarchy network is one of best choices to make when improving the efficiently of the network. But in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt; there is one layer that can&#39;t have redundancy at least logically and that is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstraction_layer&#34; title=&#34;Abstraction layer&#34;&gt;Layer&lt;/a&gt; two of the OSI model. If you follow this blog way back when I talked about the OSI model, layer two belongs to the switches and by design the ethernet frame does not support a TTL (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_to_live&#34; title=&#34;Time to live&#34;&gt;Time-To-Live&lt;/a&gt;) like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Protocol&#34;&gt;IP packet&lt;/a&gt;. So bring forth STP, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanning_Tree_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Spanning Tree Protocol&#34;&gt;Spanning Tree Protocol&lt;/a&gt; which works at layer two of the OSI model. If more than one path is available in the network the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.) So although there are multiple links connected physically to offer redundancy, logically the switches in the network only see one path that ethernet frame can travel. &lt;strong&gt;Your Thought:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait...I have plugged into multiple Cisco switches before to create a redundant path and I did not notice anything wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s because by default STP is enabled, to the average person they can plug away and create redundant paths with switches and cause no harm to the network. But if STP has been disabled on those switches or switches that don&#39;t support STP (dumb switches), a Layer 2 loop can occur. A Layer 2 loop is a nightmare if this happens in a production network and can happen in seconds. Loops result in high &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_processing_unit&#34; title=&#34;Central processing unit&#34;&gt;CPU&lt;/a&gt; load on all switches caught in the loop. Because the same frames are constantly being forwarded back and forth between all switches in the loop, the CPU of the switch ends up having to process a lot of data. This slows down performance on the switch when legitimate traffic arrives.  A host caught in a network loop is not accessible to other hosts on the network. Because the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MAC_address&#34; title=&#34;MAC address&#34;&gt;MAC address&lt;/a&gt; table is constantly changing with the updates from the broadcast frames, the switch does not know which port to send the unicast frames out to reach the destination. The unicast frames end up looping around the network as well. As more and more frames end up looping on the network, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcast_radiation&#34; title=&#34;Broadcast radiation&#34;&gt;broadcast storm&lt;/a&gt; occurs. What makes this even more fun is if you try connecting to the switches to solve this problem, good luck :). Most of the time you have to physically turn off the switches to kill the broadcast storm and if it happened once expect it to happen again. To make things worse if any end-devices are connected to the switch ports that are experiencing a broadcast storm they too have a hard time keeping up with the mountain of broadcast frames being sent and sometimes malfunction. Usually you would have to disconnect the switch from the redundant links and apply STP to it and then re-connect the redundant links in order for your network to be broadcast storm free. Although I&#39;m just getting started I think by just introducing this topic will help you better understand it later, I will get into more of this STP magic and how this really helps us design a hierarchy network. Like always I hope this information was informative and if you can&#39;t wait a simple search about STP will help. You can also go right to the source for more STP information at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; Support and Documentation. Have an idea of the next topic either ICND1 or ICND2 let me know about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/smallbusiness/get-data-to-its-destination-faster/&#34;&gt;Get Data to Its Destination Faster&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/17/the-osi-layer/&#34; title=&#34;The OSI Layer&#34;&gt;The OSI Layer&lt;/a&gt;  (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.co.uk/2011/06/16/network_tuning/&#34;&gt;When tuning the server, don&#39;t forget the network&lt;/a&gt; (go.theregister.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-07 12:08:56&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Vector Routing</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/distance-vector-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 16:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/distance-vector-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Couple weeks ago I talked about routing protocols and in the post I mentioned two routing protocol features distance vector and link state. Although these protocols fundamentally do the same thing by getting information on remote networks they get this information in a different way. For today let&#39;s introduce distance vector routing. With a distance vector routing protocol, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;router&lt;/a&gt; learns about a route to a different &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Network Layer&#34;&gt;network&lt;/a&gt; (that&#39;s the purpose of a routing protocol) the router only knows the &amp;quot;distance&amp;quot; to get there this is usually called the metric. The router also knows the next-hop router along with the outgoing interface to use when sending a packet destined to that network and that&#39;s it. You could say that a distance vector protocol does not give a graphical representation of the entire network. Look at the picture below R1 has two routes two the network 192.168.3.0. For distance vector the router chooses the lowest metric if this example was using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Routing_Information_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Routing Information Protocol&#34;&gt;RIP&lt;/a&gt; the routers metric would be using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hop_count&#34; title=&#34;Hop count&#34;&gt;hop count&lt;/a&gt; and pick the path with the lowest hop count/metric. So although we have multiple routers between R1 and R3, for R1 it only knows and pretty much only cares about the routers that are directly connected to R1 (the red routers) and those are routers are advertising that they have a route reach to R3 (the 192.168.3.0 network.) &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/distance-vector/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/distance-vector.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Distance Vector Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Distance Vector&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Which &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Protocol&#34;&gt;IP&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Routing_protocol&#34; title=&#34;Routing protocol&#34;&gt;Routing Protocols&lt;/a&gt; use &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distance-vector_routing_protocol&#34; title=&#34;Distance-vector routing protocol&#34;&gt;Distance Vector&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RIPv1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RIPv2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enhanced_Interior_Gateway_Routing_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Enhanced Interior Gateway Routing Protocol&#34;&gt;EIGRP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Shortest_Path_First&#34; title=&#34;Open Shortest Path First&#34;&gt;OSPF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IS-IS&#34; title=&#34;IS-IS&#34;&gt;IS-IS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classless&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supports &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classless_Inter-Domain_Routing&#34; title=&#34;Classless Inter-Domain Routing&#34;&gt;VLSM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send Subnet Mask&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distance Vector&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*EIGRP is considered a hybrid routing protocol (Uses the best of both Distance Vector and Link-State protocols) In some Cisco documentation EIGRP is also referred to as an advance distance vector protocol. That&#39;s my summary of at least Distance Vector routing protocols, there is a lot of other helpful information about distance vector and if you would like to learn simple web search would do. Also check out Cisco.com as they do have this and much more helpful documentation. I hope this information was informative and if you have an idea of the next topic that either deals with ICND1 or ICND2 let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/&#34;&gt;Dynamic Routing Protocols&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/&#34;&gt;Configure Static Routing&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/01/classful-vs-classless-routing/&#34;&gt;Classful vs. Classless Routing&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-07-06 09:47:24&#34;&gt;Jul 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[jjrinehart]( &#34;joe.rinehart@seacug.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-20 23:30:52&#34;&gt;Jun 1, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading earlier that you passed the ICND1 and that you would be working on ICND2, how is that going?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-21 17:52:40&#34;&gt;Jun 2, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m getting there, like with everything in life things get in the way but in the end I&#39;ll find time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
