<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VPN on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/vpn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VPN on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 18:13:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/vpn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fortigate ECMP with BGP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2020/10/11/fortigate-ecmp-with-bgp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 18:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2020/10/11/fortigate-ecmp-with-bgp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s like clock work...around this time the seasons are changing..autumn colors are out, and the colder air reminds us that things are changing around here, embrace it! One thing that I&#39;ve been working with is AWS Transit gateways, a common theme this year is all cloud! AWS Transit Gateways make it easier to move towards that!
AWS Transit gateways relatively new, (couple years old now) so instead of attaching to each AWS VPC environment independently we can connect to the transit gateway and attach VPCs to the gateway.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VTIs with ASA</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2020/08/08/vtis-with-asa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 15:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2020/08/08/vtis-with-asa/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve been stuck in more ways then one this year...working from home indefinitely seems to be the status quo right now, and I&#39;m in &amp;quot;tunnel&amp;quot; mode for most part. Most of these projects I&#39;m working on all of common theme.. connect on-premise to more cloud resources! One way to do that is using VTIs. (Virtual Tunnel Interfaces) VTIs which are not new...been around for a bit, Cisco IOS had the feature available like 10+ years ago!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Site to Site VPN (DHCP)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/04/19/asa-site-to-site-vpn-dhcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/04/19/asa-site-to-site-vpn-dhcp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you don’t already know, site to site VPNs can be a cost-effective way for remote sites to connect to HQ resources instead of a lease line like using MPLS or Metro-E circuits. We can instead use a standard internet connection with a static IP, this is usually cheaper than a dedicated circuit. Our next steps are purchasing a firewall for the remote site (assuming you already have one at HQ) and setup a site to site VPN connection to make the connection.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Site to Site VPN (PATed)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/03/08/asa-site-to-site-vpn-pated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/03/08/asa-site-to-site-vpn-pated/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you ever needed to hide multiple systems behind a single IP address you would use PAT. (Port Address Translation) besides using this to connect to the internet when using an RFC 1918 address, you can configure PAT for VPN connections. The benefit is the same, hide multiple systems behind a single IP address with the advantage being you can have many systems on one side of the VPN tunnel all using that single IP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site-To-Site VPN via CCP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/05/02/site-to-site-vpn-via-ccp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 02:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/05/02/site-to-site-vpn-via-ccp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I have ran through before on how to create a site-to-site VPN with Cisco SDM which sounds like a repeat but I thought why not bring CCP into light and since I&#39;m studying the newly created CCNA Security (640-554) I figured let&#39;s create a tutorial on it. In this lab I am going to post the running-config of both locations so you can either run it through Packet Tracer or live equipment if you wish.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure a Site-to-Site VPN via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 18:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure a site-to-site VPN on a router using the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. (See the post Configuring SDM) Let&#39;s start configuring a site-to-site VPN with SDM! This tutorial is assuming that the configurations to set up Cisco SDM have already been completed.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
