<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CentOS on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/centos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CentOS on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 12:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/centos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TFTP &amp; FTP Server on Centos 7</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/09/16/tftp-ftp-server-on-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/09/16/tftp-ftp-server-on-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you ever needed a TFTP or an anonymous FTP server to transfer files, logs, or crash debugs to and from your network devices it can be a little tricky if you don&#39;t have anything setup. There are some free quick programs out there if you are in a pinch for one-time transfers but if you ever wanted to have something in infrastructure that is ready to go for this kind of stuff just follow this tutorial below.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rancid can’t SSH to older ISRs?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/03/03/rancid-cant-ssh-to-older-isrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 02:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/03/03/rancid-cant-ssh-to-older-isrs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well its 2016 and you still have that one-of-kind Cisco ISR 2811 or 3845 running in the environment? You followed and installed Rancid, all the new stuff works like it should but when you try to connect to that “one-of-kind” 2811 with Rancid it closes the connection... :/
This is a simple fix and the bug is reported here: LINK. The bug is something with OpenSSH which is installed on your Linux operating system and Rancid rides on top of it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Graylog on Centos 7</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/01/01/installing-graylog-on-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2016/01/01/installing-graylog-on-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s start out 2016 with setting up a logging system called Graylog. If you have not used Graylog before then I encourage you to check it out. This is an open source log management system and is pretty flexible as it can capture, index and analyze almost anything. Once up and running this system can be scaled out for an enterprise wide log management system. High availability, clustered, and replicated is what Graylog thrives on.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Rancid</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/02/27/configuring-rancid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/02/27/configuring-rancid/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In my last post I talked about Installing Rancid on Centos 7 so be sure to check that out. In this post we now want to actually use Rancid so I’ll walk through on how to setup Rancid to login into network equipment and get configurations.
To recap: Rancid is a great tool to help monitor a device configuration for any changes. It also keeps track of them by using CVS (Concurrent Version System) for backups, so you can go back and compare versions or revert to a previous configuration.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Rancid and ViewVC on Centos 7</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/01/03/install-rancid-and-viewvc-on-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/01/03/install-rancid-and-viewvc-on-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I want to walk though the steps to install Rancid on CentOS 7 minimal. Rancid is a great tool to help monitor a device configuration for any changes. It also keeps track of them by using CVS (Concurrent Version System) for backups, so you can go back and compare versions or revert to a previous configuration. Rancid supports multiple hardware from Cisco, HP, Dell, Juniper and more. This is all open-source so you can create custom scripts or add commands to really make this a personal repository that fits your company.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install RSYSLOG &amp; LogAnalyzer on CentOS 6-5</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/06/11/install-rsyslog-loganalyzer-on-centos-6-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/06/11/install-rsyslog-loganalyzer-on-centos-6-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am looking at rsyslog which is fast syslog system and Loganalyzer as an upfront web GUI for those logs. The Loganalyzer application offers searching of various syslogs, all of which is open source and available to download. In this guide I will go through the steps to get these two applications to work together and in the end of this tutorial we should have a working syslog system ready to take logs!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
