<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:45:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Factory Reset Firepower 4100 &amp; 9300</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2016/10/factory-reset-firepower-4100-9300/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2016/10/factory-reset-firepower-4100-9300/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;I got my hands on some Cisco Firepower 4100 units and after playing around with them I wanted to reset them to factory settings, essentially erase the &amp;quot;startup-config&amp;quot; on the FXOS. The Firepower units act a little differently than your normal Cisco IOS or ASA and you can&#39;t just erase startup-config and reload the device, that would be too easy. (Edit: 7-21-17) After Gabriele made this &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2016/10/18/factory-reset-firepower-4100-9300/#comment-2869&#34;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; it looks like you can. You also can follow the  password recovery on this post which will also erases the configuration. You have to be physically at the device with a console cable, plug into the console port to begin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power off the system, and then power it back on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the system is booting, you have go into ROMMON mode to do that press ESC or CTRL+L. You&#39;ll see a message confirming that you are going to ROMMON&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[code]!! Rommon image verified successfully !! Cisco System ROMMON, Version 1.0.10, RELEASE SOFTWARE Copyright (c) 1994-2015 by Cisco Systems, Inc. Compiled Mon 11/30/2015 15:23:18.60 by builder Current image running: Boot ROM0 Last reset cause: PowerCycleRequest DIMM Slot 0 : Present DIMM Slot 1 : Present No USB drive !! BIOS has been locked !! Platform FPR-4110-SUP with 8192 Mbytes of main memory[/code]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make note of the kickstart and FXOS system image as you need these names to be able to boot to the correct image. In this example under ROMMON the following appeared on-screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[code]find the string ! boot bootflash:/installables/switch/fxos-k9-kickstart.5.0.3.N2.3.14.69.SPA bootflash:/installables/switch/fxos-k9-system.5.0.3.N2.3.14.69.SPA[/code]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load the kickstart image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[code]rommon 1 &amp;gt; boot bootflash:/installables/switch/fxos-k9-kickstart.5.0.3.N2.3.14.69.SPA !! Kickstart Image verified successfully !! [/code]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When kickstart loads you&#39;ll be at the switch(boot)# prompt, enter configuration mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[code]switch(boot)# switch(boot)# config t Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z.[/code]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the configuration mode, type admin-password erase, this will erase everything and bring the system back to factory defaults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[code]switch(boot)(config)# admin-password erase Your password and configuration will be erased! Do you want to continue? (y/n) [n] y switch(boot)(config)# exit[/code]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load the system image to startup the FXOS, once the image has been loaded you&#39;ll be prompted to enter the setup wizard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;codeswitchboot-load-bootflashinstallablesswitchfxos-k9-system503n231469spa-uncompressing-system-image-bootflashinstallablesswitchfxos-k9-system503n231469spa-you-have-chosen-to-setup-a-new-security-appliance-continue-yncode-i-hope-this-information-is-helpful-the-information-i-was-referencing-is-located-here-password-recovery-procedure-for-firepower-93004100-series-applianceshttpwwwciscocomcenussupportdocssecurityfirepower-9300-security-appliance200491-password-recovery-procedure-for-firepowehtml&#34;&gt;[code]switch(boot)# load bootflash:/installables/switch/fxos-k9-system.5.0.3.N2.3.14.69.SPA Uncompressing system image: bootflash:/installables/switch/fxos-k9-system.5.0.3.N2.3.14.69.SPA You have chosen to setup a new Security Appliance. Continue? (y/n):[/code] I hope this information is helpful, the information I was referencing is located here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/docs/security/firepower-9300-security-appliance/200491-Password-Recovery-Procedure-For-FirePOWE.html&#34;&gt;Password Recovery Procedure For Firepower 9300/4100 Series Appliances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22228496698@qq.com%22&#34;&gt;Jimmy&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-11-07 21:54:51&#34;&gt;Nov 1, 2016&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi :Ryan ,I got several devices like ASA 5525x with firepower mode ,i want to reinstall the whole system from ASA(firepower software ) to firepower system complete(called FTD system) ,Do you have similar experence ? Also i purchase (Protection,Control,Malware,URL Filtering) licence ,i find the the firepower mode didnt filter locker virus (like CryptoLocker,CBT locker),Can you give me some suggestion ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://ciscoskills.net/ &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2017-04-29 19:40:22&#34;&gt;Apr 6, 2017&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Gabriele, Never tried that command, that&#39;s a lot easier than what I was doing :) Thanks. Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://ciscoskills.net/ &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-11-09 21:24:39&#34;&gt;Nov 3, 2016&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Jimmy, I have not had experience upgrading to the FTD image for the ASAs and from what I can tell you may have to upgrade/download several things. I found this on Cisco website which may be a good starting point: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/firepower/quick&#34;&gt;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/firepower/quick&lt;/a&gt;_start/reimage/asa-ftd-reimage.html I have worked with the Firepower 4100 units which give you the option to use either ASA or an FTD image. I have been playing around with the FTD image and the ASA SFR module, they are different you really don&#39;t manage the device directly, it all works through the Firepower Management Center. Its interesting you&#39;re not having any luck with the filtering make sure if you are using the ASA image that you set up a service policy under the global policy to inspect all traffic with the SFR module and its not in monitor mode. You will also need to setup policies and rules in the FMC to block this type of traffic. Hope that helps :) Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[anon]( &#34;aasdsadf@asdfasfafds.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2017-07-19 20:56:08&#34;&gt;Jul 3, 2017&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should update your post at the top with this advice. I almost took the long path as well. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://ciscoskills.net/ &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2017-07-21 18:51:16&#34;&gt;Jul 5, 2017&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated, thanks Anon :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Gabriele]( &#34;ferrarigabriele84@gmail.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2017-04-26 09:08:26&#34;&gt;Apr 3, 2017&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try with the commands &amp;quot;connect local-mgmt&amp;quot; and then &amp;quot;erase configuration&amp;quot;. It should work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 5)</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2014/02/640-911-chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 19:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2014/02/640-911-chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/640-911-todd-lammle.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/640-911-todd-lammle.jpg?w=118&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Last week we covered chapter four which talked about the TCP/IP and the DoD models and what role they cover in networking as we learned that every application like FTP, DNS, DHCP depend on it. Like always post questions if you have any about the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Data-Center-Introducing-Networking/dp/1118661265/&#34;&gt;CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ll continue to cover  topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. Let&#39;s go over chapter five. **Overview: **I think we knew it was on the way, in this chapter we opened the door to IPv4 addressing. If this is your first time understanding IP addresses go over it carefully, this exam will cover it. Know the ranges of a Class A, B and C networks, where&#39;s the loopback? Also know the private IP class ranges of A, B and C. (RFC1918) Know the difference between broadcasts, unicast, and multicast addresses. We also got introduced into IPv6, know the address format, the short hand way to write an IPv6 address as well as the types of IPv6 addresses. (link-local, unicast, global unicast addresses, and unique local address) &lt;strong&gt;My thoughts:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have been around IPv4 addresses you might be good on this chapter, towards the end of the chapter I would look at IPv6, we don&#39;t talk about subnetting yet that&#39;s next week. :) Pretty short chapter this week post questions below if you have any on this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/07/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/07/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Discovery_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Discovery Protocol&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt;. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;router&lt;/a&gt; or switch is set up correctly  at least up to layer two in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt;. This also helps us discover &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; devices that are in are network and which &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interface_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Interface (computing)&#34;&gt;interfaces&lt;/a&gt; these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary  and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information&#34; title=&#34;Information&#34;&gt;information&lt;/a&gt; CDP gives out which helps you has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_administrator&#34; title=&#34;Network administrator&#34;&gt;network administrator&lt;/a&gt; build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet. So what is the purpose of CDP? CDP can gather device information from neighboring switches and routers without the need for a password. Like mentioned before this is great for troubleshooting a problem, discovering new devices that are not documented in your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_topology&#34; title=&#34;Network topology&#34;&gt;network topology&lt;/a&gt;, and verifying that each device is physically connected to the correct interfaces according to network documentation. CDP can discover the following details from neighboring devices that support CDP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Identifier: The hostname of the device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address List: Network and data-link addresses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local Interface: The interface on the switch or router issuing the command &lt;em&gt;Show CDP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port Identifier: Identifies the port used by the device to send CDP messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capabilities List: Information on what the device is like a router or a switch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platform: The model and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating_system&#34; title=&#34;Operating system&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/a&gt; running on the device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since CDP is enabled by default it does create a security risk, Cisco recommends that CDP be disabled on all interfaces that do not have need for it. You can disable CDP in two ways, by each interface with the sub-command &lt;em&gt;no cdp enable&lt;/em&gt; under the interface you wish to disable CDP. Or you can also disable CDP globally within the router or switch with the command &lt;em&gt;no cdp run&lt;/em&gt; under the configuration mode. That&#39;s just some general information about CDP and why CDP is useful. Although CDP could be a security risk it&#39;s still a helpful protocol to get some detailed information about your Cisco devices for inventory or to update your network topology. It can also be useful to just verify that the physical layer and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Link_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Data Link Layer&#34;&gt;data-link layer&lt;/a&gt; are working correctly for troubleshooting purposes. Like always I hope this information is informative and if you have an idea on the next topic that deals with wither ICND1 or ICND2 let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS Commands&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/&#34;&gt;Distance Vector Routing&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/ar/cisco-again-makes-ip-ngns-simpler-more-capable-less-costly/&#34;&gt;Cisco Again Makes IP NGNs Simpler, More Capable, Less Costly&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
