<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>switching on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/switching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in switching on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:05:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/switching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Passed 300-115</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/04/02/passed-300-115/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/04/02/passed-300-115/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just a short post about my recent Cisco exam, I was able to pass the 300-115 to renew all my lower CCNA certifications. The last time I took a Cisco exam was almost 3 years ago when I passed the CCNA Data Center certification. Overall the exam was fair although you will need multiple study resources to make sure you cover all the exam objectives. The primary reason for doing this exam first instead of ROUTE or TSHOOT was I felt it was maybe the hardest one?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 Alpha – Install and Setup</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/05/10/gns3-alpha-install-and-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 01:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/05/10/gns3-alpha-install-and-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So Alpha 3 came out last week with a bunch updates and I decided to give it run this week. I&#39;m not doing anything that difficult with the program so maybe I&#39;m not breaking it in all the way but I also was looking at some installation notes for Ubuntu and other Linux flavors, I figured I’ll try to install it on a Windows machine and not Linux (call me lazy) feel free to follow this guide.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 12 &amp; 13)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/19/640-911-chapter-12-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 16:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/19/640-911-chapter-12-13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are at the last chapters of the CCNA Data Center 640-911 by Todd Lammle. Chapter 12 talks about redundant switched technologies and chapter 13 talks about security. Just like before I will go over the high-points, so let’s get started!
Chapter 12 Overview: In this chapter we get to learn about Spanning Tree Protocol and some history with it. With networks we like multiple ways to a destination however in the layer two area redundancy does not play well and that’s where spanning tree can help us.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter-VLAN Routing on the Nexus 5k</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 15:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I previously had the chance to play around with the 5596UP switch, and made some notes on how to configure inter-vlan routing. Since this was a 5596UP switch I needed a layer 3 card to take advantage of it. The next-generation units the 5600 include layer 3 without a card required along with introducing 40GB uplinks! However in this post let&#39;s go back to the basics and configure inter-vlan routing on a nexus switch and in this case I am using a 5596UP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting FEX (5k to 2k)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/12/01/connecting-fex-5k-to-2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 15:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/12/01/connecting-fex-5k-to-2k/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was pretty excited to get my hands on some of the Cisco Nexus product line which focuses on switching in the data center. The gear I have is an evaluation unit so I made some notes and one thing I was impressed is how easy it is to connect a Nexus 5K to a Nexus 2k also known as a fabric extender. I have kept it simple as the gear I have is a single Nexus 5596 along with a single Nexus 224TP-E who needs redundancy right?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring EtherChannel (PAgb)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 15:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bundling physical links into one logical link is a common practice to up the bandwidth between switches, you may have this also configured on a server to bundle connections as well. In this tutorial I have two 2960 switches both of them trunking all VLANs on two gigabit ports. So in the end game is get 2gbps instead of 1gbps between switches while using Cisco’s proprietary protocol PAgb. It is important to remember that both of these protocols (PAgb and LACP) are link aggregation protocols only, their job is to make sure that EtherChannel is setup correctly by negotiating.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
