<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Certification on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/certification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Certification on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 04:15:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/certification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Changes on the Horizon - Cisco</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/06/11/changes-on-the-horizon-cisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 04:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/06/11/changes-on-the-horizon-cisco/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well we finally got an answer, Cisco is upping their Certifications and making some big changes. The CCNA track is taking a hit as all of the secondary exams under CCNA are being retired. If you are studying for any of these CCNA secondary exams keep in mind these won&#39;t transfer over after February 24th 2020. If you complete any current CCNA/CCDA certification before February 24, you’ll receive the new CCNA certification and a training badge in the corresponding technology area.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco VIRL is out ... for a price</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/12/05/cisco-virl-is-out-...-for-a-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 03:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/12/05/cisco-virl-is-out-...-for-a-price/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just wanted to put this up has Cisco has recently released VIRL. This is a network simulation platform that you can run Cisco operating systems on which are the same operating systems that run on Cisco hardware so anything you do in this simulation environment would be realistic if it was running on dedicated hardware. You would be able to test your changes before throwing them in production. Some things that are different between VIRL and CML (Cisco Modeling Labs)
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 10 &amp; 11)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 01:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just like before if you have followed, I have gone over the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle and in this post we cover two chapters. Feel free to comment below if you have any questions on either of these two chapters.
Chapter 10 Overview: Chapter 10 starts us back in the book, before we do any configuring and we learn about routing protocols, and remember the difference between static and dynamic routing (name implies it) Also know the default administrate distances of the different routing protocols (starts on page 297).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 7)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you made it past the earlier chapters this one should be interesting, like before I am going through each chapter of the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Comment below if you have questions in this chapter, last week we learned about subnetting and in this chapter we will learn about the NX-OS which is Cisco&#39;s Data Center switches. Let&#39;s begin! Overview: This was short chapter in introducing the NX-OS product line and into the virtualized enviroments that data centers are now becoming.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 5)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 19:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last week we covered chapter four which talked about the TCP/IP and the DoD models and what role they cover in networking as we learned that every application like FTP, DNS, DHCP depend on it. Like always post questions if you have any about the book CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I&#39;ll continue to cover topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 4)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 18:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off on Chapter 3 on CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Like before feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter three we discussed about Ethernet Technologies and in chapter four we will learn about the TCP/IP protocol which is fundamentally the protocol that makes the Internet work.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNP Security Refresh</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/03/ccnp-security-refresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 14:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/03/ccnp-security-refresh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco recently published its 2014 Annual Security Report, and some interesting data was captured in 2013. One of the details was a talent gap in network security and because of this gap Cisco has a major revision in the CCNP Security certification starting in April. Its estimated that in short term or already present is shortage of more than a million security professionals worldwide! Like mentioned because of this Cisco is reworking the CCNP Security track.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 3)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/30/640-911-chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 18:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/30/640-911-chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picking up were we left on off on a series of blog posts that follow the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter two we discussed about internetworking and in chapter three we will learn about Ethernet technologies.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 1)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/16/640-911-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 17:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/16/640-911-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I bought the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I have decided it would be a good idea to go over the topics of each chapter of this book in series of blog posts. The idea of this is to work together if on a study group, go over the topics in each chapter of the book, talk about examples and to get an idea of what the exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA 2-0 What&#39;s New?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/09/30/ccna-2-0-whats-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/09/30/ccna-2-0-whats-new/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I brought this topic up in March of this year (See original post) but I wanted to re-post it to add some information because as of today this was your last day to pass the older CCNA exams. Cisco has a refreshed all the CCNA Routing and Switching exams. That includes the ICND1 (640-822), the ICND2 (640-816), and the all in wonder exam (640-816). You will notice some old references no longer mentioned on this refresh, so let&#39;s go over the differences and some of the changes Cisco has made to the associate-level certification track.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Version 2.0 Refresh</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/03/26/ccna-version-2.0-refresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 05:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/03/26/ccna-version-2.0-refresh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I think we knew it was coming at some point and Cisco has recently announced a refresh for the 640-822 (ICND1), 640-816 (ICND2) and the all in one 640-802 (CCNA) the last day to take these tests and get certified are September 30th of 2013. You will notice some old references no longer mentioned on this refresh, so let&#39;s go over the differences and some of the changes Cisco has made to the associate-level certification track.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICND2 - Passed!</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 16:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I just passed my ICND2 exam, I&#39;m now CCNA certified!
This was a long road to travel over a year ago I passed ICND1 which I recived the CCENT certification but with just general life getting in the way I also saw my chance of getting CCNA status stepping further in the distance. If you read how I passed ICND1 will find that the way I studied for this exam was totally different from studying for the ICND1.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome CCT (Cisco Certified Technician Certification)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/09/21/welcome-cct-cisco-certified-technician-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/09/21/welcome-cct-cisco-certified-technician-certification/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Switching gears for today, Cisco has introduced a certification for onsite support technicians, who need product-specific technical skills to diagnose, restore, repair, and replace critical Cisco equipment. This certification which was introduced this summer now has questions about it from CLN (Cisco Learning Network) and other Cisco sites. So what is this new cert and any changes to ICND1 or ICND2? Short answer is no, this certification is on par with ICND1 or CCENT according to Cisco but is focused on support groups like TAC (Technical Assistance Center), NOC (Network Operations Centers) and 3rd party support.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I passed the ICND1 Exam</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well my first of the many Cisco certifications that I plan take in the future was a success! I was able to pass the ICND1 exam. This blog post is going to be a little different in that I want to share how I was able to pass this test and talk about my experience.
Well in January after finishing the Cisco Networking Academy in the Exploration series I wanted to go ahead and take shot at the ICND1 exam.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
