<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cisco Modeling Labs on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/cisco-modeling-labs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cisco Modeling Labs on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 03:45:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/cisco-modeling-labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cisco VIRL is out ... for a price</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/12/05/cisco-virl-is-out-...-for-a-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 03:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/12/05/cisco-virl-is-out-...-for-a-price/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just wanted to put this up has Cisco has recently released VIRL. This is a network simulation platform that you can run Cisco operating systems on which are the same operating systems that run on Cisco hardware so anything you do in this simulation environment would be realistic if it was running on dedicated hardware. You would be able to test your changes before throwing them in production. Some things that are different between VIRL and CML (Cisco Modeling Labs)
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Modeling Labs … Waiting</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/06/28/cisco-modeling-labs-waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 20:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/06/28/cisco-modeling-labs-waiting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just waiting for CML, (Cisco Modeling Labs) it’s been little over a month since going to Cisco Live in San Francisco and with all the information of next-generation hardware and security with Source Fire I was pretty beat with a lot of note taking and PowerPoint slides. However the last session on the last day of the Cisco Live talked about Cisco’s Modeling Lab program. I also tried it out in the Cisco DevNet area earlier in the week during Cisco Live and I was impressed with the product.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
