<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>operating systems on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/operating-systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in operating systems on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 04:58:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/operating-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Network Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/11/11/network-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 04:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/11/11/network-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/thinking.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/thinking.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The thing that makes networks awesome is the fact that once you setup a network you&#39;re not done. That may sound like a drawback but it is excellent job security! Engineers or administrators must watch the performance of an organization&#39;s network to make sure that productivity is not affected. Network outages can have a huge effect on an organization, lost revenue and the cost of unproductive employees can severely damage the organization, Earlier this year I also talked about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting Process&#34;&gt;troubleshooting process&lt;/a&gt; which goes hand in hand with network troubleshooting. One of the major things a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_administrator&#34; title=&#34;Network administrator&#34;&gt;network engineer&lt;/a&gt; or administrator needs to have is documentation of the network. That may sound like common sense and it is but with outdated documentation or no documentation at all makes it difficult to diagnose where the problem is and even more difficult if more help is needed from outside sources. Just with your computer, car and home, networks need to have a regular maintenance from time to time. Spending time on an operational network can improve its performance and uptime. Instead using the &amp;quot;duct tape&amp;quot; approach when outages occur. So we know documentation is important but it always seems to be on the backburner, &amp;quot;I&#39;ll get to it when there is time to burn&amp;quot; From my recent experience working with a hospital is that when things went down I had no idea where to start, the documentation was outdated twice over and let&#39;s just say the problem could have been fixed in 5 minutes instead of an hour. Needless to say I broke out &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Visio&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Visio&#34;&gt;Microsoft Visio&lt;/a&gt; and worked from the ground up. Having documentation is good idea but the kicker is to remember to update it when changes occur :). &lt;strong&gt;Simple problems are usually simple solutions&lt;/strong&gt;, we all have been there, a problem comes up 5 minutes before heading home and the problem itself is simple but for whatever reason the solution cannot be found. From my experience from troubleshooting labs and real world environments I have found that looking at the whole problem helps and take it one step at a time. For example a server or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_computer&#34; title=&#34;Personal computer&#34;&gt;PC&lt;/a&gt; no longer has &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_network&#34; title=&#34;Access network&#34;&gt;network access&lt;/a&gt;, does another PC or server that&#39;s on the same network able to use the resources needed? Continue to use the Troubleshooting Process and ask those simple questions until the solution is found. &lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t cover your tracks!&lt;/strong&gt; I have done this couple of times myself, when configuring a device like a router, switch, firewall etc. no matter how simple the configuration change seems to be always, copy the commands to a text file after you configured the device. Or better yet copy the commands to a text document first, read it through to make sure it seems correct and if something fails reverse the command. &lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t copy-run start!&lt;/strong&gt; This kind of goes with the one above but this method has saved me in some sketchy areas. When I take an already working device and throw some extra commands on it and now it disconnects from the network making an already problem worse than before. A simple reload or a pull of a power plug brings the device up before I made those changes. Once I have confirmed that those commands worked I then issue the famous copy run start command. &lt;strong&gt;Monitor your network,&lt;/strong&gt; How do you know what &amp;quot;normal&amp;quot; looks like when you have nothing looking at it? There are tons of paid and free tools to help you find that &amp;quot;normal&amp;quot; network load. So when something happens outside of normal you know about it. Some tools that I have worked with are &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paessler_Router_Traffic_Grapher&#34; title=&#34;Paessler Router Traffic Grapher&#34;&gt;PRTG&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi_Router_Traffic_Grapher&#34; title=&#34;Multi Router Traffic Grapher&#34;&gt;MRTG&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syslog&#34; title=&#34;Syslog&#34;&gt;Syslog&lt;/a&gt; servers like Kiwi Syslog, I have also heard of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nagios&#34; title=&#34;Nagios&#34;&gt;Nagios&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whatsupgold.com/&#34; title=&#34;WhatsUp Gold&#34;&gt;WhatsUp Gold&lt;/a&gt;, and much more. A simple search will point you in the right direction ;). I hope this information is helpful when troubleshooting networks because although it can be a headache sometimes it&#39;s my favorite part of the job. If you have any ideas for the next topic that deals with either ICND1 or ICND2 you can always comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/wireless/tablets-welcomed-won%e2%80%99t-byod-increase-my-device-troubleshooting-costs/&#34;&gt;Tablets Welcomed. Won&#39;t BYOD increase my device troubleshooting costs?&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/&#34;&gt;The Codes of ICMP&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prweb.com/releases/2010/03/prweb3712464.htm&#34;&gt;Ipswitch WhatsUp Gold Receives Network Products Guide 2010 Product Innovation Award in Network Management&lt;/a&gt; (prweb.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Discovery_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Discovery Protocol&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt;. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;router&lt;/a&gt; or switch is set up correctly  at least up to layer two in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt;. This also helps us discover &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; devices that are in are network and which &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interface_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Interface (computing)&#34;&gt;interfaces&lt;/a&gt; these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary  and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information&#34; title=&#34;Information&#34;&gt;information&lt;/a&gt; CDP gives out which helps you has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_administrator&#34; title=&#34;Network administrator&#34;&gt;network administrator&lt;/a&gt; build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet. So what is the purpose of CDP? CDP can gather device information from neighboring switches and routers without the need for a password. Like mentioned before this is great for troubleshooting a problem, discovering new devices that are not documented in your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_topology&#34; title=&#34;Network topology&#34;&gt;network topology&lt;/a&gt;, and verifying that each device is physically connected to the correct interfaces according to network documentation. CDP can discover the following details from neighboring devices that support CDP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Identifier: The hostname of the device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address List: Network and data-link addresses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local Interface: The interface on the switch or router issuing the command &lt;em&gt;Show CDP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port Identifier: Identifies the port used by the device to send CDP messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capabilities List: Information on what the device is like a router or a switch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platform: The model and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating_system&#34; title=&#34;Operating system&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/a&gt; running on the device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since CDP is enabled by default it does create a security risk, Cisco recommends that CDP be disabled on all interfaces that do not have need for it. You can disable CDP in two ways, by each interface with the sub-command &lt;em&gt;no cdp enable&lt;/em&gt; under the interface you wish to disable CDP. Or you can also disable CDP globally within the router or switch with the command &lt;em&gt;no cdp run&lt;/em&gt; under the configuration mode. That&#39;s just some general information about CDP and why CDP is useful. Although CDP could be a security risk it&#39;s still a helpful protocol to get some detailed information about your Cisco devices for inventory or to update your network topology. It can also be useful to just verify that the physical layer and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Link_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Data Link Layer&#34;&gt;data-link layer&lt;/a&gt; are working correctly for troubleshooting purposes. Like always I hope this information is informative and if you have an idea on the next topic that deals with wither ICND1 or ICND2 let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS Commands&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/&#34;&gt;Distance Vector Routing&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/ar/cisco-again-makes-ip-ngns-simpler-more-capable-less-costly/&#34;&gt;Cisco Again Makes IP NGNs Simpler, More Capable, Less Costly&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) via SDM</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 17:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Awhile back I talked about the differences between IPS and IDS. (See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs-ips/&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IDS vs. IPS&#34;&gt;Cisco IDS vs. IPS&lt;/a&gt; ) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure an IPS (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intrusion_prevention_system&#34; title=&#34;Intrusion prevention system&#34;&gt;Intrusion Prevention System&lt;/a&gt;) on a router using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface&#34; title=&#34;Graphical user interface&#34;&gt;GUI&lt;/a&gt; for Cisco &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;routers&lt;/a&gt; this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. ( See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/14/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34; title=&#34;Configure Cisco SDM&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM&lt;/a&gt;) Let&#39;s start configuring an IPS with SDM! This tutorial is assuming that the configurations to set up Cisco SDM have already been completed. For this tutorial all we want to focus on is configuring the IPS. Since this using Cisco SDM the IPS wizard is pretty easy to understand. Before we get started I like to have the Cisco SDM preview the commands before I deliver them to the router. To do that at the top of the menu bar click &lt;em&gt;Edit&lt;/em&gt; and select &lt;em&gt;Preferences&lt;/em&gt; a new window will appear (Like below) and verify that the &lt;em&gt;Preview commands before delivering to the router&lt;/em&gt; is checked.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/preview_commandse/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/preview_commandse.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM Preferences&#34; title=&#34;Preview_Commands&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Before we even jump into the IPS wizard we must verify that we have the IOS IPS signature package file and the public crypto key. If you don&#39;t have them you then must have a CCO account with Cisco to download them. Make sure that these files are available on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_computer&#34; title=&#34;Personal computer&#34;&gt;PC&lt;/a&gt; along with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trivial_File_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Trivial File Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;TFTP&lt;/a&gt; server installed and running. Put or verify that the IOS IPS signature file is in the default TFTP folder (IOS-Sxxx-CLI.pkg) Remember that the X values will vary depending on the file that was download from Cisco. Also verify that the realm-cisco.pub.key.txt file is available on the computer and note its location. This file is the public key that it used by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; IPS. Once Cisco SDM is opened click the configure button at the top of SDM screen and select &lt;em&gt;Intrusion Prevention&lt;/em&gt; on the left hand side under &lt;strong&gt;Tasks&lt;/strong&gt;. Click or verify that the &lt;em&gt;Create IPS&lt;/em&gt; tab is selected and select the &lt;em&gt;Launch IPS Rule Wizard&lt;/em&gt; button. If prompted for &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_Device_Event_Exchange&#34; title=&#34;Security Device Event Exchange&#34;&gt;SDEE&lt;/a&gt; click ok. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_maine/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_maine.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Main Screen&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Main&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  A window will show, the IPS Welcome Screen which gives the objectives the wizard will go over in helping us create an IPS system. Click Next.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_welcomee/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_welcomee.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizared Welcome Page&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Welcome&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The next screen (IPS Interface) will want us to select which interface(s) will have the IPS rules, select either inbound or outbound. (For this tutorial both &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_Ethernet&#34; title=&#34;Fast Ethernet&#34;&gt;Fast-Ethernet&lt;/a&gt; 0/0&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Serial 0/0&lt;/em&gt; will have the IPS rules inbound.) Click Next.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_interfacese/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_interfacese.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Interfaces&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Interfaces&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The next screen (Signature File and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public-key_cryptography&#34; title=&#34;Public-key cryptography&#34;&gt;Public Key&lt;/a&gt;) wants to know the following information, the location of the signature file and the public key.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_sig_pub_key/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_sig_pub_key.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Signature Public Key&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Sig_Pub_Key&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Focusing on the signature file first you want to specify the location where the signature file is. Click on the three dots button.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_sigfilee/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_sigfilee.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Signature File&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_SigFile&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Another window will open (Specify Signature File) if the signature file is already on the routers flash memory select the first radio button, if the signature file is by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Locator&#34; title=&#34;Uniform Resource Locator&#34;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; select the correct protocol and address, you can also specify the signature file on the PC. (For this tutorial we are using the TFTP server and are specifying the signature file by URL, once the location of the file has been selected click OK. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_sigfile_spe/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_sigfile_spe.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Signature File Location&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_SigFile_SP&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Now let&#39;s focus on the Public Key, in the name of the public key type realm-cisco.pub or relam-cisco.pub signature. Find and open the realm-cisco.pub.key.txt file and copy (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Control-C&#34; title=&#34;Control-C&#34;&gt;Ctrl-C&lt;/a&gt;) the text that is between the phrase key-string and the word quit. Paste the text (key) in the key field in the Configure Key section. Click Next. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_public_keye/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_public_keye.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Public Key&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Public_Key&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The next section (Config Location and Category) wants you to specify where you want the IPS configuration files click on the three dots and choose your location. (For this tutorial we are using flash to store the IPS configuration) Towards the bottom of the screen the wizard wants to choose a signature category for the router. (For this tutorial we are choosing the advanced option.) Click Next. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_config_locatione/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_config_locatione.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Config Location&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Config_Location&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The next section is the summary window for the IPS configuration, here you can look over the summary to verify the configuration. Click Finish. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_summarye/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_summarye.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Summary&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Summary&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; If you&#39;ve selected the option to preview commands before delivering them to the router, a final window will appear. In this window you can see the actual commands the SDM program will attempt to deliver. You have the option to save the running-configuration to the startup-configuration after the commands complete. You also have the option to save the configuration as a file and finally you can deliver them to the router. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/ips_wizard_delivere/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/ips_wizard_delivere.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM IPS Wizard Deliver&#34; title=&#34;IPS_Wizard_Deliver&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; That&#39;s it! believe it or not that&#39;s the SDM configuration of IOS IPS you can get more information at Cisco&#39;s website about SDM and the configuration settings. Like always I hope this tutorial was informative and if you have a suggestion on the next topic that relates to ICND1 or ICND2 and even some CCNA Security comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/smallbusiness/help-keep-company-data-safe-on-employees-personal-devices-2/&#34;&gt;Help Keep Company Data Safe on Employees&#39; Personal Devices&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcworld.com/article/225387/digital_threats_jumped_in_2010.html&#34;&gt;Digital Threats Jumped in 2010&lt;/a&gt; (pcworld.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/security/defending-against-sql-injection-attacks-using-cisco-asa-ips-and-ios-firewall-cisco-tac-security-podcast/&#34;&gt;Defending against SQL Injection attacks using Cisco ASA, IPS, and IOS Firewall - Cisco TAC Security Podcast&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.forbes.com/andygreenberg/2011/04/12/study-finds-firewalls-from-cisco-fortinet-others-vulnerable-to-old-attack/&#34;&gt;Study Finds Firewalls From Cisco, Fortinet, Others Vulnerable To Old Attack&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.forbes.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Zone Based Firewalls via SDM</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 15:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Last month I talked about the fundamentals for understanding zone based &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firewall_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Firewall (computing)&#34;&gt;firewalls&lt;/a&gt; (See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/&#34; title=&#34;Understanding Zone Based Firewalls&#34;&gt;Understanding Zone Based Firewalls&lt;/a&gt;). So for today&#39;s post I want to go ahead and talk about configuring the zone based firewalls but with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web&#34; title=&#34;World Wide Web&#34;&gt;Web&lt;/a&gt;-based device management tool a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface&#34; title=&#34;Graphical user interface&#34;&gt;GUI&lt;/a&gt; for Cisco &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;routers&lt;/a&gt; this can simplify router deployments and reduce ownership costs. (See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/14/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34; title=&#34;Configure Cisco SDM&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM&lt;/a&gt;) Instead of talking about what is zone based firewalls lets jump into the configuration of them. This &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tutorial&#34; title=&#34;Tutorial&#34;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; is assuming that the configurations to set up Cisco SDM have already been completed. For this tutorial all we want to focus on is configuring zone based firewalls. Since this using Cisco SDM the firewall wizard is pretty effortless. Before we get started I like to have the Cisco SDM preview the commands before I deliver them to the router. To do that at the top of the menu bar click &lt;em&gt;Edit&lt;/em&gt; and select &lt;em&gt;Preferences&lt;/em&gt; a new window will appear (Like below) and verify that the &lt;em&gt;Preview commands before delivering to the router&lt;/em&gt; is checked.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/preview_commandse.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/preview_commandse.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;SDM Preferences&#34; title=&#34;Preview_Commands&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Now that we are ready to go, the first thing we need to do is select the Configure button at the top, and to the left hand-side under tasks select the Firewall and ACL option. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall-acle/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall-acle.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Firewall and ACL Page&#34; title=&#34;Firewall ACL&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You now have to decide what type of firewall you want to configure and launch the wizard, the main difference between the basic firewall option and the advanced firewall option is you have the option to support a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DMZ_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;DMZ (computing)&#34;&gt;DMZ&lt;/a&gt; zone. The basic firewall set up does not support DMZ. (For this tutorial we are going to be using the basic firewall option) &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall_wizarde/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall_wizarde.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Basic Firewall Wizard&#34; title=&#34;Firewall_Wizard&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A new window will show, the Firewall Wizard and will explain what the selected firewall option will do. Click on the next button. The next area is going to be asking what interface is considered to be the outside (untrusted network) and the inside (trusted network). In the advanced firewall wizard you have an extra option the DMZ. For this tutorial we are using the basic firewall wizard and are selecting the serial interface has the untrusted (outside) network. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_Ethernet&#34; title=&#34;Fast Ethernet&#34;&gt;Fast-Ethernet&lt;/a&gt; interface has the trusted (inside) network. Click Next. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall_wizard_interfacee/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall_wizard_interfacee.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Basic Firewall Interface Wizard&#34; title=&#34;Firewall_Wizard_Interface&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; In the basic firewall wizard the nest section is the security configuration, depending on your type of security. Move the slider to the choice that best fits, you can also preview the commands by selecting the Preview Commands button to verify the commands before choosing them. (For this tutorial I selected the Low Security option) Click Next &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall_wizard_securitye/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall_wizard_securitye.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Basic Firewall Wizard Security&#34; title=&#34;Firewall_Wizard_Security&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The final section is the summary for the basic firewall configuration, here you can look over the summary to verify the configuration. Click Finish. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall_wizard_summarye/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall_wizard_summarye.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Basic Firewall Summary&#34; title=&#34;Firewall_Wizard_Summary&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; If you&#39;ve selected the option to preview commands before delivering them to the router, a final window will appear. In this window you can see the real commands the SDM program will attempt to deliver. You have the option to save the running-configuration to the startup-configuration after the commands complete. You also have the option to save the configuration as a file and finally you can deliver them to the router.&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/firewall_wizard_deliverye/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/firewall_wizard_deliverye.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Firewall Delivery&#34; title=&#34;Firewall_Wizard_Delivery&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Believe it or not that&#39;s the SDM configuration of a zone-based firewall you can get more information at Cisco&#39;s website about SDM and the configuration settings. Like always I hope this tutorial was informative and if you have a suggestion on the next topic that relates to ICND1 or ICND2 and even some &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Career_Certifications&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Career Certifications&#34;&gt;CCNA Security&lt;/a&gt; comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/&#34;&gt;Understanding Zone Based Firewalls&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brighthub.com/computing/smb-security/articles/63980.aspx&#34;&gt;Configuring Cisco Router Firewall through Command Prompt&lt;/a&gt; (brighthub.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcworld.com/article/225115/firewall_vendors_challenge_findings_of_nss_labs_report.html&#34;&gt;Firewall Vendors Challenge Findings of NSS Labs Report&lt;/a&gt; (pcworld.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nsslabs.blogspot.com/2011/04/enterprise-network-firewalls-leak.html&#34;&gt;Enterprise Network Firewalls Leak&lt;/a&gt; (nsslabs.blogspot.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcworld.com/article/225136/firewall_security_issue_raised_in_report_ignites_vendors_ire.html&#34;&gt;Firewall Security Issue Raised in Report Angers Vendors&lt;/a&gt; (pcworld.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firemon.com/blog/security-management&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Security Needs Management | FireMon Blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-04-21 12:35:30&#34;&gt;Apr 4, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configuring Zone Based Firewalls via SDM (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Process</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/thinking.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/thinking.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today&#39;s post is going to be talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Troubleshooting&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting&#34;&gt;troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; and where to start the troubleshooting process. Yes there is an actual process that every technician should be aware of. You can also use this troubleshooting process at home, you may not know how to fix it but at least you know where the issue is and find someone who can.  Before we begin if you haven&#39;t seen yet, let me introduce to you the troubleshooting process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to gather information about the problem. (What happened?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep it simple, verify the obvious issues FIRST! (Is the device powered on?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try some quick solutions first (restart, reinstall, verify connections)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gather information from the device (Device Manger, if you are in routers or switches use &amp;quot;Show&amp;quot; commands and &amp;quot;Debug&amp;quot; commands)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your research skills! Evaluate the problem and try possible solutions. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet&#34; title=&#34;Internet&#34;&gt;Internet&lt;/a&gt; searches, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_forum&#34; title=&#34;Internet forum&#34;&gt;Online Forums&lt;/a&gt;, past experiences etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally keep note of what you did even if you did not fix the issue. (Keep an engineer notebook!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may look simple, and it is! This is the exact method I use when troubleshooting a problem. Troubleshooting is a hard skill to have, as you really can&#39;t learn from it in a book. You have to have experience with the type of technology you&#39;re working with. One thing I use all the time is my research skills this can be a life saver if you know what to look for, use key details! The internet can be helpful but putting generic terms like &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_XP&#34; title=&#34;Windows XP&#34;&gt;windows XP&lt;/a&gt; is not working&amp;quot; will not help you but instead waste your time. Use the key terms when have an issue like an error code, type the error message, describe what you can&#39;t do, etc. Chances are somebody somewhere has had the same problem or at least something like it and decided to post it. Another thing I like to do when checking on a problem is going to the source! Although there are helpful places around web like forums, and chat systems I usually use this last. If I am having a problem with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Windows&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Windows&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; for example I&#39;ll go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; Support. Same thing if I have an issue with a Cisco product I&#39;ll go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; Support webpage before I go and search my problem around the web. Finally remember ask other technicians if they have seen the problem. By using these steps and guidelines will be able to become better at troubleshooting like before it&#39;s something you can&#39;t learn from a book you must have experience with technology before you can even start troubleshooting. My last word of advice is keeping a record! Write down the steps you did, why did them and what where the solutions to the problem? If you couldn&#39;t figure it still write it down. That way if the issue occurs again you and other people know exactly how to fix the problem or also know what solutions not work last time and not waste any of your time, like always I hope this information was informative and if you have an idea about the next ICND1 or ICND2 topic comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Zone Based Firewalls</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Earlier we talked about using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context-based_access_control&#34; title=&#34;Context-based access control&#34;&gt;CBAC&lt;/a&gt; (See the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/&#34; title=&#34;Understanding CBAC&#34;&gt;Understanding CBAC&lt;/a&gt;) the &amp;quot;classic firewall&amp;quot; and we mention some information about zone based &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firewall_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Firewall (computing)&#34;&gt;firewalls&lt;/a&gt; but not nearly enough. So today we will be talking about zone based firewalls. Why are they different? We also will learn the basics about what is zone based and what are the advantages compared to CBAC. You can think of zone based has making &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interface_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Interface (computing)&#34;&gt;interfaces&lt;/a&gt; in a quarantine zone, each interface by default if set up in a zone is denied access to any other interface. This helps isolate networks that have private and or secure information that does not need the public network to have access to it. The firewall policies are configured using the Cisco Common Classification Policy Language (C3PL), this uses a hierarchical structure to define &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communications_protocol&#34; title=&#34;Communications protocol&#34;&gt;network protocol&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inspection&#34; title=&#34;Inspection&#34;&gt;inspection&lt;/a&gt; and allows network devices to be grouped under one inspection policy. Believe it or not it should be easier to configure zone based firewall compared to CBAC Remember that CBAC has these limitations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By having multiple inspection policies and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control_list&#34; title=&#34;Access control list&#34;&gt;ACLs&lt;/a&gt; on several interfaces on a router makes it difficult and sometimes overwhelming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All traffic through a given interface is subject to the same inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CBAC relies too heavily on ACLs, which can only do so much!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using zones that borders a network the traffic is inspected by the policy restrictions. These restrictions can be different in each zone or interface. Using the zone based approach does have its benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Zone Based firewall is not dependent on ACLs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The router security posture is to block unless explicitly allowed. CBAC allows everything unless explicitly denied or checked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Policies are easy to read and troubleshoot with C3PL. (Cisco Common Classification Policy Language)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One policy affects any given traffic, instead of needing multiple ACLs, inspection actions and rules that CBAC would need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important note when deciding to implement CBAC or Zone based is that either models can be enabled on the router simultaneously. They however cannot be used on the same interface as a router. There are three actions the zone based firewall can take when looking at traffic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect - This action is like the CBAC ip inspect command. It automatically allows for return traffic and potential &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Control_Message_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Control Message Protocol&#34;&gt;ICMP&lt;/a&gt; messages. For protocols requiring multiple parallel signaling and data sessions (such as, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;File Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;FTP&lt;/a&gt; or H.323), the inspect action also handles the proper establishment of data sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drop - To a deny statement in an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anterior_cruciate_ligament&#34; title=&#34;Anterior cruciate ligament&#34;&gt;ACL&lt;/a&gt;. A log option is also available to log the rejected packets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pass - To a permit statement in an ACL. The pass action does not track the state of connections or sessions within the traffic. Pass allows the traffic only in one direction. A corresponding policy must be applied to allow return traffic to pass in the opposite direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When determining how to set up zone-based firewalls the first thing you need to think of is the different zones that need to be implemented. The infrastructure must be split into separate zones with different security levels. Example the public network or internet to the inside network would be split into two zones. Create the zones for the firewall with the &lt;em&gt;zone security&lt;/em&gt; command.&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/zone-based/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/zone-based.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Zone Based Firewall&#34; title=&#34;zone-based&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You also have to set up policies between the zones. Remember by default when zones are configured they deny all access to any other zone as well has non-zone interfaces. You must define the type of traffic that will be allowed on the zone. Example would be &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transmission_Control_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Transmission Control Protocol&#34;&gt;TCP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_Datagram_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;User Datagram Protocol&#34;&gt;UDP&lt;/a&gt; sessions which are the most common, but there is also ICMP and others that can be defined. You want to define the traffic classes with the &lt;em&gt;class-map type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command.  After the zones have been identified along with the traffic requirements between them, the next thing to do is design the physical infrastructure and policies this would be stating the number of devices between the mission-critical devices and least critical devices and determining redundant routes and devices if any. You would specify the firewall policies with the &lt;em&gt;policy-map type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command. Define the class-map name and you want that policy to do? Do you want the policy to pass, inspect or drop the traffic specified by the class-map?  You want to apply the firewall policies the source and destination zones, by using the &lt;em&gt;zone-pair security&lt;/em&gt; command. What zone is the source? What zone is the destination? What policy-map are you going to use by using the &lt;em&gt;service-policy type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command.  The last setup is to identify a subset within zones and merge the traffic; the technician must identify the connected interfaces and apply that zone to the interface, by using the &lt;em&gt;zone-member security&lt;/em&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To recap, you must create a zone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then define the type of traffic that will be checked by the policy by using the &lt;em&gt;class-map type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, is define the firewall policies by using the &lt;em&gt;policy-map type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command. You what do you want to do with that traffic that you specified earlier with the class-maps (Pass, inspect or drop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign the policy-maps to the zone pairs, tell the router which policy is the source and destination by using the &lt;em&gt;zone-pair security&lt;/em&gt; command. Tell the router which policy to use by using the &lt;em&gt;service-policy type inspect&lt;/em&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally apply that zone-pair to the interface by using the &lt;em&gt;zone-member security&lt;/em&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the rundown of zone-based firewalls! Look complex? If you start to understand it you will find it easier to carry out than CBAC. Zone-based helps keep interfaces apart by blocking all traffic unless allowed by the policies. Like before you can always find more information online. I recommend Cisco.com for a full understanding of zone-based policy firewall, I hope this tutorial was helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cracking WEP</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/14/cracking-wep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2011 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/14/cracking-wep/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BackTrack&#34; title=&#34;BackTrack&#34;&gt;BackTrack&lt;/a&gt; is Linux  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_security&#34; title=&#34;Network security&#34;&gt;network security&lt;/a&gt; audit tool for security professionals. This tool is used for testing and penetrating networks. That being said** This tutorial is for educational use only. This is meant only to teach that WEP is an insecure option, and is recommend to use a harder encryption. Using this tutorial on a network that you do not have permission to access or is not yours, could be illegal! ** This was tested on BackTrack version 4 and the steps outlined in this tutorial were successful. (this tutorial is assuming that you have BackTrack 4 installed and are ready with a shell prompt)  The first thing you want to do is start your wireless interface in most cases this is wlan0 [code]airmon-ng start wlan0[/code] In the output look for the monitor interface in most cases this is mon0   The next thing you want to do is copy down the target AP&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Service_set_%28802.11_network%29&#34; title=&#34;Service set (802.11 network)&#34;&gt;ESSID&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MAC_address&#34; title=&#34;MAC address&#34;&gt;MAC address&lt;/a&gt; of the AP,  also copy down the channel of the target AP.  [code]airodump-ng mon0[/code] There must be a client or clients using the AP if not you can&#39;t crack it. Match the MAC address of the AP to the available clients you have listed.   Next only output what you want (for example I have an AP on channel 8 and that MAC address of the AP is 00:dd:aa:cc:88:33 and it&#39;s out monitor 0) the command would be:       [code]airodump-ng --channel 8 --write output --bssid 00:dd:aa:cc:88:33 mon0[/code] (Open a new shell prompt) The next step is you want to associate your wireless card with the AP(for example I have the AP&#39;s MAC and ESSID (which is test) and my wireless MAC address (which is aa:00:55:bb:DD:FF) the command would look like:       [code]aireplay-ng -1 0 -e test -a 00:dd:aa:cc:88:33 -h aa:00:55:bb:DD:FF[/code]   (Open a new shell prompt) The next step is start the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Packet_injection&#34; title=&#34;Packet injection&#34;&gt;packet injection&lt;/a&gt; (for example you will need the target AP&#39;s MAC address (which is 00:dd:aa:cc:88:33 and my(yours) wireless MAC address (which is 00:55:bb:DD:FF) the command would look like:       [code]aireplay-ng -3 -b 00:dd:aa:cc:88:33 -h 00:55:bb:DD:FF mon0[/code]   (Open a new shell prompt) The final step depends were the outputs are saved and the name of the output (for this example they were on /root and the name of the file was output-01.cap) so the command would look like:     [code]aircrack-ng output-01.cap[/code] Again this depends were the file was saved it could be in a different location. But after that command aircrack will attempt to crack the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wired_Equivalent_Privacy&#34; title=&#34;Wired Equivalent Privacy&#34;&gt;WEP key&lt;/a&gt; it will tell you that it either failed or if it was able to find it. (If it does fail wait for more packets and try again.)   The way aircrack works is that it reads the packet injection file, (this file is continues to update as packets move across the network) aircrack then finds the common key because that key is sent back and forth in the network. Depending on how active the network is aircrack is able to find the key in less than a minute!   Keep in mind when I was setting this up on a test AP I did run into some difficulties, although cracking a WEP key is relatively easy it still took me some time in troubleshooting. I hope this tutorial is helpful, you can find more information at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&lt;/a&gt; Also check my tutorial on &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/&#34; title=&#34;Install BackTrack&#34;&gt;Installing BackTrack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install BackTrack</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 18:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp3/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is a full install of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34; title=&#34;BackTrack&#34;&gt;BackTrack&lt;/a&gt; 4 this can be in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_machine&#34; title=&#34;Virtual machine&#34;&gt;virtual machine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi_boot&#34; title=&#34;Multi boot&#34;&gt;dual-boot&lt;/a&gt;, or the main &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating_system&#34; title=&#34;Operating system&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/a&gt;. So you burned the image that you downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&lt;/a&gt;  and are ready to go! If not I would recommend you do that first. BackTrack is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kernel.org/&#34; title=&#34;Linux&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; penetration testing for network security. This is a free tool that IT administrators can use to audit their network.   First put the disk into the tray and restart your computer. This depends on your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BIOS&#34; title=&#34;BIOS&#34;&gt;BIOS setup&lt;/a&gt; but you can either set the boot order or go into a boot menu and select the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compact_Disc&#34; title=&#34;Compact Disc&#34;&gt;CD&lt;/a&gt; tray as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Booting&#34; title=&#34;Booting&#34;&gt;boot device&lt;/a&gt;.  This is the first thing you will see when you boot into BackTrack you can play around with the different options later but select the screen resolution that is close to your screen size.   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/backtrack-1/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/backtrack-1.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrack Main&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Once you select the option you want you will see a loading page, this can take some time so be patient!   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/backtrack-load/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/backtrack-load.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrackLoad&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Once backtrack is done loading then you can start from there and have fun with command-line but if your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Command-line_interface&#34; title=&#34;Command-line interface&#34;&gt;CLI&lt;/a&gt; skills are a little rusty then you can go into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface&#34; title=&#34;Graphical user interface&#34;&gt;GUI&lt;/a&gt; by typing &lt;em&gt;startx&lt;/em&gt; and hit enter. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/backtrack-loadst/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/backtrack-loadst.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrack loadst&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; From here you can run BackTrack now (it’s called a Live CD) &lt;em&gt;this could be useful if you just want to look at it and play around with settings that you have no idea what they are or do. That why if you mess something up you can always restart and go back into it without it saving anything!&lt;/em&gt; But let’s install this thing! Click on the Install.sh icon.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/install-shell/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/install-shell.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;install shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  This next window is the installer, it is pretty simple to understand, you want to select your location that is in the same time-zone as you.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp1/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp1.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Install Page 1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  This next window is the keyboard layout, Usually USA works for me. &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp2/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp2.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;install page 2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  This next page is the partition manager thing, from here you can dual-boot if you have another OS. (You want to be careful if you do have another OS on the hardrive because you can wipe your other OS from here) For this example I am taking the whole drive.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp3.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;install page 3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  The next page gives you a review before you start installing BackTrack this is also a good time to make sure everything is set up properly before you install BackTrack &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp4/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp4.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;installpage 4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  After you click install the installer will start installing!! (amazing! right!) Here you can watch the bar go across the screen or do something productive in this timeframe it takes about 20 to 30 minutes but this also depends on the hardware you have.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btinstallp5/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btinstallp5.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;installpage 5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  After it finishes it gives you two options, stay on the live CD or reboot to start BackTrack. &lt;em&gt;(Hint: reboot)&lt;/em&gt;   Once the machine is rebooting it will take some time so be patient as it is loading. Once it is ready it will ask you for your username and password. The username is &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt; and the password is &lt;em&gt;toor .&lt;/em&gt; Once you type that you&#39;re in CLI again, if you want to go to the GUI just type &lt;em&gt;startx&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btstart/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btstart.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrack start&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   Once you type &lt;em&gt;startx&lt;/em&gt; it will load the GUI and you now have a full install of BackTrack! From here you can go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to audit your network.&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/btstartdesk/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/btstartdesk.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;backtrackdesk&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I hope this tutorial was helpful&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intel Thunderbolt</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/28/intel-thunderbolt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/28/intel-thunderbolt/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intel_Corporation&#34; title=&#34;Intel Corporation&#34;&gt;Intel&lt;/a&gt; announced on Friday (February 25th 2011) the new high speed connector that will coexists with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Serial_Bus&#34; title=&#34;Universal Serial Bus&#34;&gt;USB 3.0&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Inc.&#34; title=&#34;Apple Inc.&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; also announced that it will be appearing first on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MacBook_Pro&#34; title=&#34;MacBook Pro&#34;&gt;MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt;. Thunderbolt known before has &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_Peak&#34; title=&#34;Light Peak&#34;&gt;Light Peak&lt;/a&gt; is a new high-speed PC connection &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technology&#34; title=&#34;Technology&#34;&gt;technology&lt;/a&gt;. This cable can combine data and high-definition all in one cable running at 10Gbps. So you could say it is like the all in wonder &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HDMI&#34; title=&#34;HDMI&#34;&gt;HDMI cable&lt;/a&gt; that combines video and audio into one cable. How fast is 10Gbps? Well if you had a full length HD movie so on average 120 minutes it would be able to transfer that movie in less than 30 seconds!! Although the codename was called Light Peak Intel Is running the new technology as an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electric_current&#34; title=&#34;Electric current&#34;&gt;electrical current&lt;/a&gt; based on copper. Intel has said that it will work and move the technology over to optical but not schedule has been released yet. This Thunderbolt technology will not replace USB 3.0 according to Jason Ziller, an Intel manager, &amp;quot;They will co-exist on the same platform...in terms of storage (devices) we&#39;ll see both products on the market&amp;quot;. You can read more information at Intel&#39;s website in the press room about the Thunderbolt Technology. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://newsroom.intel.com/community/intel_newsroom/blog/2011/02/24/thunderbolt-technology-the-fastest-data-connection-to-your-pc-just-arrived?cid=rss-258152-c1-264729&#34;&gt;Thunderbolt Technology: The Fastest Data Connection to Your PC Just Arrived&lt;/a&gt;) This technology is pretty cool, but the question is will it take off. Consumers have to buy it in order for it to be a success. Also Apple kind of took the product, although Apple did have some say in the Thunderbolt Technology it feels like at least for now that only Apple will have this. I am throwing a guess that other manufactures are waiting to see if this is a hit or a flop. What do think? Comment below!&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistency on Linux</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/04/persistency-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 16:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/04/persistency-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Many popular Linux OS can be installed on USB, and have persistency (Data and or settings) saved on that USB. So in the end you have a “almost installed” OS on your USB. This tutorial focuses on BackTrack but you can put other Linux OS like, Ubuntu, Fedora, Debian, Open SUSE, and many more can be used as well. First and the easiest way I found was running a program called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxliveusb.com/&#34;&gt;Linux Live USB Creator&lt;/a&gt;. This program can put together a LiveUSB (in which data cannot be saved, like a Live CD) or also put persistency on (which allows you to save file and settings). The only thing you can’t usually do with a persistency system is update system settings, and sometimes installing additional software. This program can also put up a portable Virtual Box so you don’t have to restart your system to use it. So the first thing to do is to download and install Linux Live USB Creator, follow the simple setup information to install Linux Live After you install Linux Live you can start-up the program and choose your USB drive.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/04/persistency-on-linux/lili-usb/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/lili-usb.png?w=90&#34; alt=&#34;Linux Live USB Program&#34; title=&#34;Linux Live USB Program&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Next choose the source of the .iso file, you can even download the .iso from here as well. For this example I was trying out BackTrack 4, So I selected backtrack. (Many other Linux OS are available)   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/04/persistency-on-linux/source/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/source.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;ISO Source File&#34; title=&#34;Source&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  The next one is persistency this allows you to actually save data on the USB. You can then boot that USB from multiple machines and you settings and files should be there. Select how much space you want for persistency. If you set it to zero it will be a LiveUSB. &lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/persistence.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Persistence Level&#34; title=&#34;Persistence&#34;&gt;Next are options and are totally up to you, (what I did was select every one of them when I installed BackTrack4)   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/04/persistency-on-linux/options/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/options.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;Options&#34; title=&#34;Options&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Then after all the selections have been made hit that lightning bolt!   &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/04/persistency-on-linux/startnow/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/startnow.png?w=150&#34; alt=&#34;To Start Click the Lighting Bolt&#34; title=&#34;Start Now&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Once completed you can either start the OS within Windows from the portal VM, or reboot and select you USB drive to boot and you now should have a persistent system up and running.   (For BackTrack4 I have found that you need to select “Start Persistent Live CD” in order for the persistent mode to start and save data.)   You can find more information on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxliveusb.com/&#34;&gt;Linux Live USB Creator’s&lt;/a&gt; website. I hope this tutorial was helpful&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 8 What We Know...So Far</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/28/windows-8-what-we-know...so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/28/windows-8-what-we-know...so-far/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Just when you were getting used to Windows 7, Windows 8 moves into the spotlight. So what do we know about Windows 8? Well from the announcements from CES 2011 it did provide us with more information in what Microsoft plans to do with the Windows platform. So I found some facts, and rumors about the operating system, and it looks pretty interesting so far. From the CES 2011 announcement the next version of Windows will support system-on-a-chip architectures using ARM processors, which means that you should expect Windows to be on a wide range of devices, like tablets. But I wouldn&#39;t be surprised if something more came out of it besides tablets. Also an architectural summit in London last year, Microsoft &amp;quot;hinted&amp;quot; the idea of virtualizing the Windows platform, so apps, data, and Windows settings and maybe parts of the operating system itself will be in the &amp;quot;Cloud.&amp;quot; There is also a rumor that the Windows operating system will have a different user interface codenamed &amp;quot;Wind&amp;quot; for the 64bit OS. It&#39;s hard to tell what the interface would look like but rumors say that this interface would be for high-end devices, like desktops and notebook computers. It also says that the &amp;quot;Wind&amp;quot; interface would require 170MB of video memory and might be in 3D. The rumor also states that the &amp;quot;Wind&amp;quot; interface will be able to adapt to user habits. My guess is Windows will be aware of it surroundings, so if the operating system was outside it would it be easier to see, and programs and icons might change locations, I really don&#39;t know it&#39;s a total guess. :) Some other rumors are that the operating system will be able to follow users wherever they go. So an example would be users would be able to roam between desktops, laptops, and tablets. The programs and files would sync between those devices and the information would be stored on the cloud. There is also a &amp;quot;reset button&amp;quot; rumor that locks in applications and settings while being able to clear viruses and other harmful programs. Some people suggest that storing applications and data in the cloud could make this a possible feature. Another rumor by Paul Thurrott suggests that Windows 8 will introduce a tile based interface called &amp;quot;Mosh&amp;quot; for those tablets and other low powered touchscreens. This would also be interesting feature as although Windows 7 is touch screen supported, it isn&#39;t necessarily touchscreen friendly. When will Windows 8 be released? Multiple rumors suggest that Microsoft is setting a goal for 2012, or early 2013. I&#39;m sure more rumors and facts will become available once we get closer to the release date and I&#39;ll be sure to post additional information, if you find any rumors or added information comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
