<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 05:23:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Goals</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2020/01/03/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 05:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2020/01/03/goals/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every year I think about goals, either how to conquer them, reflect on them, and recently change them. We all have been there, we have a plan in our head that we follow for a handful of years or even decades... something happens... all of sudden things change. It&#39;s this change that I believe is so important to life, we can&#39;t and shouldn&#39;t be static, we have to change in order to grow ourselves.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMCv - Change IP Address</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/10/01/fmcv-change-ip-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/10/01/fmcv-change-ip-address/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome Back ;) Think about this for a bit, its been years ago when we first configured the our Cisco FMCv in our virtual environment perhaps this is running for years with no problems. (Lucky us!) All of our firewalls connect to it, policies are pushed correctly, IPS rules are updated correctly and we even have URL filtering turned on some devices, and upgrades work out of the box, it just works, again lucky us!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graylog with AWS Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/06/21/graylog-with-aws-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 18:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/06/21/graylog-with-aws-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Graylog has been through some changes last time I talked about them, hitting version 3.0 in February is awesome and one of things that make Graylog run well is Elasticsearch backend. Although Elasticsearch is not too hard to setup it usually runs better on bare metal, so there is cost of that as well as maintenance of the cluster is important, updates and upgrades. Depending your team experience you may not have time to learn it or run it the way it should be.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes on the Horizon - Cisco</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/06/11/changes-on-the-horizon-cisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 04:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/06/11/changes-on-the-horizon-cisco/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well we finally got an answer, Cisco is upping their Certifications and making some big changes. The CCNA track is taking a hit as all of the secondary exams under CCNA are being retired. If you are studying for any of these CCNA secondary exams keep in mind these won&#39;t transfer over after February 24th 2020. If you complete any current CCNA/CCDA certification before February 24, you’ll receive the new CCNA certification and a training badge in the corresponding technology area.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed 300-115</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/04/02/passed-300-115/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/04/02/passed-300-115/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just a short post about my recent Cisco exam, I was able to pass the 300-115 to renew all my lower CCNA certifications. The last time I took a Cisco exam was almost 3 years ago when I passed the CCNA Data Center certification. Overall the exam was fair although you will need multiple study resources to make sure you cover all the exam objectives. The primary reason for doing this exam first instead of ROUTE or TSHOOT was I felt it was maybe the hardest one?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual ISP - Cisco ASA HA Active/Standby</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/03/12/dual-isp-cisco-asa-ha-active/standby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 12:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/03/12/dual-isp-cisco-asa-ha-active/standby/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So a single ISP isn&#39;t cutting it anymore you need a backup just in case the primary fails and might as well add a second ASA into this design, more redundancy equals more up-time, right? On paper it sounds good but in the &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; world there probably is tipping point, more redundancy increases complexity. In this post we&#39;ll aim to keep it simple, with setting up a Cisco ASA HA active/standby pair and then add in the second ISP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh...Spanning Tree</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/01/02/oh...spanning-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 15:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/01/02/oh...spanning-tree/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s the &amp;quot;S&amp;quot; word we don&#39;t like to hear, and often times it has degraded networks or even took them down entirely. (All Systems Down - an older but classic story) It&#39;s also one of those things that nobody really likes, we even had network companies, as well as IEEE try to replace it with something else. Remember the names like TRILL, and IEEE 802.1aq (SPB) or Cisco&#39;s FabicPath technologies? You had all of these different flavors that showed a lot progress, but they never really took off for one reason or another.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barracuda Load Balancer- Powershell</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/12/14/barracuda-load-balancer-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 15:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/12/14/barracuda-load-balancer-powershell/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Working on my Powershell skills, I was playing around with a Barracuda Load Balancer and noticed it supported some APIs which is kind of cool. At first I was playing around with it in postman and got to login and put some servers in maintenance mode, but then thought it would be really neat if I could get this working in Powershell, that way us humans can just run a script and even thinking in the &amp;quot;future&amp;quot; maybe have some automated process (a.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Dance</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/11/13/automation-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 15:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/11/13/automation-dance/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I keep doing the automation dance, (yeah...that&#39;s me) there are a lot of different tooling products out there. I have been trying to understand a use case around using it with network automation. Recently I have been dancing around with Ansible. My personal belief is that using any type of these tools would be helpful but it can be a steep learning curve if you really don&#39;t have any programming knowledge.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Many TCP Resets</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/06/20/too-many-tcp-resets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/06/20/too-many-tcp-resets/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So, recently we enforced some firewall rules on a new environment, we did testing of the environment and everything was working as expected. In about 24 hours a lot of traffic from the web infrastructure was being denied and it continued, at first glance it looked like return traffic was being dropped, the web servers were sourcing at port 443 and the destination ports were using dynamic ports (RFC 6335) No user or application problems were reported when we enforced rules, and we waited additional days to see if anything came up.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Layer Three EtherChannel</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/05/07/configuring-layer-three-etherchannel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 13:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/05/07/configuring-layer-three-etherchannel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you want more speed all you need is EtherChannel, EtherChannel can be configured as a layer three logical interface instead of just sitting at layer two. This is very helpful if we are running layer three down to the access layer switches, instead of at the distribution layer. You also could see this in a collapsed core design, we also don’t have to worry too much about STP when we configure EtherChannel’s.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless VLANs</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/04/16/wireless-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 13:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/04/16/wireless-vlans/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been fun four months of 2018 so far and I’m back to talk about Wireless VLANs. With 802.11ax around the corner (2019) I think we all can agree that “weird” connections although less likely have interference isn’t as mobile as a wireless LAN. Also, with 802.11ax the maximum theoretical throughput is 10Gbps! We’re going to need some serious backend infrastructure available to be able to support that type of bandwidth.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private VLANs</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/01/09/private-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 13:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/01/09/private-vlans/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s start out 2018 with private VLANs, with PVLANs the network gets a little more privacy added to it. When we have privacy on the network we can seclude certain parts of it. Essentially, &amp;quot;you can go about your business - move along, move along&amp;quot;. Private VLANs allow us to segment networks within a single VLAN. So in this post we&#39;ll go over the types of PVLANs as well as setup a network topology with private VLANs, Let&#39;s get started!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLAN Access Lists (VACLs)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/11/20/vlan-access-lists-vacls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/11/20/vlan-access-lists-vacls/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VACLs are another good layer of security to help control who can talk to who, much like access control lists that are in firewalls and routers, however the difference is VACLs operate at layer two of the OSI model. There could be situations where you have multiple hosts on the same LAN and want to block traffic from reaching certain hosts within that same network, how would you go about blocking that type of traffic without using a router or firewall?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable the NX-OS API</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/10/18/enable-the-nx-os-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 13:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/10/18/enable-the-nx-os-api/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So what has changed in the past 20 years? Take for example the network equipment that was manufactured in 1997, how did you configure that equipment? I would imagine it involved a serial port, HyperTerminal and trusty command line. Was API even a thing back in 1997, was it common to have an API interface in network equipment like today? Why do we even need an API on the equipment in the first place?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enter Cisco Firepower CLI (Read-Only)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/09/20/enter-cisco-firepower-cli-read-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 11:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/09/20/enter-cisco-firepower-cli-read-only/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You have the FMC installed and connect to FTD device with configuration deployed but for what ever reason there is a problem and you need to enter the CLI on the Firepower device to troubleshoot the equipment and although you can&#39;t configure anything you can do show and debug commands to troubleshoot via the CLI. We have to enter the Diagnostic CLI and we can do this in two ways:
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLBP Load Balancing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/08/17/glbp-load-balancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 14:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/08/17/glbp-load-balancing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We could use HSRP or VRRP to have a redundant default gateway for our PC/server networks. Although this works well we now have hardware powered-on and just sitting around waiting for its counterpart to fail, we are not actively using it. We could split up networks or use multiple default gateways within the same network but who does that? Well if your router or layer three switch happens to have that Cisco logo on it and a software release of at least 12.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Firepower Devices - Manually</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/07/12/update-firepower-devices-manually/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 14:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/07/12/update-firepower-devices-manually/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is short and hopefully helpful post on how to manually update Cisco Firepower Devices. I have run into this problem a couple of times which is pushing this update with the FMC sometimes just fails and it never really seems to download the update to the Firepower sensor. On the FMC it will stay on &amp;quot;Initializing&amp;quot; for an hour and timeout so here are the steps to manually update your Firepower Sensor:
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco FTDv in Cisco VIRL</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/06/14/cisco-ftdv-in-cisco-virl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 13:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/06/14/cisco-ftdv-in-cisco-virl/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco is actively pushing their Firepower Threat Defense software with the new Firepower 2100 units on their way this summer in effort to eventually replace the ASA5525-X, ASA5545-X and ASA5555-X platforms. When using FTD you must also have the Firepower Management Center (FMC) available to manage and configure these devices. This gets difficult especially if you want to test things out because not everyone has Cisco Firepower lying around unused. How are you supposed to test and learn the depths of this product?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring EIGRP - Named Mode</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/05/25/configuring-eigrp-named-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 12:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/05/25/configuring-eigrp-named-mode/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            From its older brother IGRP which was developed in 1980s to overcome the limitations of RIP, EIGRP was an &amp;quot;Enhanced&amp;quot; IGRP protocol. The main purpose of EIGRP was to overcome the limitations of classful networks and make EIGRP a classless routing protocol. During designing of this protocol a different convergence algorithm was used making EIGRP that &amp;quot;hybrid&amp;quot; between distance-vector and link-state routing protocols. In this post we&#39;ll go over a basic design and setup for EIGRP, however instead of using the &amp;quot;classic way&amp;quot; let&#39;s look at configuring EIGRP using named mode which is available in Cisco IOS starting in version 15.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Site to Site VPN (DHCP)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/04/19/asa-site-to-site-vpn-dhcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/04/19/asa-site-to-site-vpn-dhcp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you don’t already know, site to site VPNs can be a cost-effective way for remote sites to connect to HQ resources instead of a lease line like using MPLS or Metro-E circuits. We can instead use a standard internet connection with a static IP, this is usually cheaper than a dedicated circuit. Our next steps are purchasing a firewall for the remote site (assuming you already have one at HQ) and setup a site to site VPN connection to make the connection.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Site to Site VPN (PATed)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/03/08/asa-site-to-site-vpn-pated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/03/08/asa-site-to-site-vpn-pated/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you ever needed to hide multiple systems behind a single IP address you would use PAT. (Port Address Translation) besides using this to connect to the internet when using an RFC 1918 address, you can configure PAT for VPN connections. The benefit is the same, hide multiple systems behind a single IP address with the advantage being you can have many systems on one side of the VPN tunnel all using that single IP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco VIRL and Windows VMs</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/01/08/cisco-virl-and-windows-vms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 01:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2017/01/08/cisco-virl-and-windows-vms/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the neat features of Cisco VIRL is it runs on an open platform, with OpenStack as the orchestration program running on top of an Ubuntu operating system. This gives VIRL additional flexibly by being able to run third-party VMs with KVM begin the hypervisor. In this guide I’ll walk through some of the steps I took to get Windows XP up and running in VIRL. :) If you have a more recent version of Windows that&#39;s in the current decade following this guide is pretty much the same just adjust the disk space and RAM to fit the requirements.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t get stuck with &#34;speed-groups&#34;</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/12/21/dont-get-stuck-with-speed-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 03:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/12/21/dont-get-stuck-with-speed-groups/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was working with a Cisco 9372TX switch, and on it I had two 40Gbps uplinks that we where using out of the available four. Talking with our VAR because we where planning on connecting in additional equipment that only supported SFP+ interfaces. So the solution was to connect to this switch with QSFP to SFP+ adapters.
Thinking this would be a simple change because we are just plugging in additional adapters on the QSFP ports we planned our maintenance window and rollback plans but I wasn&#39;t expecting a rollback for this one :) The interfaces were configured in a shutdown status before we plugged in the adapters and cables so didn&#39;t see anything out of the ordinary, when it was time to do the maintenance let&#39;s bring up the interfaces with the command of no shutdown and we should be up.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factory Reset Firepower 4100 &amp; 9300</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/10/19/factory-reset-firepower-4100-9300/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/10/19/factory-reset-firepower-4100-9300/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I got my hands on some Cisco Firepower 4100 units and after playing around with them I wanted to reset them to factory settings, essentially erase the &amp;quot;startup-config&amp;quot; on the FXOS. The Firepower units act a little differently than your normal Cisco IOS or ASA and you can&#39;t just erase startup-config and reload the device, that would be too easy.
(Edit: 7-21-17) After Gabriele made this comment - &amp;quot;connect local-mgmt&amp;quot; and then &amp;quot;erase configuration&amp;quot; it looks like you can.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TFTP &amp; FTP Server on Centos 7</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/09/16/tftp-ftp-server-on-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/09/16/tftp-ftp-server-on-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you ever needed a TFTP or an anonymous FTP server to transfer files, logs, or crash debugs to and from your network devices it can be a little tricky if you don&#39;t have anything setup. There are some free quick programs out there if you are in a pinch for one-time transfers but if you ever wanted to have something in infrastructure that is ready to go for this kind of stuff just follow this tutorial below.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed the 640-916 DCICT</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/08/27/passed-the-640-916-dcict/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/08/27/passed-the-640-916-dcict/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s been a little more than year in the making since I passed my last Cisco exam the 640-911 but I finally did it and passed the 640-916. I can now call myself CCNA Data Center Certified. :) If you ever get the chance to take go up Data Center route it really is interesting of all the products and services Cisco has in their portfolio. Cisco UCS, OTV, Fabicpath and FCoE are just really cool technologies to learn about.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Problems, New Job, and a New Look</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/07/13/new-problems-new-job-and-a-new-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 13:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/07/13/new-problems-new-job-and-a-new-look/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I still consider myself a rookie in this field even though I started my &amp;quot;official&amp;quot; career in the Network/IT space 5 years ago. Why is that? Is part of the reason because of the rapid push that applications are demanding from the infrastructure? For example if we want XYZ app to be ready for testing today and production in a week how would you be able to stand that up manually?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBAC Radius with Microsoft NPS 2012 R2</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/04/12/rbac-radius-with-microsoft-nps-2012-r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/04/12/rbac-radius-with-microsoft-nps-2012-r2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this configuration I&#39;m at looking at using Microsoft NPS 2012 R2 as radius server and I’m going to skip the installation of NPS because it really is just a next, next, finish installation. In this demo I already have this NPS system connected to a Windows domain, my goal is to create role based access on Cisco IOS routers while using radius to login. I’ll have a couple for active directory accounts each them will represent different types of allowed access to these IOS routers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPerf Throughput Testing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/02/12/iperf-throughput-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 19:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/02/12/iperf-throughput-testing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Testing a network’s throughput is a good move, if you are testing a new service you stood up or making sure you getting what you paid for. iPerf is good free open source tool when there isn’t really a need to use commercial more expensive tools. In this short tutorial I’ll go over how to configure iPerf which is a CLI tool so let’s get started.
iPerf needs client and server on each end of the connection in order to test the throughput.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco VIRL – Update</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/11/18/cisco-virl-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 13:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/11/18/cisco-virl-update/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco released VIRL almost a year ago and it’s not at the 1.0 version yet but it’s getting close as they have done some good work towards the product since it first lunched. Cisco VIRL is like GNS3 which is simulation platform that runs Cisco’s current operating systems so instead of buying used Cisco hardware you can run this program on your computer. This software is geared towards proof-of-concept designs, for personal and training on Cisco Certifications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRTG Daily Email Powershell Script</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/06/03/prtg-daily-email-powershell-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/06/03/prtg-daily-email-powershell-script/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I don&#39;t write much powershell but recently I needed a way to send daily emails out of PRTG. Thanks Paessler which has kept it simple with their PRTG monitoring system as the hardest part of this script was getting the data in HTML, remember I don&#39;t write much powershell. ;) If you have not used PRTG before check it out if you need some alerting in your environment. Personally this is one of my favorite systems for just monitoring because a lot of other monitoring systems include everything but the kitchen sink and reality we just need to know what&#39;s up and what&#39;s down.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed the 640-911 DCICN</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/05/14/passed-the-640-911-dcicn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 01:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/05/14/passed-the-640-911-dcicn/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco started this exam back in 2012 and I have thought/semi-studied about this test for about over a year now, just did not feel comfy about it until recently. I took the test last week and passed, however there were some questions on the exam I noticed that weren&#39;t on the exam blueprint so that kind of surprised me. I was happy to still be able to pass the exam but I was caught off guard.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Hexadecimal to Decimal and Binary</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/04/22/converting-hexadecimal-to-decimal-and-binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 02:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/04/22/converting-hexadecimal-to-decimal-and-binary/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The purpose of this post is to reference the CCNA Data Center (640-911) exam. This exam starts the conversation of IPv6 and since IPv6 is hexadecimal this post starts the talk about how we look at a hexadecimal values and learn how to convert them to binary and decimal. If you know subnetting skills then this won’t be that difficult. If you are new then check out The Wonders of Binary post as well as Part 1 and Part 2 of subnetting.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Rancid</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/02/27/configuring-rancid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/02/27/configuring-rancid/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In my last post I talked about Installing Rancid on Centos 7 so be sure to check that out. In this post we now want to actually use Rancid so I’ll walk through on how to setup Rancid to login into network equipment and get configurations.
To recap: Rancid is a great tool to help monitor a device configuration for any changes. It also keeps track of them by using CVS (Concurrent Version System) for backups, so you can go back and compare versions or revert to a previous configuration.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco VIRL is out ... for a price</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/12/05/cisco-virl-is-out-...-for-a-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 03:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/12/05/cisco-virl-is-out-...-for-a-price/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just wanted to put this up has Cisco has recently released VIRL. This is a network simulation platform that you can run Cisco operating systems on which are the same operating systems that run on Cisco hardware so anything you do in this simulation environment would be realistic if it was running on dedicated hardware. You would be able to test your changes before throwing them in production. Some things that are different between VIRL and CML (Cisco Modeling Labs)
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up GNS3 1.1 on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/10/28/setting-up-gns3-1.1-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 12:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/10/28/setting-up-gns3-1.1-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s only been a week since GNS3 1.0 was released and it&#39;s already been updated to 1.1 so in this post I have Ubuntu 14.04 LTS with the latest updates and its time to set up GNS3. GNS3 is an open source tool that helps network professionals run a virtual network right on their computer, GNS3 is not a simulation program but rather an emulation program. So if you wanted to test a configuration change but did not want to run it on production you can run it in GNS3 instead.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some QoS Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/08/05/some-qos-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 02:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/08/05/some-qos-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When I started taking classes from the Cisco CCNA Discover books years ago, I remember for the first part of the book it talked about QoS and the theory behind it. To me QoS was a very interesting but after a chapter or two we never mentioned it again or really knew how to configure it. It seemed like it disappeared but it always something being tested on so we know it was there, somewhere… QoS can be a little boring and it does get a reputation of being difficult to understand, like where and how do I implement QoS?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Modeling Labs … Waiting</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/06/28/cisco-modeling-labs-waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 20:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/06/28/cisco-modeling-labs-waiting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just waiting for CML, (Cisco Modeling Labs) it’s been little over a month since going to Cisco Live in San Francisco and with all the information of next-generation hardware and security with Source Fire I was pretty beat with a lot of note taking and PowerPoint slides. However the last session on the last day of the Cisco Live talked about Cisco’s Modeling Lab program. I also tried it out in the Cisco DevNet area earlier in the week during Cisco Live and I was impressed with the product.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install RSYSLOG &amp; LogAnalyzer on CentOS 6-5</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/06/11/install-rsyslog-loganalyzer-on-centos-6-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/06/11/install-rsyslog-loganalyzer-on-centos-6-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am looking at rsyslog which is fast syslog system and Loganalyzer as an upfront web GUI for those logs. The Loganalyzer application offers searching of various syslogs, all of which is open source and available to download. In this guide I will go through the steps to get these two applications to work together and in the end of this tutorial we should have a working syslog system ready to take logs!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 Alpha – Install and Setup</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/05/10/gns3-alpha-install-and-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 01:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/05/10/gns3-alpha-install-and-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So Alpha 3 came out last week with a bunch updates and I decided to give it run this week. I&#39;m not doing anything that difficult with the program so maybe I&#39;m not breaking it in all the way but I also was looking at some installation notes for Ubuntu and other Linux flavors, I figured I’ll try to install it on a Windows machine and not Linux (call me lazy) feel free to follow this guide.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 12 &amp; 13)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/19/640-911-chapter-12-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 16:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/19/640-911-chapter-12-13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are at the last chapters of the CCNA Data Center 640-911 by Todd Lammle. Chapter 12 talks about redundant switched technologies and chapter 13 talks about security. Just like before I will go over the high-points, so let’s get started!
Chapter 12 Overview: In this chapter we get to learn about Spanning Tree Protocol and some history with it. With networks we like multiple ways to a destination however in the layer two area redundancy does not play well and that’s where spanning tree can help us.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 10 &amp; 11)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 01:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just like before if you have followed, I have gone over the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle and in this post we cover two chapters. Feel free to comment below if you have any questions on either of these two chapters.
Chapter 10 Overview: Chapter 10 starts us back in the book, before we do any configuring and we learn about routing protocols, and remember the difference between static and dynamic routing (name implies it) Also know the default administrate distances of the different routing protocols (starts on page 297).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter-VLAN Routing on the Nexus 5k</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 15:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I previously had the chance to play around with the 5596UP switch, and made some notes on how to configure inter-vlan routing. Since this was a 5596UP switch I needed a layer 3 card to take advantage of it. The next-generation units the 5600 include layer 3 without a card required along with introducing 40GB uplinks! However in this post let&#39;s go back to the basics and configure inter-vlan routing on a nexus switch and in this case I am using a 5596UP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 7)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you made it past the earlier chapters this one should be interesting, like before I am going through each chapter of the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Comment below if you have questions in this chapter, last week we learned about subnetting and in this chapter we will learn about the NX-OS which is Cisco&#39;s Data Center switches. Let&#39;s begin! Overview: This was short chapter in introducing the NX-OS product line and into the virtualized enviroments that data centers are now becoming.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 6)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/20/640-911-chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 19:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/20/640-911-chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s start chapter six of the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle, feel free to post questions if you have any. Like before I have covered the topics of the each chapter. Last week we learned about the different IP classes and today we get a course in subnetting. Let&#39;s go over what you should know if you want to pass the exam.
Overview: It seems I have talked subnetting to death on this blog, repetition, repetition, repetition.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 5)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 19:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last week we covered chapter four which talked about the TCP/IP and the DoD models and what role they cover in networking as we learned that every application like FTP, DNS, DHCP depend on it. Like always post questions if you have any about the book CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I&#39;ll continue to cover topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 4)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 18:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off on Chapter 3 on CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Like before feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter three we discussed about Ethernet Technologies and in chapter four we will learn about the TCP/IP protocol which is fundamentally the protocol that makes the Internet work.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNP Security Refresh</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/03/ccnp-security-refresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 14:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/03/ccnp-security-refresh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco recently published its 2014 Annual Security Report, and some interesting data was captured in 2013. One of the details was a talent gap in network security and because of this gap Cisco has a major revision in the CCNP Security certification starting in April. Its estimated that in short term or already present is shortage of more than a million security professionals worldwide! Like mentioned because of this Cisco is reworking the CCNP Security track.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 3)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/30/640-911-chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 18:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/30/640-911-chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picking up were we left on off on a series of blog posts that follow the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter two we discussed about internetworking and in chapter three we will learn about Ethernet technologies.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 2)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 19:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am continuing the ongoing of series of blog posts that follow the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I figured that this type of post would help me and anybody else looking at studying for the exam. Feel free to post questions below as if on a study group, In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 1.0 Campaign</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/11/21/gns3-1.0-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 06:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/11/21/gns3-1.0-campaign/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s been almost 24 hours since GNS3 launched a campaign to bring in funds to support the open source network simulator and bring it up to version 1.0. A lot of new features are on the list, like switching, cloud processing, hassle free configuration, labs/training materials and 3rd party integrations. All of which are in the works for this new version added along with some pretty cool plug-ins. As of writing this post they are at $106,973 dollars which is 300 percent over funded!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring EtherChannel (PAgb)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 15:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bundling physical links into one logical link is a common practice to up the bandwidth between switches, you may have this also configured on a server to bundle connections as well. In this tutorial I have two 2960 switches both of them trunking all VLANs on two gigabit ports. So in the end game is get 2gbps instead of 1gbps between switches while using Cisco’s proprietary protocol PAgb. It is important to remember that both of these protocols (PAgb and LACP) are link aggregation protocols only, their job is to make sure that EtherChannel is setup correctly by negotiating.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA 2-0 What&#39;s New?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/09/30/ccna-2-0-whats-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/09/30/ccna-2-0-whats-new/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I brought this topic up in March of this year (See original post) but I wanted to re-post it to add some information because as of today this was your last day to pass the older CCNA exams. Cisco has a refreshed all the CCNA Routing and Switching exams. That includes the ICND1 (640-822), the ICND2 (640-816), and the all in wonder exam (640-816). You will notice some old references no longer mentioned on this refresh, so let&#39;s go over the differences and some of the changes Cisco has made to the associate-level certification track.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy Running-Config From PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/08/16/copy-running-config-from-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 03:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/08/16/copy-running-config-from-powershell/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I will be up front on this I really never had that much experience with power-shell scripts but I wanted a quick way to connect to routers and switches and issue the show run command and have that script output everything into one file. So some searching around I decided to drive into power-shell to see if I could get something to work. One of my first problems was to find a way to have power-shell SSH into my devices I found out about SharpSSH which look interesting but I also found SSH.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Your Network Healthy?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/07/19/is-your-network-healthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 01:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/07/19/is-your-network-healthy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Networks are becoming more &amp;quot;borderless&amp;quot; as Cisco likes to call it and it&#39;s definitely true. Having the ability to get access to resources remotely without having to be at our office physically is a nice touch, you may even notice higher productivity and who doesn&#39;t want that! Networks have to be in a healthy state in order for people remotely and people at the office to get their work done.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site-To-Site VPN via CCP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/05/02/site-to-site-vpn-via-ccp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 02:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/05/02/site-to-site-vpn-via-ccp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I have ran through before on how to create a site-to-site VPN with Cisco SDM which sounds like a repeat but I thought why not bring CCP into light and since I&#39;m studying the newly created CCNA Security (640-554) I figured let&#39;s create a tutorial on it. In this lab I am going to post the running-config of both locations so you can either run it through Packet Tracer or live equipment if you wish.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring AAA – Locally</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/04/04/configuring-aaa-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 01:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/04/04/configuring-aaa-locally/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A while back I talked about AAA but never put out a post on how configure it until now. In this post I am going to be going over the configuration steps of how to configure AAA locally on a Cisco router, (The same commands would also work on Cisco switch). To review what exactly AAA does check my earlier post Understanding AAA. Like mentioned in my earlier post of Understanding AAA it gets better if you have some type of radius or tacacs+ server.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Version 2.0 Refresh</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/03/26/ccna-version-2.0-refresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 05:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/03/26/ccna-version-2.0-refresh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I think we knew it was coming at some point and Cisco has recently announced a refresh for the 640-822 (ICND1), 640-816 (ICND2) and the all in one 640-802 (CCNA) the last day to take these tests and get certified are September 30th of 2013. You will notice some old references no longer mentioned on this refresh, so let&#39;s go over the differences and some of the changes Cisco has made to the associate-level certification track.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction into Cisco Configuration Professional</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/03/10/introduction-into-cisco-configuration-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/03/10/introduction-into-cisco-configuration-professional/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s walk through the basics with Cisco Configuration Professional as it is a helpful tool to use at the associate levels of the Cisco certification track and needed if you are looking at getting the CCNA Security certification. In this introduction we will introduce CCP and setup a community and then finally discover our devices within CCP. This is not the first GUI tool Cisco has produced to manage individual routers, an older tool called Cisco SDM also helped Network Administrators which supports the ISR Generation 1 routers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive your Configuration</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/01/22/archive-your-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 05:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/01/22/archive-your-configuration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It is important to save your router and switch configuration but what happens if the device fails or if you saved a configuration mistake, without having to manually worry about it? Well if your Cisco router or switch has Cisco IOS 12.3T and higher you would be able to set up an auto archive within the flash memory of the unit or you can send that configuration file to a server that does either FTP, HTTP, SCP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure DHCP on a Cisco Router</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/12/01/configure-dhcp-on-a-cisco-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 16:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/12/01/configure-dhcp-on-a-cisco-router/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Data-connect-computer In this short tutorial let&#39;s configure a DHCP server on a Cisco Router. Why would we want to do that? Well configuring a basic DHCP server on a router is a good idea if this is a branch/satellite office or just a small business. There are some pros and cons of configuring DHCP on a Cisco Router so let&#39;s briefly discuss them and then start configuring. Putting DHCP on a router is pretty easy and that&#39;s one advantage of setting up DHCP no need to setup a Linux or Windows server.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Data Center</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 02:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco has now introduced another associate level exam, the CCNA Data Center exam. Like the name suggests this exam focuses on the Data Center and if passed you can continue up the stack by also taking the CCNP Data Center exam which was also recently introduced as well. Still want more a little more, if you are up for the challenge you can also tackle the CCIE Data Center which is an exam that was introduced in March of 2012.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Network and its Forces</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/10/30/the-network-and-its-forces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 03:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/10/30/the-network-and-its-forces/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            communication I have started looking CCDA information and some of it is interesting, towards the beginning the material started out at design methodologies. It talked about the &amp;quot;forces&amp;quot; of a new network framework and in this post I&#39;ll focus on the business forces that make a new framework necessary. I find it interesting when looking at companies because although customer service is important to sustain a company, I also think it will and may already have depend on who embraces the technology wheel, those that do will ultimately win.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 01:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Cisco Lab When it comes to learning and getting started with Cisco there are some tools that will help out a lot like Packet Tracer, GNS3 and other emulators. These are great tools for that &amp;quot;simulation&amp;quot; of hands on learning, but you can&#39;t always stay in that area. I find it best to get hands on with &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; Cisco Gear and so with this post I&#39;ll go through my current setup of what I have and ask that question when it is a good time to get a lab?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why IPv6?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/08/22/why-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 01:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/08/22/why-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although this protocol has been around since 1996 it has been anticipated that IPv4 would one day be exhausted. In February 2011 the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA) assigned the last /8 address blocks to the Regional Internet Registries so time is getting close but you have heard this warning before right? Let&#39;s go over IPv6 at least just an overview some the features and changes compared to IPv4 because one day it will happen it&#39;s just a matter of when.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password Recovery – Cisco IOS Routers</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/07/21/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/07/21/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure In this post I want to cover how to recover passwords on a Cisco IOS Router. This is helpful in lab environments as well as production environments. Although this method can be used the correct &amp;quot;legal&amp;quot; way you can also use this method to break into these devices &amp;quot;illegally&amp;quot; if you have physical console access to the device. However to get into it physical power must be turned off first causing a disruption in the environment, let get started!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/29/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 01:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/29/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this short but helpful post, I&#39;ll go through the process of upgrading the ASA IOS via the ASDM. This is a pretty painless method if all goes well the only thing you have to do schedule downtime if this box is in production, and grab the ASA IOS image from Cisco. For this post all have been covered let&#39;s get started! First things first is always backup your configuration before upgrading and I always read the release notes that Cisco provides when I download the IOS image, it&#39;s good reading and important because usually new features are introduced and sometime the ASDM can&#39;t paraphrase and parse the new configuration which way I usually upgrade the ASDM first.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1 - The Joys of Subnetting!</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 20:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since network technicians work with IP addressing, it is hugely important to understand subnetting. I remember back when I started to learn subnetting it was confusing and I wanted nothing to do with it. The thing that made me change my mind was after I understood it and how important it is. In the &amp;quot;Cisco world&amp;quot; they don&#39;t cover useless topics...right? ;) there is always a reason why they expect you to know this and it&#39;s not just for the exams.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Nexus 1000v?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/03/17/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 17:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/03/17/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network_cloud I have worked with the Nexus 1000v product and wanted to share my thoughts on it. I want to explain in this blog what this product is and what it does. The Nexus 1000v can be virtual or a hardware appliance and is considered to be a virtual switch that runs in VMware. The major benefit to this product is the visibly you get when running in a virtual environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIGRP… The Basics</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/02/29/eigrp-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 02:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/02/29/eigrp-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Routing_Updates Enhanced Interior Gateway Routing Protocol (EIGRP) is an impressive set of features for IP Routing, which converges quickly and is on par and sometimes faster than OSPF. This routing protocol requires less processing time, less memory, and less network design than compared to OSPF. What&#39;s the catch? This protocol is Cisco proprietary, if you have a network that uses non-Cisco routers, EIGRP will not and cannot be used on those routers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Tiers</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/21/the-three-tiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 19:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/21/the-three-tiers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network_switch Working towards the CCNA Cisco talks about a hierarchical network there are three layers to this design. Access Layer, distribution layer and the core layer. Each of them have their own set of functions and is also considered to be a best practice when the network continues to grow and for redundancy along with just a better way to manage it. The Access layer is the layer that devices connect to, such as PCs, printers, and IP Phones.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Understanding of EtherChannel</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/04/basic-understanding-of-etherchannel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/04/basic-understanding-of-etherchannel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network cables Let&#39;s start the New Year with understanding EtherChannel which is having more than one link connected to a server, switch, or router and treating it like one logical link. This is a fault-tolerant technique that is becoming a common setup in highly available, core devices. Cisco has come up with their own proprietary version call EtherChannel. The open standard that IEEE approved is 802.3ad which works with other venders and is often called LAG for short.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color Code Your Routers</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/11/30/color-code-your-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 17:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/11/30/color-code-your-routers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I came across an interesting idea, what if you could color code your devices in command line? So such as if you were operating routers at a core level you could color code the CLI to the color red, and the branch routers green and etc. I wasn&#39;t sure if this would possible but doing some searching through the internet I found a guy Ivan Pepelnjak who wrote how to do this a couple years ago and wrote a couple books as well, check out his blog/website at http://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure SSH on Dell Power-Connect</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/26/how-to-configure-ssh-on-dell-power-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 15:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/26/how-to-configure-ssh-on-dell-power-connect/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            keys Although not dealing with Cisco directly Dell switches are around in network closets and with my limited experience with them I thought this would be a perfect blog post to show the differences between Dell and Cisco. I like to think of Dell CLI like a dumb downed version of the Cisco CLI so I had some time to play around with a Dell 6248P switch and wanted to figure out how to get SSH working in the thing.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of WAN Links</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/19/types-of-wan-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 16:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/19/types-of-wan-links/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve found this table that I created a while ago and it lists common WAN connections that businesses use. I have used this table like a reference guide to familiar myself into other protocols. People don&#39;t think of it much but the WAN is a different beast compared the LAN as it uses different protocols besides Ethernet. The WAN or wide area network is what connects us to remote locations within a organization.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the month of August I talked about the &amp;quot;beginnings&amp;quot; of layer two redundancy mainly looking at the basic foundations and fundamentals of having layer two redundancy. Let&#39;s continue are discussion about redundancy in the layer two environment. To review what STP does (Spanning Tree Protocol) it works at layer two of the OSI model. If more than one path is available in the network the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until the active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link-State Protocols</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/31/link-state-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/31/link-state-protocols/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network-Cables Weeks ago and maybe months :), I talked about distance vector protocols and with that you probably got the feeling that when using a distance vector protocol it does not give a full network graphical representation of the entire network. Only the directly connected routes can&#39;t remember? Check out this post Distance Vector Routing. Link state protocols are faster to converge network changes compared to distance vector however when compared to distance vector setup they can be harder to set up, maintain, and troubleshoot when problems arise.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Codes of ICMP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post I wanted to talk about the widely used Ping command. Which is one of the best methods (I think) to begin network troubleshooting. When part of the network goes down it is sometimes hard to figure out why? When you issue the ping command or the extended ping command in a Cisco router several ICMP codes can come up on the router. Let&#39;s discuss them! The first status code &amp;quot;!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network-diagram In a perfect world we would never need redundancy on a network infrastructure, but as you know as well as I know we don&#39;t live in a perfect world. Hardware will eventually fail, bottlenecks will appear, and the speed of our network will become slower when we max the bandwidth on links. So having redundancy in routers, connections, and having a hierarchy network is one of best choices to make when improving the efficiently of the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Super WiFi</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/29/welcome-super-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 15:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/29/welcome-super-wifi/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WiFi_Logo Wow July is almost over and I only posted one topic! Before August comes up I wanted to post at least one more topic which deals with the wireless side of the networking world. Ever heard of Super WiFi? The IEEE has published this standard recently its official number is 802.22. What does Super WiFi bring to the table compared to other WiFi Standards? Well according to IEEE these speeds can bring up to 22Mbps to devices as far has 62 miles!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the Cisco Discovery Protocol. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between router or switch is set up correctly at least up to layer two in the OSI model. This also helps us discover Cisco devices that are in are network and which interfaces these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed information CDP gives out which helps you has a network administrator build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Vector Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 16:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Couple weeks ago I talked about routing protocols and in the post I mentioned two routing protocol features distance vector and link state. Although these protocols fundamentally do the same thing by getting information on remote networks they get this information in a different way. For today let&#39;s introduce distance vector routing. With a distance vector routing protocol, a router learns about a route to a different network (that&#39;s the purpose of a routing protocol) the router only knows the &amp;quot;distance&amp;quot; to get there this is usually called the metric.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World IPv6 Day!!</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/08/world-ipv6-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 18:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/08/world-ipv6-day/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IPv6 So what is IPv6 day? Today major companies like Google, Facebook, Yahoo and ISPs (Internet Service Providers) test their IPv6 deployments. Why is this important? Well if you follow IPv4 news you might already know that IPv4 addresses have been exhausted and the need to move to different address space is critical, if new web services are to be deployed. The question is can we run both? Although running two different IP addressing protocols is likely, by &amp;quot;stacking&amp;quot; them that is one reason the Internet Society wanted major sites and ISPs to test out the IPv6 address space.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classful vs. Classless Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 16:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud-Computing-icon Before the internet and general networking become popular into what it is now, there were and still are routing protocols that only do classful routing. What is classful routing? When I was talking about Dynamic Routing earlier (See the post Dynamic Routing Protocols) I mentioned there was a difference between classful routing and classless routing. So in today&#39;s post let&#39;s focus on these two but important topics when using routing protocols.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS Commands</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 17:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the master list of some of the many Cisco IOS Commands that go with the CCNA track. This list also talks about what each command does in brief detail. You may also find that some commands may or may not be used for a CCNA level but offer some important information. If you don&#39;t know what a command does or understand it, I would look at Cisco documentation. Since this is a pretty big list of commands you can see the links to move to the different sections within this page.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Wireless LAN Security</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/18/basic-wireless-lan-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 16:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/18/basic-wireless-lan-security/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wireless-Security-Icon Although having a wireless LAN sounds like a wonderful idea, there are things that need to be implemented like security. A wireless LAN can be uncontrollable has it is just radio waves and anybody can receive them. Having and using good security practices can help you be under control of your wireless LAN. Not having any security in a wireless LAN environment will cause anybody to have access to the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VTP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some people hate it, some people love it. It&#39;s the Cisco proprietary VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) which in short means that Cisco switches can exchange VLAN configuration, instead of manually configuring each switch with the same VLANs. I also suggest if you don&#39;t know what a VLAN is check out the post Creating VLANs Let&#39;s get right into understanding VTP. The thing that makes VTP shine is what it does, although simple to understand it saves time by automatically distributing VLAN information.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Routing Protocols</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 16:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dynamic Routing If you ever wanted to set up a network manually, you will quickly find how much overhead is required to get PCs, printers, and other network equipment. That&#39;s where dynamic routing protocols come into play although they are helpful I strongly urge you to understand static routing first. (See the post Configure Static Routing) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s get the foundation of understanding dynamic routing protocols. By definition a routing protocol is a set of messages, rules and algorithms used by routers for the overall purpose of learning routes to other networks not physically connected to it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Static Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plugging Cisco routers together and hoping they work out of the box is not something you should hope for. A router can learn about networks in two ways, manually from configured static routers which we will talk about today and dynamic routing protocols which will talk about on Wednesday. Let&#39;s get started! Static routes are not that uncommon they at first need some attention to get set up but after it is working nothing needs to change.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding AAA</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/29/understanding-aaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/29/understanding-aaa/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            User The wonderful AAA which in the Cisco world means, Authentication, Authorization, and Accounting but what does that really mean? In today&#39;s post that&#39;s what we are going to be talking about. What is AAA and what are the benefits of using it along with what is it? The first &amp;quot;A&amp;quot; of AAA is Authentication which provides the method of identifying users, including login and password dialog, challenge and response, messaging support, and, depending on the security protocol you select, encryption.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure a Site-to-Site VPN via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 18:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure a site-to-site VPN on a router using the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. (See the post Configuring SDM) Let&#39;s start configuring a site-to-site VPN with SDM! This tutorial is assuming that the configurations to set up Cisco SDM have already been completed.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 17:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Awhile back I talked about the differences between IPS and IDS. (See the post Cisco IDS vs. IPS ) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure an IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) on a router using the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. ( See the post Configure Cisco SDM) Let&#39;s start configuring an IPS with SDM!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Zone Based Firewalls via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 15:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last month I talked about the fundamentals for understanding zone based firewalls (See the post Understanding Zone Based Firewalls). So for today&#39;s post I want to go ahead and talk about configuring the zone based firewalls but with the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and reduce ownership costs. (See the post Configure Cisco SDM) Instead of talking about what is zone based firewalls lets jump into the configuration of them.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Cisco SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we will be going over the steps that are required to set up the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger) The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. SDM is fairly easy to set up but you still need at least some experience in the router command-line to get SDM working. This tutorial is already assuming that the Cisco SDM program has been installed on the PC.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Process</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Troubleshooting Today&#39;s post is going to be talking about troubleshooting and where to start the troubleshooting process. Yes there is an actual process that every technician should be aware of. You can also use this troubleshooting process at home, you may not know how to fix it but at least you know where the issue is and find someone who can. Before we begin if you haven&#39;t seen yet, let me introduce to you the troubleshooting process:
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Learning Labs is Live!</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/13/cisco-learning-labs-is-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/13/cisco-learning-labs-is-live/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday was kind of exciting at least for me when I got an e-mail in the morning about Cisco Learning Labs. Studying for the CCNA, CCNP or CCIP is in itself changeling, but getting that hands-on experience is a another problem! When money is short that last thing you want to do is spend it on routers and switches, and most of them on eBay are used and the risk of failing devices makes it a scary choice.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11n</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/11/802.11n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/11/802.11n/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On this Monday let&#39;s wrap up the 802.11 wireless standards, Friday I talked about the 802.11g (See the post 802.11g) and before that I talked about the 802.11b (See the post 802.11b ) I also talked about 802.11a, (See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of last week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So let&#39;s end the discussion and talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11g</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/08/802.11g/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/08/802.11g/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well again we are continuing the discussion about the wireless standards. Yesterday I talked about 802.11b (See the post 802.11b), and before that I talked about 802.11a,(See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Standards) So on this Friday let&#39;s talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11b</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/07/802.11b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 17:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/07/802.11b/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off the discussion, todays post will be talking about 802.11b wireless standard that was developed by IEEE. Yesterday&#39;s post we talked about the 802.11a standard. (See the post 802.11a) We also we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I went over some Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So now that we are up to speed lets learn about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11a</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/06/802.11a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/06/802.11a/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing the discussion about wireless standards we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) Today&#39;s post will be talking about the IEEE 802.11a standard. On Monday I talked about the Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post will be going over the second standard 802.11a out of the five standards that make up the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11 - Legacy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/05/802.11-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 15:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/05/802.11-legacy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday we talked about the wireless concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post one of the five standards that make up the 802.11. The 802.11 – Legacy has its called now and is not in use anymore by manufactures and is now obsolete was the first wireless standard available for consumer laptops. When the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Wireless Concepts</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/04/basic-wireless-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 15:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/04/basic-wireless-concepts/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            wireless-connection-icon Mobility is now a common thing in a business environment, you no longer are fixed to specific cubicle in the work place anymore. What is also amazing is it will continue to change and become easier for employees to get work done, with their phone, tablet, and laptop computer. But what makes this possible? What is the underlying component? The internet is becoming more available in more locations, coffee shops, airports, and your cell phone service provider, with 3G and 4G speeds.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating VLANs</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today this tutorial is going to be talking about creating VLANs (Virtual Local Area Networks) with a Cisco Catalyst switch. By creating a VLAN you are separating the network, why would you do this? There are some several reasons, like separating your production network from a guest network, and separating a test environment from a production network. This all adds security to your network. You can separate core critical network components from the rest of the production network for added security, easier troubleshooting along with separating or segmenting your network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Port Security</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/31/configuring-port-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/31/configuring-port-security/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure Today this tutorial is going to be talking about how to configure port security on a Cisco Catalyst switch. Port security is one of the first things you can do to keep your network secure from unauthorized access. Port security can restrict devices so only devices you allow are granted access to network resources. If and when an unauthorized device is connected to a port you can decide what you want the switch to do.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collision Domains vs Broadcast Domains</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/30/collision-domains-vs-broadcast-domains/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These different types of domains mean different things and when designing a LAN both of these domains can harm the performance of your network. If you are not aware of the difference between these two, this tutorial should help you out. If you have a small network at your home there is usually the router/modem that is connected via phone line or cable to the ISP that router/modem is then connected to a switch or they even have a switch built into the device.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring SSH</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/29/configuring-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 15:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/29/configuring-ssh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today this tutorial is going be talking about how to configure SSH on a Cisco router or switch. SSH or Secure Shell encrypts the data that is sent from the terminal application to the device. Making if far more safer when it is compared to telnet which sends the data in plain text. To add support for SSH to a Cisco router or switch, the device needs some added information then just passwords.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding UDP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 16:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Forever ago I talked about TCP (Understanding TCP) and I said that in that post that UDP would be another day, well this is the day where we get to understand UDP, which stands for User Datagram Protocol. UDP is the total opposite of the TCP communication. UDP in short sends information or data without notifying the receiver that its sending data. UDP is considered a connectionless protocol, and does not guarantee the reliability or order the packets like TCP does.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I passed the ICND1 Exam</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well my first of the many Cisco certifications that I plan take in the future was a success! I was able to pass the ICND1 exam. This blog post is going to be a little different in that I want to share how I was able to pass this test and talk about my experience.
Well in January after finishing the Cisco Networking Academy in the Exploration series I wanted to go ahead and take shot at the ICND1 exam.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Zone Based Firewalls</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier we talked about using CBAC (See the post Understanding CBAC) the &amp;quot;classic firewall&amp;quot; and we mention some information about zone based firewalls but not nearly enough. So today we will be talking about zone based firewalls. Why are they different? We also will learn the basics about what is zone based and what are the advantages compared to CBAC. You can think of zone based has making interfaces in a quarantine zone, each interface by default if set up in a zone is denied access to any other interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Network Attacks</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/17/common-network-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 16:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/17/common-network-attacks/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network attacks have always been around but they are getting more advanced every day. These attacks are also easy to set up and use. In the past these types of attacks would have to be pulled off by someone who really knew about computers and to know what they are doing. That&#39;s a true hacker, now there are programs that do the same damage and sometimes more with a couple clicks of a mouse, so now anybody can bring down a network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a Router Routes</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 17:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/16/how-a-router-routes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial will be going over the basic information of how a router routes IP packets. Routers are used in the OSI layer three or the network layer. These routers have IP addresses and forward IP packets to the proper destination. This guide is somewhat basic and is assuming you have some information of how IP addressing works and along with what routing protocols are. So let&#39;s focus first on how a host or a computer forwards traffic and then look at how a router forwards traffic.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telecommuting Services</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/11/telecommuting-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 17:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/11/telecommuting-services/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is going to talk about the major technologies that make Teleworking or also called telecommuting possible. This is when an employee performs his or her job away from the office, usually from their home office. By doing this it allows personal convenience, less travel to and from the workplace. At an Organization level it provides continuity of operations, Secure, reliable and manageable access to information, cost-effective integration of data, voice, video and applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossover or Straight through?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 18:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The EIA/TIA puts the standards in UTP cable, and when cabling a network there are two standards. T568A and T568B these standards are important when deciding to put a crossover cable or straight through cable This tutorial is going to be talking about when and where to apply these different standards. We are going to be focusing on the UTP cable and with the RJ-45 connectors; in order for the communication to work properly we need to make sure we understand where to put these cables.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IDS vs. IPS</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 15:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are tons of network attacks out there. Using a firewall helps but does look for signature based attacks. Access Control Lists are like firewalls and only look at the protocols like HTTP, FTP POP, etc. Cisco has developed some tools that will help network administrators combat the issue; IDS, (Intrusion Detection System) and IPS. (Intrusion Prevention System) Let&#39;s go into IDS first, Cisco IDS is a physical device and is like an alarm system it will alert you when an attack happens but that&#39;s it, the system won&#39;t block the connection.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laser Printing Process</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/08/laser-printing-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 14:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/08/laser-printing-process/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s move away from Cisco for at least a day, So this post will be talking about the six steps in the laser printing process, this is good for technicians who fix or repair printers along with a good learning experience. With my limited knowledge of printers I used this process to at least help diagnose the problem. If you have no idea how a printer works, I would not try to fix it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress.com Hit by a DoS Attack</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/04/wordpress.com-hit-by-a-dos-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 15:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/04/wordpress.com-hit-by-a-dos-attack/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday, (March 3rd 2011) there was a massive DoS attack that hit WordPress.com. Cisco Skill&#39;s uses WordPress.com has a hosting provider but is not believed to one of the sites hit. There still is no word on who or why they targeted WordPress.com but goes to show that Denial of Service is still a popular type of attack and although simple to set up they can still bring down enterprise networks.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install BackTrack</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 18:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a full install of BackTrack 4 this can be in a virtual machine, dual-boot, or the main OS. So you burned the image that you downloaded from http://www.backtrack-linux.org/ and are ready to go! If not I would recommend you do that first. BackTrack is a Linux penetration testing for network security. This is a free tool that IT administrators can use to audit their network. First put the disk into the tray and restart your computer.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intel Thunderbolt</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/28/intel-thunderbolt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/28/intel-thunderbolt/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Intel announced on Friday (February 25th 2011) the new high speed connector that will coexists with USB 3.0. Apple also announced that it will be appearing first on the MacBook Pros. Thunderbolt known before has Light Peak is a new high-speed PC connection technology. This cable can combine data and high-definition all in one cable running at 10Gbps. So you could say it is like the all in wonder HDMI cable that combines video and audio into one cable.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding TCP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/25/understanding-tcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 18:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/25/understanding-tcp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This tutorial is going to be talking about the TCP protocol. Every time you connect to a website you are using the HTTP protocol, but below that you are also using a TCP protocol. The nature of TCP is to provide error recovery; there are other services or applications that use TCP. HTTP however is a common protocol that is used in online applications. Remember TCP is not the only protocol in the transport layer of the OSI model, there is another called UDP but that&#39;s another day.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding CBAC</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although using hardware firewalls are an excellent step forward when securing your network. They can cost money and are not cheap to set up and configure. Using CBAC is built-into the Cisco IOS router and helps filter those unwanted protocols that are in your network. When setting up routers as firewalls you have some choices like using CBAC the &amp;quot;Classic&amp;quot; firewall, or zone based policy (ZBF). Today we will talk about CBAC and how to understand the core components of what make CBAC possible.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11ac Standard</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/21/802.11ac-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 18:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/21/802.11ac-standard/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some things are making news in the wireless world, the IEEE wants another wireless standard in the mix called the 802.11ac, now the fastest standard they have is the 802.11n(speeds up to 300 Mbps), which was recently published in October of 2009. What is so great about the 802.11ac development? Well one thing is the speed, it is estimated that it will be able to carry up to 1 gigabit per second!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS Routers: Auto Secure</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/17/cisco-ios-routers-auto-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 17:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/17/cisco-ios-routers-auto-secure/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Auto Secure is good for small business or IT administrators that may know how to configure a router with networking protocols, setting up IP interfaces, and networks but really don&#39;t have an understanding of the security aspect of the router. So what Cisco has done is implemented a script called Auto Secure. Auto Secure is based on the questions you answer from the prompt usually &amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;no&amp;quot; answers. Sometimes the script wants a little more information depending on your network configuration.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TACACS Plus and RADIUS</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/10/tacacs-plus-and-radius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 15:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/10/tacacs-plus-and-radius/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TACACS+ and RADIUS are both used to control access to network resources, but both of these protocols are different in how they operate depending how you want to secure your network. These protocols need to have (AAA) authentication, authorization, and accounting setup on the routers before you can set up these access server protocols. First let&#39;s get some information on why we would need this type of access server protocol setup.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring RIPv2</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/09/configuring-ripv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 17:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/09/configuring-ripv2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide will go over how to configure RIPv2 on Cisco routers. This guide follows a packet tracer activity that is posted at the end of this tutorial. RIPv2 configuration is pretty simple to understand with really only three required commands to use besides the network command which depends how many networks are connected to your router. RIPv2 Layout So following the packet tracer that is used with this tutorial the first step is to configure the hostname on the routers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Control Lists</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/07/access-control-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 18:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/07/access-control-lists/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding Access Control Lists is an important role for moving up into the CCNA area. ACLs can get confusing and cause network problems if not implemented correctly. I think what I outlined below explains in a nutshell of what you can expect from ACLs.
I would still read and find more information about ACLs on the web and or reading material (becuase I don&#39;t trust myself!). By securing networks with ACLs you are adding another barrier to your network although ACLs can&#39;t fool-proof your network they add additional level of security from the outside world.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv4 Meet IPv6</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/03/ipv4-meet-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 13:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/03/ipv4-meet-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IPv4 maybe on its last leg with only a few blocks of IPv4 addresses available, computer estimates say that the IANA address depletion was January 27, 2011. Also the calculations for all central IPv4 pool addresses will be depleted by July 25, 2012.
These are estimates and may change as of writing this post. I&#39;ll be sure to update if needed, but the thing to understand is that IPv4 won&#39;t be available within weeks if not months.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybercriminals Focusing on Mobile Platforms</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/01/24/cybercriminals-focusing-on-mobile-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/01/24/cybercriminals-focusing-on-mobile-platforms/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If I were to tell you four years ago that cybercriminals were going to focus on mobile phones instead of computers would you believe me? This shift in focusing on mobile devices and platforms instead of computers means one thing, it’s easier. What does that mean? Well think of it this way if I was hacker wanting to gain access to somebody’s personal information, and I had a choice between their computer or their mobile phone which one would I choose?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
