<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Catalyst on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/catalyst/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Catalyst on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 15:56:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/catalyst/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuring EtherChannel (PAgb)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 15:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/10/networkswitches_e.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/10/networkswitches_e.png&#34; alt=&#34;NetworkSwitches&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Bundling physical links into one logical link is a common practice to up the bandwidth between switches, you may have this also configured on a server to bundle connections as well. In this tutorial I have two 2960 switches both of them trunking all &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_LAN&#34; title=&#34;Virtual LAN&#34;&gt;VLANs&lt;/a&gt; on two gigabit ports. So in the end game is get 2gbps instead of 1gbps between switches while using Cisco’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proprietary_protocol&#34; title=&#34;Proprietary protocol&#34;&gt;proprietary protocol&lt;/a&gt; PAgb.   It is important to remember that both of these protocols (PAgb and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Link_aggregation&#34; title=&#34;Link aggregation&#34;&gt;LACP&lt;/a&gt;) are link aggregation protocols only, their job is to make sure that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EtherChannel&#34; title=&#34;EtherChannel&#34;&gt;EtherChannel&lt;/a&gt; is setup correctly by negotiating. This helps prevent EtherChannel mismatches and loops. You could manually set the etherchannel mode to &amp;quot;on&amp;quot; instead of using either of these aggregation protocols. However this is considered best practice to use one of these link aggregation protocols. Here are some Guidelines for Configuring EtherChannel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can configure the port in two ways:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Port_Aggregation_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Port Aggregation Protocol&#34;&gt;PAgp&lt;/a&gt; which is Cisco proprietary protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LACP which is an industry standard 802.3ad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can combine from two links to eight links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All ports &lt;strong&gt;MUST&lt;/strong&gt; be identical such as:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Same speed that also includes duplex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cannot mix and match Fast Ethernet and Gigabit ports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cannot throw in PAgp and LACP in the same “channel”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be either all trunking or non-trunking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All links in the channel must be either in Layer 2 or Layer 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to use PAgp each side must be one of the two settings for the channel to come up.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto-Desirable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desirable-Desirable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you would like to use LACP then each side must be one of the two settings for the channel to come up.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Active-Active&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Active-Passive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for this example I have a two Cisco 2960 switches, one switch is a 24-port while the other one is a 48-port switch. I have already done some pre-configuring for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Inter-Switch_Link&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Inter-Switch Link&#34;&gt;native VLAN&lt;/a&gt; (not using VLAN1) and I have also created an additional VLAN for data traffic on both of these switches. The two switches I am working with both have two gigabit trunk uplinks to each other, by default of STP one link will be in blocking state. To allow both of these links in a forwarding state follow the configuration below. On the 24-port switch under both gigabit interfaces: [code highlight=&amp;quot;3,4,5&amp;quot;] 24-SW3#configure t Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. 24-SW3(config)#interface range gigabitEthernet 0/1 -2 24-SW3(config-if-range)#channel-group 1 mode desirable Creating a port-channel interface Port-channel 1 *Mar 2 22:53:06.895: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface GigabitEthernet0/1, changed state to down *Mar 2 22:53:06.920: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface GigabitEthernet0/2, changed state to down *Mar 2 22:53:09.688: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface GigabitEthernet0/2, changed state to up *Mar 2 22:53:09.713: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface GigabitEthernet0/1, changed state to up [/code] On the 48-port switch under both gigabit interfaces: [code highlight=&amp;quot;3,4,10,11&amp;quot;] 48-SW1#configure t Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. 48-SW1(config)#interface range gigabitEthernet 0/1 - 2 48-SW1(config-if-range)#channel-group 1 mode auto Creating a port-channel interface Port-channel 1 *Mar 2 09:56:03.907: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface GigabitEthernet0/1, changed state to down *Mar 2 09:56:03.940: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface GigabitEthernet0/2, changed state to down *Mar 2 09:56:13.327: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface GigabitEthernet0/1, changed state to up *Mar 2 09:56:13.797: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface GigabitEthernet0/2, changed state to up *Mar 2 09:56:27.235: %LINK-3-UPDOWN: Interface Port-channel1, changed state to up *Mar 2 09:56:28.242: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface Port-channel1, changed state to up[/code] To verify that port-channel is working as expected (Notice line 4) [code highlight=&amp;quot;1,4&amp;quot;] 24-SW3#show interfaces port-channel 1 Port-channel1 is up, line protocol is up (connected) Hardware is EtherChannel, address is 001a.6d44.0c1a (bia 001a.6d44.0c1a) MTU 1500 bytes, BW 2000000 Kbit, DLY 10 usec, reliability 255/255, txload 1/255, rxload 1/255 Encapsulation ARPA, loopback not set Keepalive set (10 sec) Full-duplex, 1000Mb/s, link type is auto, media type is unknown --- Omitted ---[/code] You can also verify EtherChannel with the following command, several options are available. [code highlight=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;] 24-SW3#show etherchannel 1 ? detail Detail information port Port information port-channel Port-channel information protocol protocol enabled summary One-line summary per channel-group [/code] We now have a 2gbps unlink between these two switches, if we looked at spanning-tree we would see the port-channel interface (Po1) is in a forwading state and the two gigabit links are not listed as active interfaces. If you would like more information about EtherChannel look at the post I did some time ago about &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/04/basic-understanding-of-etherchannel/&#34; title=&#34;Basic Understanding of EtherChannel&#34;&gt;Understanding EtherChannel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://datacenteroverlords.com/2013/09/02/link-aggregation/&#34;&gt;Link Aggregation&lt;/a&gt; (datacenteroverlords.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thegeekstuff.com/2013/09/cisco-vlan-trunk/&#34;&gt;How to Create VLAN Trunking on Cisco Catalyst Switch&lt;/a&gt; (thegeekstuff.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
