<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OSPF on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/ospf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OSPF on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 11:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/ospf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuring OSPF - The Basics</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/08/13/configuring-ospf-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/08/13/configuring-ospf-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have to start somewhere so let’s look at the basics of configuring OSPF. Remember OSPF is an IGP (Interior Gateway Protocol) and allows packet authentication as well as IP multicast when sending and receiving updates. In this post we are configuring OSPF in a single area. In this topology we have four routers and two PCs. The PCs subnet are 172.30.2.0/24 and 172.30.3.0/24. We have point to point connections between each router.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSPF...What a Protocol!</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/11/02/ospf...what-a-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 18:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/11/02/ospf...what-a-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For today let&#39;s discuss a routing protocol that was being thought of in 1987 by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF). OSPF currently has three versions and the first version was in the 1980s when the internet was still being used for research. What is interesting about the first version of OSPF is although one version ran on routers the other type of version ran on UNIX computers. When OSPFv2 come out in the 1990s the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) was working on another routing protocol called IS-IS (Intermediate System-to-Intermediate System).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
