<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wireless on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/wireless/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wireless on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 13:30:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/wireless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wireless VLANs</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/04/16/wireless-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 13:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/04/16/wireless-vlans/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s been fun four months of 2018 so far and I’m back to talk about Wireless VLANs. With 802.11ax around the corner (2019) I think we all can agree that “weird” connections although less likely have interference isn’t as mobile as a wireless LAN. Also, with 802.11ax the maximum theoretical throughput is 10Gbps! We’re going to need some serious backend infrastructure available to be able to support that type of bandwidth.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Super WiFi</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/29/welcome-super-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 15:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/29/welcome-super-wifi/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WiFi_Logo Wow July is almost over and I only posted one topic! Before August comes up I wanted to post at least one more topic which deals with the wireless side of the networking world. Ever heard of Super WiFi? The IEEE has published this standard recently its official number is 802.22. What does Super WiFi bring to the table compared to other WiFi Standards? Well according to IEEE these speeds can bring up to 22Mbps to devices as far has 62 miles!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Wireless LAN Security</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/18/basic-wireless-lan-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 16:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/18/basic-wireless-lan-security/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wireless-Security-Icon Although having a wireless LAN sounds like a wonderful idea, there are things that need to be implemented like security. A wireless LAN can be uncontrollable has it is just radio waves and anybody can receive them. Having and using good security practices can help you be under control of your wireless LAN. Not having any security in a wireless LAN environment will cause anybody to have access to the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11n</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/11/802.11n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/11/802.11n/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On this Monday let&#39;s wrap up the 802.11 wireless standards, Friday I talked about the 802.11g (See the post 802.11g) and before that I talked about the 802.11b (See the post 802.11b ) I also talked about 802.11a, (See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of last week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So let&#39;s end the discussion and talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11g</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/08/802.11g/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/08/802.11g/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well again we are continuing the discussion about the wireless standards. Yesterday I talked about 802.11b (See the post 802.11b), and before that I talked about 802.11a,(See the post 802.11a) I even talked about the 802.11 –Legacy (See the post 802.11 –Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I talked about the basic wireless concepts. (See the post Basic Wireless Standards) So on this Friday let&#39;s talk about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11b</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/07/802.11b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 17:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/07/802.11b/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off the discussion, todays post will be talking about 802.11b wireless standard that was developed by IEEE. Yesterday&#39;s post we talked about the 802.11a standard. (See the post 802.11a) We also we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I went over some Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So now that we are up to speed lets learn about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11a</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/06/802.11a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/06/802.11a/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing the discussion about wireless standards we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) Today&#39;s post will be talking about the IEEE 802.11a standard. On Monday I talked about the Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post will be going over the second standard 802.11a out of the five standards that make up the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11 - Legacy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/05/802.11-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 15:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/05/802.11-legacy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday we talked about the wireless concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) in that post I mentioned the wireless standards but did not go further into detail. This post one of the five standards that make up the 802.11. The 802.11 – Legacy has its called now and is not in use anymore by manufactures and is now obsolete was the first wireless standard available for consumer laptops. When the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Wireless Concepts</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/04/basic-wireless-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 15:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/04/basic-wireless-concepts/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            wireless-connection-icon Mobility is now a common thing in a business environment, you no longer are fixed to specific cubicle in the work place anymore. What is also amazing is it will continue to change and become easier for employees to get work done, with their phone, tablet, and laptop computer. But what makes this possible? What is the underlying component? The internet is becoming more available in more locations, coffee shops, airports, and your cell phone service provider, with 3G and 4G speeds.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cracking WEP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/14/cracking-wep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2011 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/14/cracking-wep/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BackTrack is Linux network security audit tool for security professionals. This tool is used for testing and penetrating networks. That being said** This tutorial is for educational use only. This is meant only to teach that WEP is an insecure option, and is recommend to use a harder encryption. Using this tutorial on a network that you do not have permission to access or is not yours, could be illegal! ** This was tested on BackTrack version 4 and the steps outlined in this tutorial were successful.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11ac Standard</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/21/802.11ac-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 18:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/21/802.11ac-standard/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some things are making news in the wireless world, the IEEE wants another wireless standard in the mix called the 802.11ac, now the fastest standard they have is the 802.11n(speeds up to 300 Mbps), which was recently published in October of 2009. What is so great about the 802.11ac development? Well one thing is the speed, it is estimated that it will be able to carry up to 1 gigabit per second!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
