<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Information on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/information/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Information on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/information/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the Cisco Discovery Protocol. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between router or switch is set up correctly at least up to layer two in the OSI model. This also helps us discover Cisco devices that are in are network and which interfaces these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed information CDP gives out which helps you has a network administrator build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Process</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Troubleshooting Today&#39;s post is going to be talking about troubleshooting and where to start the troubleshooting process. Yes there is an actual process that every technician should be aware of. You can also use this troubleshooting process at home, you may not know how to fix it but at least you know where the issue is and find someone who can. Before we begin if you haven&#39;t seen yet, let me introduce to you the troubleshooting process:
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IDS vs. IPS</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 15:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are tons of network attacks out there. Using a firewall helps but does look for signature based attacks. Access Control Lists are like firewalls and only look at the protocols like HTTP, FTP POP, etc. Cisco has developed some tools that will help network administrators combat the issue; IDS, (Intrusion Detection System) and IPS. (Intrusion Prevention System) Let&#39;s go into IDS first, Cisco IDS is a physical device and is like an alarm system it will alert you when an attack happens but that&#39;s it, the system won&#39;t block the connection.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
