<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Configuration file on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/configuration-file/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Configuration file on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 03:09:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/configuration-file/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Copy Running-Config From PowerShell</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2013/08/copy-running-config-from-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 03:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2013/08/copy-running-config-from-powershell/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/logo-powershell.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/logo-powershell.png&#34; alt=&#34;powershell-logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I will be up front on this I really never had that much experience with power-shell scripts but I wanted a quick way to connect to routers and switches and issue the show run command and have that script output everything into one file. So some searching around I decided to drive into power-shell to see if I could get something to work. One of my first problems was to find a way to have power-shell &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell&#34; title=&#34;Secure Shell&#34;&gt;SSH&lt;/a&gt; into my devices I found out about SharpSSH which look interesting but I also found SSH.NET. So I went with my second choice and decided to try the SSH.NET module. I would not of went to far if I did not stumble across this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powershelladmin.com/wiki/Main_Page&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; which helped out a lot. Here is the direct &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powershelladmin.com/wiki/SSH_from_PowerShell_using_the_SSH.NET_library&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; of the Wiki page I was referring to. Also here is the code I quickly put together and I can bet there is a better way to setup this script but since I am pretty green when it comes to scripting this is what I could come up with. Feel free to edit and use, if you have suggestions on how to improve this script let me know by commenting below. [code language=&amp;quot;powershell&amp;quot;] #--------------------------------------------------------------------------- # PowerShell Script for Connecting using SSH to Network Devices and to # issue one or multiple commands. # RECOMMENDED USE: Automating Backups # ATTENTION: Module SSH-Sessions must be in the Default System32 # Location: Windows\system32\WindowsPowerShell\v1.0\Modules # MORE INFORMATION: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powershelladmin.com/wiki/SSH&#34;&gt;http://www.powershelladmin.com/wiki/SSH&lt;/a&gt;_from_PowerShell_using_the_SSH.NET_library #--------------------------------------------------------------------------- # Settings below should not need to be changed, however feel free to add-on! # Lets run by some house rules like asking what to do if an error occurs. $ErrorActionPreference =&amp;quot;Inquire&amp;quot; # Do you even have the SSH-Sessions Module? Let’s check before we continue. Import-Module SSH-Sessions # With the output file that is created by this script lets timestamp # the current Year, Month and Day and put it as part of the filename. $time =&amp;quot;$(get-date -f yyyy-MM-dd)&amp;quot; # Let&#39;s put in something in front of the date timestamp of the soon to be # created file defualt is &amp;quot;config&amp;quot; $filename =&amp;quot;config&amp;quot; # By default the type of file created is a text file. $ext =&amp;quot;.txt&amp;quot; #--------------------------------------------------------------------------- # START WITH CUSTOM CONFIGURATION # Where do you want the created file to be placed? The current user running # this script will need # access to that location. Also this script will not create folders if the # path does not exist expect an error # A good example to place the created files would be &amp;quot;C:\Cisco-Backups&amp;quot; $filepath =&amp;quot;&amp;quot; # Depending on the amount of devices you want to connect, this part of the # script could be lengthy. # To set this up follow the example. # $d1 =&amp;quot;192.168.1.1&amp;quot; # This is setting up a variable called &amp;quot;d1&amp;quot; followed by the IP address of # the device you would connect with SSH. # Each device will have a different variable if you have five devices it # would look like the following: # $d2 =&amp;quot;192.168.2.1&amp;quot; # $d3 =&amp;quot;192.168.3.1&amp;quot; # $d4 =&amp;quot;192.168.4.1&amp;quot; # $d5 =&amp;quot;192.168.5.1&amp;quot; # $d6 =&amp;quot;192.168.6.1&amp;quot; # Below is your custom list of devices that you want to connect with SSH. $d1 =&amp;quot;&amp;quot; # Depending on the environment each device may have a different account to # log in. # For simplicity&#39;s sake it is recommended to use one custom account for # all logins. # However you can specify different account logins per device. Follow the example. # $u1 =&amp;quot;admin&amp;quot; # $u2 =&amp;quot;bob&amp;quot; # This example shows two different username accounts it recommended to # match these up with the device you would be connecting to, # for example &amp;quot;d1&amp;quot; uses &amp;quot;u1&amp;quot;, etc. # Below is your custom list of login account names that each device # will use, if all devices use the same account just specify one variable. $u1 =&amp;quot;&amp;quot; # Depending on the environment each device may have a different password # to log in. For simplicity&#39;s sake it is recommended to use one password # for all logins. However you can specify different passwords per device. # Follow the example. # $p1 =&amp;quot;password123&amp;quot; # $p2 =&amp;quot;P@$$w0rd987&amp;quot; # This example shows two different passwords it recommended to match # these up with the device and username you would be connecting to, # for example &amp;quot;d1&amp;quot; uses &amp;quot;u1&amp;quot; which use &amp;quot;p1&amp;quot; etc. # Below is your custom list of passwords that each device will use, # if all devices use the same password just specify one variable. $p1 =&amp;quot;&amp;quot; # Depending on the amount of devices you want to connect, this part # of the script could be lengthy. The command to connect with SSH is # &amp;quot;New-SshSession&amp;quot; We have to specify the device to connect, the username # to use along with the password. Follow the example. # New-SshSession $d1 -Username $u1 -Password &amp;quot;$p1&amp;quot; # New-SshSession $d2 -Username $u2 -Password &amp;quot;$p2&amp;quot; # This example shows that we are going to be connecting with two devices, # with two different usernames and passwords. # If you are using the same username and password on all devices it would # follow this example which is using the same # variable for the username and password. # New-SshSession $d1 -Username $u1 -Password &amp;quot;$p1&amp;quot; # New-SshSession $d2 -Username $u1 -Password &amp;quot;$p1&amp;quot; # Below is your custom list that specifies the device to connect to, the # username and password. If all devices use the same username and password # just speifiy the same variable. New-SshSession $d1 -Username $u1 -Password &amp;quot;$p1&amp;quot; # DONE WITH CUSTOM CONFIGURATION #--------------------------------------------------------------------------- # What command to you want to run on all devices defualt is the &#39;show run&#39; # command. $c1 =&amp;quot;show run&amp;quot; # Lets run the command that we configured and output all of that into one # file. $Results = Invoke-Sshcommand -InvokeOnAll -Command &amp;quot;$c1&amp;quot; | Out-File &amp;quot;$filepath$filename-$time$ext&amp;quot; # We are done running commands on these devices lets close the connection. Remove-SshSession -RemoveAll # Close out of PowerShell exit [/code] I have tested this out and it works pretty good, I was able to test up to 12 devices at the same time. Since this script does not have any &amp;quot;if&amp;quot; statements and other smarts to it you do have to change a configuration option on your router or switch to go right into Privileged EXEC when the account logs in. This is done by usually saying privilege level 15 when setting up a user account on the router or switch. I hope this information is helpful and I will see if I can re-work this script as it is a work in progress with power-shell :) What are other ways to backup your configuration, what tools and or scripts have you used in the past?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://reviews.cnet.com/8301-13727_7-57524257-263/ssh-tip-send-commands-remotely/?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&#34;&gt;SSH tip: Send commands remotely&lt;/a&gt; (reviews.cnet.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://community.spiceworks.com/topic/370296-what-actually-is-required-to-get-the-configuration-from-a-cisco-device&#34;&gt;What actually is required to get the configuration from a Cisco device?&lt;/a&gt; (community.spiceworks.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://myvirtualife.net/2013/08/07/how-to-enable-ssh-root-access-in-horizon-workspace-virtual-machines/&#34;&gt;How to enable SSH root access in Horizon Workspace Virtual Machines&lt;/a&gt; (myvirtualife.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive your Configuration</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2013/01/archive-your-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 05:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2013/01/archive-your-configuration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hard20drive-black.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hard20drive-black.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hard-Drive&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It is important to save your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Router (computing)&#34;&gt;router&lt;/a&gt; and switch configuration but what happens if the device fails or if you saved a configuration mistake, without having to manually worry about it? Well if your Cisco router or switch has &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; 12.3T and higher you would be able to set up an auto archive within the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_memory&#34; title=&#34;Flash memory&#34;&gt;flash memory&lt;/a&gt; of the unit or you can send that configuration file to a server that does either &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;File Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;FTP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypertext_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Hypertext Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt;, SCP. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trivial_File_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Trivial File Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;TFTP&lt;/a&gt;, etc. Let&#39;s work through on setting up the archive feature on a Cisco Router. In this example we will look at one way to archive your configuration to the flash memory of the unit. This is good if you want the ability to revert back quickly to an existing configuration that has been saved in flash. Keep in mind this is not the only way to archive your configuration, instead of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Archive&#34; title=&#34;Archive&#34;&gt;archiving&lt;/a&gt; it to flash memory you could back it up on a server using some common transfer file protocol like FTP, TFTP and other options. Let&#39;s start setting up the archive feature so I&#39;m on the HQ Router and to archive to flash, the first thing we have to do is enter configuration mode followed by typing &lt;strong&gt;archive&lt;/strong&gt; and hit enter. [code]HQ#configure terminal Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. HQ(config)#archive HQ(config-archive)#[/code] You will notice we are in the archive configuration mode hit the question to see the available commands. [code]HQ(config-archive)#? Archive configuration commands: default Set a command to its defaults exit Exit from archive configuration mode log Logging commands maximum maximum number of backup copies no Negate a command or set its defaults path path for backups rollback Rollback parameters time-period Period of time in minutes to automatically archive the running-config write-memory Enable automatic backup generation during write memory[/code] For this we will put are configuration on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_file_system&#34; title=&#34;Flash file system&#34;&gt;flash file system&lt;/a&gt; let&#39;s keep it simple by just calling it &lt;strong&gt;HQ-RTR.config&lt;/strong&gt; here is our example: [code]HQ(config-archive)#path flash:HQ-RTR.config[/code] This writes the configuration into flash and by default writes up to ten and then rolls them over. This is also where you could point this path to an FTP/TFTP server instead of flash. To archive your configuration while under the &lt;strong&gt;config-archive&lt;/strong&gt; mode you have two choices, both of these options could be used together. The write-memory option will archive you configuration after you issue the &lt;strong&gt;copy running-config startup-config&lt;/strong&gt; command. The time-period command will write the configuration to flash every &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; amount minutes. Where &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; is the number of minutes you specify after the command. See an example of both commands below: [code]HQ(config-archive)#write-memory HQ(config-archive)#time-period 500000[/code] To see your archives you can issue the command show archive, in this example I have two archives located in flash. This command would also work if you are storing them on a FTP/TFTP server. [code]HQ#show archive There are currently 3 archive configurations saved. The next archive file will be named flash:HQ-RTR.config-3 Archive # Name 0 1 flash:HQ-RTR.config-1 2 flash:HQ-RTR.config-2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14[/code] You can also see these archives in the flash file system by issuing the &lt;strong&gt;show flash&lt;/strong&gt; command. [code]HQ#show flash: -#- --length-- -----date/time------ path 1 19939672 Sep 16 2008 15:51:54 +00:00 c1841-spservicesk9-mz.124-6.T7.bin 2 1122 Jan 22 2013 03:49:18 +00:00 HQ-RTR.config-1 3 1142 Jan 22 2013 03:54:28 +00:00 HQ-RTR.config-2 44060672 bytes available (19951616 bytes used)[/code] Let&#39;s roll back from an archive, to do this it is pretty simple just use the &lt;strong&gt;configure replace&lt;/strong&gt; command followed by &lt;strong&gt;archive&lt;/strong&gt; and the archive file you would like to replace the running-config. Let&#39;s look below and see the process as an example. [code]HQ#configure replace archive:flash:HQ-RTR.config-2 This will apply all necessary additions and deletions to replace the current running configuration with the contents of the specified configuration file, which is assumed to be a complete configuration, not a partial configuration. Enter Y if you are sure you want to proceed. ? [no]: Y HQ#[/code] That&#39;s it! You can either put these archives on the flash of the device or you can setup a simple FTP, TFTP, SCP, etc. box and have your configurations stored there. Like always I hope this information is helpful and post below if you have questions about this topic.You can also find more information on Cisco&#39;s website about the archiving along with the configure replace and rollback commands. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/ios/12_3t/12_3t7/feature/guide/gtrollbk.html#wp1066264&#34; title=&#34;Configuration Replace and Configuration Rollback&#34;&gt;Configuration Replace and Configuration Rollback&lt;/a&gt; Enjoy! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/12/01/configure-dhcp-on-a-cisco-router/&#34;&gt;Configure DHCP on a Cisco Router&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rekrowten.wordpress.com/2012/12/26/how-to-remove-tracked-interface-from-hsrp/&#34;&gt;How to Remove Tracked Interface from HSRP&lt;/a&gt; (rekrowten.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sucuri.net/2012/11/psa-sftpftp-password-exposure-via-sftp-config-json.html&#34;&gt;SFTP/FTP Password Exposure via sftp-config.json&lt;/a&gt; (sucuri.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password Recovery – Cisco IOS Routers</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2012/07/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2012/07/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/lock.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/lock.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Secure&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; In this post I want to cover how to recover passwords on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Router (computing)&#34;&gt;Router&lt;/a&gt;. This is helpful in lab environments as well as production environments. Although this method can be used the correct &amp;quot;legal&amp;quot; way you can also use this method to break into these devices &amp;quot;illegally&amp;quot; if you have physical console access to the device. However to get into it physical power must be turned off first causing a disruption in the environment, let get started! So I have a router called R2-D2 at ACME Corp, I have been given permission to recover the password and access the device. I have tried some passwords that where written down but all failed. [code]R2-D2 con0 is now available Press RETURN to get started. *************************************************************************** * L E G A L N O T I C E -- Y O U M U S T R E A D * *************************************************************************** * * * You must have explicit permission to access or configure this * * device. All activities performed on this device are logged and * * violations of this policy may result in criminal prosecution. * * * *************************************************************************** * * * This system is for the use of authorized users only. Individuals using * *this computer system without authority, or in excess of their authority, * * are subject to having all of their activities on this system monitored * * and recorded by system personnel. * * * * * * Anyone using this system expressly consents to such monitoring and is * * advised that if such monitoring reveals possible evidence of criminal * * activity, system personnel may provide the evidence of such monitoring * * to law enforcement officials. * * * =========================================================================== User Access Verification Username: admin Password: % Login invalid Username: admin Password: % Login invalid[/code] It is after-hours so I can physically power off the device and that&#39;s what I need to do next. Immediately I have to press the &amp;quot;break sequence&amp;quot; (which depends on the terminal application you are using. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tera_Term&#34; title=&#34;Tera Term&#34;&gt;TeraTerm&lt;/a&gt; this sequence is ALT + B) I like to think of this as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BIOS&#34; title=&#34;BIOS&#34;&gt;BIOS&lt;/a&gt; like on a computer, but it is normally called ROMon in Cisco terms or ROM Monitor, notice the prompt? At this prompt you have to type &amp;quot;confreg 0x2142&amp;quot; which ignores or bypass the startup-config file. Then type the command &amp;quot;reset&amp;quot; to reload the router which will bypass the statup-config. [code]System Bootstrap, Version 12.4(13r)T, RELEASE SOFTWARE (fc1) Technical Support: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/techsupport&#34;&gt;http://www.cisco.com/techsupport&lt;/a&gt; Copyright (c) 2006 by cisco Systems, Inc. Initializing memory for ECC . c2811 platform with 262144 Kbytes of main memory Main memory is configured to 64 bit mode with ECC enabled Upgrade ROMMON initialized PC = 0xbfcd0d54, Cause = 0x2000, Status Reg = 0x3040a803 rommon 1 &amp;gt; confreg 0x2142 You must reset or power cycle for new config to take effect rommon 2 &amp;gt;[/code] Now that the router bypassed its startup-config we have to go into the privilege mode and type the command &amp;quot;copy startup-config running-config&amp;quot; which will load the startup-config into the running-config. [code]DRAM configuration is 64 bits wide with parity enabled. 239K bytes of non-volatile configuration memory. 125440K bytes of ATA CompactFlash (Read/Write) --- System Configuration Dialog --- Would you like to enter the initial configuration dialog? [yes/no]:no Press RETURN to get started! ---Output Omitted--- Router#copy startup-config running-config Destination filename [running-config]? 2341 bytes copied in 0.288 secs (8128 bytes/sec) R2-D2#[/code] Next we change the password to something that we know, I&#39;m changing the login password and the enable secret: [code]R2-D2(config)#username admin password $%^cisco R2-D2(config)#enable secret !!@@cisco[/code] After that we have to change config-register back to the default 0x2102 which will load the startup-config file when reloaded. [code]R2-D2(config)#config-register 0x2102 R2-D2#copy startup-config running-config Destination filename [running-config]? 2341 bytes copied in 0.292 secs (8017 bytes/sec) R2-D2#reload[/code] Copy the running-config to save those password changes by using the &amp;quot;copy running-config startup-config command and reload the device one last time to confirm changes. you should be able to access the device and the configuration by using the passwords you just created . :) I hope this information was helpful some may ask what do those config-resister values do? Well there is some documention on Cisco&#39;s website and it goes over the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/en/US/products/hw/routers/ps133/products_tech_note09186a008022493f.shtml&#34; title=&#34;Use of the Configuration Register on All Cisco Routers&#34;&gt;Use of the Configuration Register on All Cisco Routers&lt;/a&gt; and if you have other questions comment below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/&#34;&gt;Basic Cisco ASA Overview&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/28/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/&#34;&gt;Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/&#34;&gt;CCNA Security - 640-554&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/irisdan/basics-of-cisco-switch-administration&#34;&gt;Basics of cisco switch administration&lt;/a&gt; (slideshare.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netcomm-solutions.com/&#34; title=&#34;imran@sheensol.com&#34;&gt;Network Communications&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-10-30 03:01:29&#34;&gt;Oct 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really appreciate your efforts in writing really helpful points in password recovery. Because there are many users who face difficulties in case of password recovery...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-10-30 19:28:04&#34;&gt;Oct 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glad I could help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS Commands</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/05/cisco-ios-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 17:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2011/05/cisco-ios-commands/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;This is the master list of some of the many &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; Commands that go with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CCNA&#34; title=&#34;CCNA&#34;&gt;CCNA&lt;/a&gt; track. This list also talks about what each command does in &lt;strong&gt;brief&lt;/strong&gt; detail. You may also find that some commands may or may not be used for a CCNA level but offer some important information. If you don&#39;t know what a command does or understand it, I would look at Cisco documentation. Since this is a pretty big list of commands you can see the links to move to the different sections within this page. Enjoy! &lt;a href=&#34;#PrivilegedMode&#34;&gt;Privileged Mode&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#Setconp&#34;&gt;Set a password for console access&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#Setvtyp&#34;&gt;Set a Password for virtual terminal (telnet) access&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#Setauxp&#34;&gt;Set a password for auxiliary (modem) access&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#Setuprouter&#34;&gt;Setting up the Router&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#Generalcom&#34;&gt;General Commands&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#Processesstats&#34;&gt;Processes and Statistics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#cdpcom&#34;&gt;CDP Commands&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#miscellaneous&#34;&gt;Miscellaneous Commands&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Privileged Mode:&lt;/strong&gt; [code]Router&amp;gt;enable[/code] This command &amp;quot;enable&amp;quot;will get you in privileged mode in the router or switch. [code]Router#disable Router&amp;gt;[/code] This command &amp;quot;disable&amp;quot; will put you back to the user mode in the router or switch. [code]Router(config)#enable password knowing[/code] This will put a unencrypted password on the privileged mode (in this example the password would be &amp;quot;knowing&amp;quot;) [code]Router(config)#enable secret knowing[/code] This command will put an encrypted password on the privileged mode (in this example the password would be &amp;quot;knowing&amp;quot;) &lt;strong&gt;Set a password for console access:&lt;/strong&gt; [code]Router(config)#line console 0 Router(config-line)#login % Login disabled on line 0, until &#39;password&#39; is set Router(config-line)#password allknowing[/code] This sets the password as &amp;quot;allknowing&amp;quot; when accessed by the consolde line in a router or switch. &lt;strong&gt;Set a Password for virtual terminal (telnet) access:&lt;/strong&gt; [code]Router(config)#line vty 0 4 Router(config-line)#login % Login disabled on line 66, until &#39;password&#39; is set % Login disabled on line 67, until &#39;password&#39; is set % Login disabled on line 68, until &#39;password&#39; is set % Login disabled on line 69, until &#39;password&#39; is set % Login disabled on line 70, until &#39;password&#39; is set Router(config-line)#password knowingall[/code] Remember you must have a password on telnet to access the router or switch with a telnet session otherwise the router or switch will close the session immediately. This sets the password as &amp;quot;knowingall&amp;quot; &lt;strong&gt;Set a password for auxiliary (modem) access:&lt;/strong&gt; [code]Router(config)#line aux 0 Router(config-line)#login Router(config-line)#password all[/code] This sets the password as &amp;quot;all&amp;quot; when accessed via the auxiliary port. &lt;strong&gt;Setting up the Router:&lt;/strong&gt; [code]Router#show running-config Building configuration... &lt;output omitted=&#34;&#34;&gt;[/code] This command &amp;quot;show running-config&amp;quot; shows the details of the running configuration file in RAM. [code]Router#show startup-config[/code] This command &amp;quot;show startup-config&amp;quot; shows the details of the startup configuration file in NVRAM (If there is one saved) [code]Router#setup --- System Configuration Dialog --- Continue with configuration dialog? [yes/no]: [/code] This command will start the automatic setup process, (The same as when you first boot the router) [code]Router#configure terminal [/code] This command &amp;quot;configure terminal&amp;quot; is used to execute configuration commands from the terminal. [code]Router#configure memory[/code] This command &amp;quot;configure memory&amp;quot; is used to execute configuration commands stored in NVRAM. [code]Router#configure network[/code] This command &amp;quot;configure network&amp;quot; is used to retrieve configuration from a TFTP server. [code]Router#copy startup-config running-config[/code] This command &amp;quot;copy startup-config running-config&amp;quot; will copy the startup configuration file to the running configuration file. [code]Router#copy running-config startup-config[/code] This command &amp;quot;copy running-config startup-config&amp;quot; will copy the running configuration fiel to the startup configuration file. [code]Router(config)#boot system flash[/code] This command &amp;quot;boot system flash&amp;quot; will tell the router which IOS file in flash to boot from. [code]Router(config)#boot system tftp[/code] This command &amp;quot;boot system tftp&amp;quot; will tell the router which IOS file on the TFTP server to boot from. [code]Router(config)#boot system rom[/code] This command &amp;quot;boot system rom&amp;quot; will tell the router to boot from ROM at next boot. [code]Router#copy flash tftp:[/code] This command &amp;quot;copy flash tftp:&amp;quot; will copy the flash to a TFTP server. [code]Router#copy tftp flash:[/code] This command &amp;quot;copy tftp flash:&amp;quot; will restore flash from a TFTP server. [code]Router#copy running-config tftp[/code] This command &amp;quot;copy running-config tftp&amp;quot; will copy the current running configuration file to a TFTP server. [code]Router#copy tftp running-config[/code] This command &amp;quot;copy tftp running-config&amp;quot; will restore the running configuration file from a TFTP server. &lt;strong&gt;General Commands:&lt;/strong&gt; [code]Router(config-if)#no shutdown[/code] The command &amp;quot;no shutdown&amp;quot; will enable the interfaces on the router [code]Router#reload[/code] The command &amp;quot;reload&amp;quot; will restart the router. [code]Router#show version[/code] The command &amp;quot;show version&amp;quot; displays the Cisco IOS version, uptime, of the router, how the router started, where the system was loaded from, along with the configuration register. [code]Router#show clock[/code] The command &amp;quot;show clock&amp;quot; will display the date and time. [code]Router#show history[/code] The command &amp;quot;show history&amp;quot; will display the past commands that you entered earlier. [code]Router#show debug[/code] This command &amp;quot;show debug&amp;quot; will show all debugging that is currently enabled. [code]Router#no debug all[/code] The command &amp;quot;no debug all&amp;quot; turns off all possible debugging. [code]Router#show users[/code] This command &amp;quot;show users&amp;quot; will show users that are connected to the router [code]Router#show protocols[/code] This command &amp;quot;show protocols&amp;quot; displays which protocols are configured. [code]Router(config)#banner motd # Enter TEXT message.End with the character &#39;#&#39;.[/code] The command &amp;quot;banner motd&amp;quot; will set or change the banner. (The &amp;quot;#&amp;quot; symbol at the end is a custom symbol the user uses) [code]Router(config)#hostname R1[/code] The command &amp;quot;hostname&amp;quot; is used to configure the hostname of the router (for this example the router&#39;s hostname is &amp;quot;R1&amp;quot;) [code]Router#clear counters[/code] The command &amp;quot;clear counters&amp;quot; will clear the connection counters. &lt;strong&gt;Processes and Statistics&lt;/strong&gt; [code]Router#show processes[/code] The command &amp;quot;show processes&amp;quot; shows the active processes running on the router. [code]Router#show processes cpu[/code] The command &amp;quot;show processes cpu&amp;quot; shows CPU statistics. [code]Router#show memory[/code] The command &amp;quot;show memory&amp;quot; shows memory statistics. [code]Router#show flash[/code] The command &amp;quot;show flash&amp;quot; describes the flash memory and displays the size of the files and the amount of free flash memory. [code]Router#show buffers[/code] The command &amp;quot;show buffers&amp;quot; displays the stats for the router buffer pools. [code]Router#show stacks[/code] The command &amp;quot;show stacks&amp;quot; shows the reason for last reboot, and monitors the stack use of the processes and interrupts routines. &lt;strong&gt;CDP Commands&lt;/strong&gt;- Cisco Discovery Protocol uses a layer 2 multicast over SNAP capable links to send data. [code]Router#show cdp neighbors[/code] Shows directly connected neighbors. [code]Router#show cdp neighbors[/code] Shows and displays more information about the neighbor device. [code]Router#show cdp interface[/code] Shows which interfaces are running CDP. (Example Output) [code]Router#show cdp interface fastEthernet 0/1 Vlan1 is administratively down, line protocol is down Sending CDP packets every 60 seconds Holdtime is 180 seconds FastEthernet0/0 is up, line protocol is down Sending CDP packets every 60 seconds Holdtime is 180 seconds FastEthernet0/1 is administratively down, line protocol is down Sending CDP packets every 60 seconds Holdtime is 180 seconds[/code] Shows CDP information on a specific interface. (Example Output) [code]FastEthernet0/1 is administratively down, line protocol is down Sending CDP packets every 60 seconds Holdtime is 180 seconds[/code]   [code] Router#show cdp entry ? * all CDP neighbor entries WORD Name of CDP neighbor entry[/code] Shows CDP neighbor detail based on the name of that device and or all CDP entries. [code]Router(config)#cdp timer 160[/code] Change how often CDP information is sent. (updates) (This example is 160 seconds this can be any number the default is 60) [code]Router(config)#cdp holdtime 240[/code] Change how long to wait before removing CDP information. (neighbor) (This example is 240 seconds this can be any number the default is 180) [code]Router(config-if)#no cdp enable[/code] Turns off CDP on a specific interface. [code]Router(config-if)#cdp enable[/code] Turns on CDP on a specific interface. [code]Router(config)#cdp run[/code] Turns on CDP globally. (On by default) [code]Router(config)#no cdp run[/code] Turns off CDP globally. &lt;strong&gt;Miscellaneous Commands&lt;/strong&gt; Show detail status of interfaces [code]R1#show controllers ?   Async Async UART internal info   Async Async interface   E1 E1 controller internal state   FastEthernet FastEthernet IEEE 802.3   J1 J1 controller internal state   Serial Serial   T1 T1 controller internal state   T3 T3 controller internal state   XTagATM Extended Tag ATM interface   vsi VSI information | Output modifiers &lt;cr&gt;[/code] To find out if the connected serial interface is DCE or DTE? [code]R1#show controllers serial 0/1 Interface Serial0/1 Hardware is GT96K DCE 530, clock rate 2000000 idb at 0x65F84D48, driver data structure at 0x65F8C454 wic_info 0x65F8CA80 Physical Port 0, SCC Num 0 &lt;Output Omitted&gt;[/code] To configure the clock rate on serial interfaces [code]R1#config t Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. R1(config)#interface serial 0/1 R1(config-if)#clock rate 64000[/code] To set the bandwidth (This is not the physical bandwidth, mainly for routing protocol calculation) [code]R1(config-if)#bandwidth 640[/code] That&#39;s the list! Like before these are the most common and are usually used in the CCNA area when troubleshooting. If you want to find more information check out Cisco documentation and like always I hope this was informative and if you have an idea on the next topic that deals with ICND1 or ICND2 let me know. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/&#34;&gt;Configure IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) via SDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/29/configuring-ssh/&#34;&gt;Configuring SSH&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com/2011/02/17/cisco-ios-routers-auto-secure/&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS Routers: Auto Secure&lt;/a&gt; (systemstechblog.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.answers.com/Q/Which_sequence_does_a_router_follow_during_startup&#34;&gt;Which sequence does a router follow during startup&lt;/a&gt; (wiki.answers.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/&#34;&gt;Configuring Zone Based Firewalls via SDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
