<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Command-line interface on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/command-line-interface/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Command-line interface on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:23:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/command-line-interface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Password Recovery – Cisco IOS Routers</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/07/21/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/07/21/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure In this post I want to cover how to recover passwords on a Cisco IOS Router. This is helpful in lab environments as well as production environments. Although this method can be used the correct &amp;quot;legal&amp;quot; way you can also use this method to break into these devices &amp;quot;illegally&amp;quot; if you have physical console access to the device. However to get into it physical power must be turned off first causing a disruption in the environment, let get started!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Cisco ASA Overview</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Firewall The Cisco 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliances are of course an excellent firewall but the ASA also offers (depending on the model) other security services as well, like IPS systems, VPN, content security, unified communications and remote access. These ASA&#39;s can be used as a standalone appliance&#39; that can handle the need for branch offices to enterprise data centers. Or they can be included in high-performance blades that work together with the Cisco Catalyst 6500 Series, and recently new they can also run in a virtual instance which provides tenant isolation for public and private clouds!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color Code Your Routers</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/11/30/color-code-your-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 17:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/11/30/color-code-your-routers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I came across an interesting idea, what if you could color code your devices in command line? So such as if you were operating routers at a core level you could color code the CLI to the color red, and the branch routers green and etc. I wasn&#39;t sure if this would possible but doing some searching through the internet I found a guy Ivan Pepelnjak who wrote how to do this a couple years ago and wrote a couple books as well, check out his blog/website at http://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure SSH on Dell Power-Connect</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/26/how-to-configure-ssh-on-dell-power-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 15:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/26/how-to-configure-ssh-on-dell-power-connect/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            keys Although not dealing with Cisco directly Dell switches are around in network closets and with my limited experience with them I thought this would be a perfect blog post to show the differences between Dell and Cisco. I like to think of Dell CLI like a dumb downed version of the Cisco CLI so I had some time to play around with a Dell 6248P switch and wanted to figure out how to get SSH working in the thing.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
