<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cisco ASA on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/cisco-asa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cisco ASA on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 15:41:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/cisco-asa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VTIs with ASA</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2020/08/08/vtis-with-asa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 15:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2020/08/08/vtis-with-asa/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve been stuck in more ways then one this year...working from home indefinitely seems to be the status quo right now, and I&#39;m in &amp;quot;tunnel&amp;quot; mode for most part. Most of these projects I&#39;m working on all of common theme.. connect on-premise to more cloud resources! One way to do that is using VTIs. (Virtual Tunnel Interfaces) VTIs which are not new...been around for a bit, Cisco IOS had the feature available like 10+ years ago!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 01:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Cisco Lab When it comes to learning and getting started with Cisco there are some tools that will help out a lot like Packet Tracer, GNS3 and other emulators. These are great tools for that &amp;quot;simulation&amp;quot; of hands on learning, but you can&#39;t always stay in that area. I find it best to get hands on with &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; Cisco Gear and so with this post I&#39;ll go through my current setup of what I have and ask that question when it is a good time to get a lab?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/29/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 01:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/29/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this short but helpful post, I&#39;ll go through the process of upgrading the ASA IOS via the ASDM. This is a pretty painless method if all goes well the only thing you have to do schedule downtime if this box is in production, and grab the ASA IOS image from Cisco. For this post all have been covered let&#39;s get started! First things first is always backup your configuration before upgrading and I always read the release notes that Cisco provides when I download the IOS image, it&#39;s good reading and important because usually new features are introduced and sometime the ASDM can&#39;t paraphrase and parse the new configuration which way I usually upgrade the ASDM first.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Cisco ASA Overview</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Firewall The Cisco 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliances are of course an excellent firewall but the ASA also offers (depending on the model) other security services as well, like IPS systems, VPN, content security, unified communications and remote access. These ASA&#39;s can be used as a standalone appliance&#39; that can handle the need for branch offices to enterprise data centers. Or they can be included in high-performance blades that work together with the Cisco Catalyst 6500 Series, and recently new they can also run in a virtual instance which provides tenant isolation for public and private clouds!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Security - 640-554</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 16:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network-security-lock Out with the old and in with new Cisco is updating its well-known certification CCNA Security. Candidates that are studying for the older exam (640-553) are suggested to take it on or before September 30th 2012. What has changed in the exam? For the most part Cisco SDM is no longer covered, as it has reached its &amp;quot;End of Life&amp;quot; and in fact Cisco Engineering stopped covering the product from developing and testing on February 26th 2012.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
