<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fast-Ethernet on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/fast-ethernet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fast-Ethernet on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 15:56:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/fast-ethernet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuring EtherChannel (PAgb)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 15:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bundling physical links into one logical link is a common practice to up the bandwidth between switches, you may have this also configured on a server to bundle connections as well. In this tutorial I have two 2960 switches both of them trunking all VLANs on two gigabit ports. So in the end game is get 2gbps instead of 1gbps between switches while using Cisco’s proprietary protocol PAgb. It is important to remember that both of these protocols (PAgb and LACP) are link aggregation protocols only, their job is to make sure that EtherChannel is setup correctly by negotiating.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Zone Based Firewalls via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 15:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last month I talked about the fundamentals for understanding zone based firewalls (See the post Understanding Zone Based Firewalls). So for today&#39;s post I want to go ahead and talk about configuring the zone based firewalls but with the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and reduce ownership costs. (See the post Configure Cisco SDM) Instead of talking about what is zone based firewalls lets jump into the configuration of them.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
