<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VirtualBox on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/virtualbox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VirtualBox on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 01:29:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/virtualbox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 Alpha – Install and Setup</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/05/10/gns3-alpha-install-and-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 01:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/05/10/gns3-alpha-install-and-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So Alpha 3 came out last week with a bunch updates and I decided to give it run this week. I&#39;m not doing anything that difficult with the program so maybe I&#39;m not breaking it in all the way but I also was looking at some installation notes for Ubuntu and other Linux flavors, I figured I’ll try to install it on a Windows machine and not Linux (call me lazy) feel free to follow this guide.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look at GNS3 - New Version</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/07/06/look-at-gns3-new-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 18:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/07/06/look-at-gns3-new-version/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Look at GNS3 - New Version: A new version of GNS3 released on July 5th 2013 is available for download. You can download GNS3 v0.8.4 at gns3.net. This release includes improvements and new features. Some of the important one are:
Lots of GUI improvements. New hub device. New Idlemax and Idlesleep settings (advanced manipulation of IDLE PC). IOS image and settings test button. New Tool menu to start external scripts/tools. Drag &amp;amp; drop of multiple devices when pressing SHIFT.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 8 Developer Preview</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/12/windows-8-developer-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 17:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/12/windows-8-developer-preview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Changing topics for today, I want to talk about the Windows 8 Developer Preview which was released on September 13th. I had the time to install it under virtual box and was pleasantly surprised! About how fast it installed the easy to understand install prompts and the new &amp;quot;Metro&amp;quot; UI which is aimed at touched devices. Also the ability to switch to the standard Windows operating system. This is an alpha build so it&#39;s not even on at the beta stages yet, Take a look for yourself!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
