<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reflection on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reflection on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 15:37:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The World Keeps Turning</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/05/21/the-world-keeps-turning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 15:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/05/21/the-world-keeps-turning/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Well..couple of things have changed these past months that have had a lasting impact on everyone on this earth. A single reminder that we all share a common home on this place, even though we sometimes think were world&#39;s apart from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time I&#39;ve been working from home, and busier then ever making sure the lights stay on. I like to think of myself as a lighthouse keeper or some type of engineer maintaining a spacecraft floating in space sending &amp;quot;pings&amp;quot; waiting for reply... We&#39;ll get a response and when we do, we&#39;ll be ready for the next adventure, we always are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are changing around us, and every change is different depending where you are and who you are. One thing is for sure life events happen to us all the time but I think its important that we step back for a second and self-reflect on them, because that’s when things happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ups and downs personal and professional let these events change you throughout your life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about them, self-reflect on them, it’s these milestones that I believe are so important and ultimately the purpose of life. Let&#39;s take what we&#39;ve learned, continue to learn, pull ourselves and others up because this is the place we call home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2020/08/08/vtis-with-asa/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;VTIs with ASA – Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-08-08 09:41:19&#34;&gt;Aug 6, 2020&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] The World Keeps Turning and we’ll continue to navigate the times as technology plays such a critical piece in making sure communication between people and or systems goes uninterrupted. We as engineers are right in the middle of it… like always I hope this information is helpful, stay calm and carry on! […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/01/04/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 05:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/01/04/goals/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Every year I think about goals, either how to conquer them, reflect on them, and recently change them. We all have been there, we have a plan in our head that we follow for a handful of years or even decades... something happens... all of sudden things change. It&#39;s this change that I believe is so important to life, we can&#39;t and shouldn&#39;t be static, we have to change in order to grow ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life events happen to us all the time, the big ones that have happen to me are things like, collage graduation, this website!, my first career job as Network Engineer, unexpected loss of a family member, a new job, moving, my first home, promotions, all of which happened in the last decade. 2019 was such special year for me and I&#39;ll remember it for the rest my life, so much has happen to me personally...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope everyone allows themselves to be able to experience these life events, ups and downs personal or professional let these change you, that&#39;s really the whole point of life...which in turn allows you to find who you are truly, and that should be everyone&#39;s goal. I started this blog to get better at writing, teaching people about networking and my overall experiences in this field. I really didn&#39;t care if someone stumbled on it in the beginning, however over time that changed, I love this! I&#39;m not saying goodbye, but what happens next is anyone&#39;s guess, and that&#39;s how I think life works the best! - Ryan :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-comments&#34;&gt;Static Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2020/08/15/its-always-changing/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;It’s Always Changing – Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-08-15 13:35:59&#34;&gt;Aug 6, 2020&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] last year I recognized my personal life had been the status quo for way too long. I talked about Goals. I started to think about where do I see my personal life in five, ten, twenty years from now? What […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
