<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BGP on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/bgp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BGP on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 18:13:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/bgp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fortigate ECMP with BGP</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/10/11/fortigate-ecmp-with-bgp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 18:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2020/10/11/fortigate-ecmp-with-bgp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s like clock work...around this time the seasons are changing..autumn colors are out, and the colder air reminds us that things are changing around here, embrace it! One thing that I&#39;ve been working with is AWS Transit gateways, a common theme this year is all cloud! AWS Transit Gateways make it easier to move towards that!
AWS Transit gateways relatively new, (couple years old now) so instead of attaching to each AWS VPC environment independently we can connect to the transit gateway and attach VPCs to the gateway.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Routing Protocols</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 16:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/04/dynamic-routing-protocols/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dynamic Routing If you ever wanted to set up a network manually, you will quickly find how much overhead is required to get PCs, printers, and other network equipment. That&#39;s where dynamic routing protocols come into play although they are helpful I strongly urge you to understand static routing first. (See the post Configure Static Routing) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s get the foundation of understanding dynamic routing protocols. By definition a routing protocol is a set of messages, rules and algorithms used by routers for the overall purpose of learning routes to other networks not physically connected to it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
