<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethernet on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/ethernet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ethernet on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/ethernet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network-diagram In a perfect world we would never need redundancy on a network infrastructure, but as you know as well as I know we don&#39;t live in a perfect world. Hardware will eventually fail, bottlenecks will appear, and the speed of our network will become slower when we max the bandwidth on links. So having redundancy in routers, connections, and having a hierarchy network is one of best choices to make when improving the efficiently of the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VTP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some people hate it, some people love it. It&#39;s the Cisco proprietary VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) which in short means that Cisco switches can exchange VLAN configuration, instead of manually configuring each switch with the same VLANs. I also suggest if you don&#39;t know what a VLAN is check out the post Creating VLANs Let&#39;s get right into understanding VTP. The thing that makes VTP shine is what it does, although simple to understand it saves time by automatically distributing VLAN information.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossover or Straight through?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 18:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/10/crossover-or-straight-through/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The EIA/TIA puts the standards in UTP cable, and when cabling a network there are two standards. T568A and T568B these standards are important when deciding to put a crossover cable or straight through cable This tutorial is going to be talking about when and where to apply these different standards. We are going to be focusing on the UTP cable and with the RJ-45 connectors; in order for the communication to work properly we need to make sure we understand where to put these cables.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
