<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Classless Inter-Domain Routing on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/classless-inter-domain-routing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classless Inter-Domain Routing on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 02:06:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/classless-inter-domain-routing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 2 – The Joys of Subnetttting – VLSM!</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 02:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So here we are on Part 2 of subnetting. What makes me laugh is that I really think a lot of people over think this stuff, and the fact that I mispelled subnetting! (Really? 4Ts) It&#39;s really not the complicated and it should not scare you. Another thing to mention is that usually in the real world you usually have calculators and another pair of eyes to double-check your work unlike the exam you will need to fully understand it if you would like to pass the ICND2 or the CCNA test.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classful vs. Classless Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 16:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud-Computing-icon Before the internet and general networking become popular into what it is now, there were and still are routing protocols that only do classful routing. What is classful routing? When I was talking about Dynamic Routing earlier (See the post Dynamic Routing Protocols) I mentioned there was a difference between classful routing and classless routing. So in today&#39;s post let&#39;s focus on these two but important topics when using routing protocols.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
