<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open source on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open source on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 18:05:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Graylog with AWS Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2019/06/21/graylog-with-aws-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 18:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2019/06/21/graylog-with-aws-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Graylog has been through some changes last time I talked about them, hitting version 3.0 in February is awesome and one of things that make Graylog run well is Elasticsearch backend. Although Elasticsearch is not too hard to setup it usually runs better on bare metal, so there is cost of that as well as maintenance of the cluster is important, updates and upgrades. Depending your team experience you may not have time to learn it or run it the way it should be.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Dance</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2018/11/13/automation-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 15:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2018/11/13/automation-dance/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I keep doing the automation dance, (yeah...that&#39;s me) there are a lot of different tooling products out there. I have been trying to understand a use case around using it with network automation. Recently I have been dancing around with Ansible. My personal belief is that using any type of these tools would be helpful but it can be a steep learning curve if you really don&#39;t have any programming knowledge.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing a GNS3 Server</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2018/08/17/installing-a-gns3-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 14:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2018/08/17/installing-a-gns3-server/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although GNS3 can run local on your computer and you can use VMware Workstation and have the GNS3 appliance. I found it much more stable and predictable to run GNS3 on a dedicated server. Using this type of installation, all the projects, and images are stored on the GNS3 server, so I can install the GNS3 client any computer and get access to the same projects I was working on. You can also have multiple people working on different projects that are on the same server.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 1.0 Campaign</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/11/21/gns3-1.0-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 06:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/11/21/gns3-1.0-campaign/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s been almost 24 hours since GNS3 launched a campaign to bring in funds to support the open source network simulator and bring it up to version 1.0. A lot of new features are on the list, like switching, cloud processing, hassle free configuration, labs/training materials and 3rd party integrations. All of which are in the works for this new version added along with some pretty cool plug-ins. As of writing this post they are at $106,973 dollars which is 300 percent over funded!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
