<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cisco router on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/cisco-router/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cisco router on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 05:30:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/cisco-router/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Archive your Configuration</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/01/22/archive-your-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 05:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/01/22/archive-your-configuration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hard20drive-black.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hard20drive-black.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hard-Drive&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It is important to save your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Router (computing)&#34;&gt;router&lt;/a&gt; and switch configuration but what happens if the device fails or if you saved a configuration mistake, without having to manually worry about it? Well if your Cisco router or switch has &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; 12.3T and higher you would be able to set up an auto archive within the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_memory&#34; title=&#34;Flash memory&#34;&gt;flash memory&lt;/a&gt; of the unit or you can send that configuration file to a server that does either &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;File Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;FTP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypertext_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Hypertext Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt;, SCP. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trivial_File_Transfer_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Trivial File Transfer Protocol&#34;&gt;TFTP&lt;/a&gt;, etc. Let&#39;s work through on setting up the archive feature on a Cisco Router. In this example we will look at one way to archive your configuration to the flash memory of the unit. This is good if you want the ability to revert back quickly to an existing configuration that has been saved in flash. Keep in mind this is not the only way to archive your configuration, instead of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Archive&#34; title=&#34;Archive&#34;&gt;archiving&lt;/a&gt; it to flash memory you could back it up on a server using some common transfer file protocol like FTP, TFTP and other options. Let&#39;s start setting up the archive feature so I&#39;m on the HQ Router and to archive to flash, the first thing we have to do is enter configuration mode followed by typing &lt;strong&gt;archive&lt;/strong&gt; and hit enter. [code]HQ#configure terminal Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. HQ(config)#archive HQ(config-archive)#[/code] You will notice we are in the archive configuration mode hit the question to see the available commands. [code]HQ(config-archive)#? Archive configuration commands: default Set a command to its defaults exit Exit from archive configuration mode log Logging commands maximum maximum number of backup copies no Negate a command or set its defaults path path for backups rollback Rollback parameters time-period Period of time in minutes to automatically archive the running-config write-memory Enable automatic backup generation during write memory[/code] For this we will put are configuration on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_file_system&#34; title=&#34;Flash file system&#34;&gt;flash file system&lt;/a&gt; let&#39;s keep it simple by just calling it &lt;strong&gt;HQ-RTR.config&lt;/strong&gt; here is our example: [code]HQ(config-archive)#path flash:HQ-RTR.config[/code] This writes the configuration into flash and by default writes up to ten and then rolls them over. This is also where you could point this path to an FTP/TFTP server instead of flash. To archive your configuration while under the &lt;strong&gt;config-archive&lt;/strong&gt; mode you have two choices, both of these options could be used together. The write-memory option will archive you configuration after you issue the &lt;strong&gt;copy running-config startup-config&lt;/strong&gt; command. The time-period command will write the configuration to flash every &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; amount minutes. Where &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; is the number of minutes you specify after the command. See an example of both commands below: [code]HQ(config-archive)#write-memory HQ(config-archive)#time-period 500000[/code] To see your archives you can issue the command show archive, in this example I have two archives located in flash. This command would also work if you are storing them on a FTP/TFTP server. [code]HQ#show archive There are currently 3 archive configurations saved. The next archive file will be named flash:HQ-RTR.config-3 Archive # Name 0 1 flash:HQ-RTR.config-1 2 flash:HQ-RTR.config-2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14[/code] You can also see these archives in the flash file system by issuing the &lt;strong&gt;show flash&lt;/strong&gt; command. [code]HQ#show flash: -#- --length-- -----date/time------ path 1 19939672 Sep 16 2008 15:51:54 +00:00 c1841-spservicesk9-mz.124-6.T7.bin 2 1122 Jan 22 2013 03:49:18 +00:00 HQ-RTR.config-1 3 1142 Jan 22 2013 03:54:28 +00:00 HQ-RTR.config-2 44060672 bytes available (19951616 bytes used)[/code] Let&#39;s roll back from an archive, to do this it is pretty simple just use the &lt;strong&gt;configure replace&lt;/strong&gt; command followed by &lt;strong&gt;archive&lt;/strong&gt; and the archive file you would like to replace the running-config. Let&#39;s look below and see the process as an example. [code]HQ#configure replace archive:flash:HQ-RTR.config-2 This will apply all necessary additions and deletions to replace the current running configuration with the contents of the specified configuration file, which is assumed to be a complete configuration, not a partial configuration. Enter Y if you are sure you want to proceed. ? [no]: Y HQ#[/code] That&#39;s it! You can either put these archives on the flash of the device or you can setup a simple FTP, TFTP, SCP, etc. box and have your configurations stored there. Like always I hope this information is helpful and post below if you have questions about this topic.You can also find more information on Cisco&#39;s website about the archiving along with the configure replace and rollback commands. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/ios/12_3t/12_3t7/feature/guide/gtrollbk.html#wp1066264&#34; title=&#34;Configuration Replace and Configuration Rollback&#34;&gt;Configuration Replace and Configuration Rollback&lt;/a&gt; Enjoy! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/12/01/configure-dhcp-on-a-cisco-router/&#34;&gt;Configure DHCP on a Cisco Router&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rekrowten.wordpress.com/2012/12/26/how-to-remove-tracked-interface-from-hsrp/&#34;&gt;How to Remove Tracked Interface from HSRP&lt;/a&gt; (rekrowten.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sucuri.net/2012/11/psa-sftpftp-password-exposure-via-sftp-config-json.html&#34;&gt;SFTP/FTP Password Exposure via sftp-config.json&lt;/a&gt; (sucuri.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Security - 640-554</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 16:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/network-security-lock.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/network-security-lock.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;network-security-lock&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Out with the old and in with new Cisco is updating its well-known certification &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Career_Certifications&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Career Certifications&#34;&gt;CCNA Security&lt;/a&gt;. Candidates that are studying for the older exam (640-553) are suggested to take it on or before September 30th 2012. What has changed in the exam? For the most part Cisco SDM is no longer covered, as it has reached its &amp;quot;End of Life&amp;quot; and in fact Cisco Engineering stopped covering the product from developing and testing on February 26th 2012. You can still renew the product for support (Cisco SmartNet) until March 24th of 2013 and the last date the product will get support will be February 28th of 2014 after that it will become an old friend :). Let&#39;s compare these two CCNA Security Exams and see what has changed, removed and added. (640-553 &amp;amp; 640-554)  I have compared these two exams side-by-side. If you take look at these two exams, the red on the older exam means it is no longer covered on the (640-554 exam) and the blue on the new exam is new material that is not covered on the (640-553 exam). For the most part Cisco SDM is no longer available instead it is the Cisco Configuration Professional along with that the new exam mentions the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_ASA&#34; title=&#34;Cisco ASA&#34;&gt;Cisco ASA&lt;/a&gt; system and walking you into the ASDM along with the different products and services the ASA system offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCNA Security Exam Topics – (640-553)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Describe the security threats facing modern network infrastructures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe and list mitigation methods for common network attacks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe and list mitigation methods for Worm, Virus, and Trojan Horse attacks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the Cisco Self Defending Network architecture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure Cisco routers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure Cisco routers using the SDM Security Audit feature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the One-Step Lockdown feature in SDM to secure a Cisco router&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure administrative access to Cisco routers by setting strong encrypted passwords, exec timeout, login failure rate and using IOS login enhancements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure administrative access to Cisco routers by configuring multiple privilege levels&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure administrative access to Cisco routers by configuring role based &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Command-line_interface&#34; title=&#34;Command-line interface&#34;&gt;CLI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; image and configuration file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement AAA on Cisco routers using local router database and external ACS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain the functions and importance of AAA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the features of TACACS+ and RADIUS AAA protocols&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure AAA authentication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure AAA authorization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure AAA accounting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigate threats to Cisco routers and networks using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_control_list&#34; title=&#34;Access control list&#34;&gt;ACLs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain the functionality of standard, extended, and named &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Protocol&#34;&gt;IP&lt;/a&gt; ACLs used by routers to filter packets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure and verify IP ACLs to mitigate given threats (filter IP traffic destined for Telnet, SNMP, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denial-of-service_attack&#34; title=&#34;Denial-of-service attack&#34;&gt;DDoS attacks&lt;/a&gt;) in a network using CLI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure IP ACLs to prevent &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address_spoofing&#34; title=&#34;IP address spoofing&#34;&gt;IP address spoofing&lt;/a&gt; using CLI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss the caveats to be considered when building ACLs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement secure network management and reporting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use CLI and SDM to configure SSH on Cisco routers to enable secured management access&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use CLI and SDM to configure Cisco routers to send Syslog messages to a Syslog server&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigate common Layer 2 attacks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe how to prevent layer 2 attacks by configuring basic &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Catalyst&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Catalyst&#34;&gt;Catalyst switch&lt;/a&gt; security features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement the Cisco IOS firewall feature set using SDM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the operational strengths and weaknesses of the different firewall technologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain stateful firewall operations and the function of the state table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement Zone Based Firewall using SDM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement the Cisco IOS IPS feature set using SDM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Define network based vs. host based intrusion detection and prevention&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain IPS technologies, attack responses, and monitoring options&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enable and verify Cisco IOS IPS operations using SDM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement site-to-site &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network&#34; title=&#34;Virtual private network&#34;&gt;VPNs&lt;/a&gt; on Cisco Routers using SDM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain the different methods used in cryptography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain IKE protocol functionality and phases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the building blocks of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPsec&#34; title=&#34;IPsec&#34;&gt;IPSec&lt;/a&gt; and the security functions it provides&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure and verify an IPSec site-to-site VPN with pre-shared key authentication using SDM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCNA Security Exam Topics – (640-554)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Common Security Threats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe common security threats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security and Cisco Routers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement security on Cisco routers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe securing the control, data, and management plane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Security_Manager&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Security Manager&#34;&gt;Cisco Security Manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe IPv4 to IPv6 transition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AAA on Cisco Devices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement AAA (authentication, authorization, and accounting)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe TACACS+&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe RADIUS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe AAA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verify AAA functionality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IOS ACLs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe standard, extended, and named IP IOS access control lists (ACLs) to filter packets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe considerations when building ACLs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement IP ACLs to mitigate threats in a network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure Network Management and Reporting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe secure network management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement secure network management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Layer 2 Attacks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe Layer 2 security using Cisco switches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe VLAN security&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement VLANs and trunking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement spanning tree&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cisco Firewall Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe operational strengths and weaknesses of the different firewall technologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe stateful firewalls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the types of NAT used in firewall technologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement zone-based policy firewall using CCP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement the Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement Network Address Translation (NAT) and Port Address Translation (PAT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cisco IPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe Cisco Intrusion Prevention System (IPS) deployment considerations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe IPS technologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure Cisco IOS IPS using CCP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VPN Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the different methods used in cryptography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe VPN technologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the building blocks of IPSec&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement an IOS IPSec site-to-site VPN with pre-shared key authentication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verify VPN operations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) VPN using ASA device manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part if you have older books and products that cover the 640-553 exam continue studying as you can see when you compare these exams the fundamentals stay the same and if you think you can take it before September 30th go ahead and go for it! For me I want to take the new exam so I&#39;ll take it after September 30th. I also have some good tutorials that cover SDM like (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34; title=&#34;Configure Cisco SDM&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM&lt;/a&gt;) back a year ago on this blog along with some security topics like AAA an Radius and TACACS+ go ahead search for them! If you are like me and want to get your hands on some books that cover the new exam (640-554) you will have to wait until July 16th for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/CCNA-Security-640-554-Official-Guide/dp/1587204460/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1338222713&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; title=&#34;CCNA Security 640-554 Official Cert Guide &#34;&gt;Official Certification Guide&lt;/a&gt; according to Amazon but you can go head and order the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Security-640-554-Portable-Command-Guide/dp/1587204487/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1338222713&amp;amp;sr=8-2&#34; title=&#34;CCNA Security (640-554) Portable Command Guide&#34;&gt;CCNA Security Portable Command Guide&lt;/a&gt; which released today. Like always I hope this information is helpful, if you have questions feel free to post them :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/&#34;&gt;ICND2 - Passed!&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.net-security.org/secworld.php?id=12515&#34;&gt;Cisco updates security certs&lt;/a&gt; (net-security.org)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22adamsiewert@mbk.com%22&#34;&gt;adam&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-08-06 16:39:53&#34;&gt;Aug 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you use for labs? hardware or virtualized? if virtualized, do you use gns3 if hardware, where did you get your hardware form? Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-08-06 18:18:47&#34;&gt;Aug 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Adam, I have used both and GNS3 works for routers well, but for switches it does not support them well. For the physical gear eBay is a pretty good spot. Hope that helps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Password Recovery – Cisco IOS Routers | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2012/07/21/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-07-21 11:04:29&#34;&gt;Jul 6, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] CCNA Security – 640-554 (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/28/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-28 19:25:05&#34;&gt;Jun 4, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] CCNA Security – 640-554 (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Basic Cisco ASA Overview | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-24 11:50:56&#34;&gt;Jun 0, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-07-03 23:34:16&#34;&gt;Jul 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glad I could help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Rujvelt](http://ipsol.net &#34;rujvelt.tbs@gmail.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-07-03 05:30:34&#34;&gt;Jul 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good comparison shown......red and blue which gives idea of new exam material Thanks for infomation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Router on a Stick</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/01/configure-router-on-a-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 03:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/01/configure-router-on-a-stick/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;A while ago I talked about putting different &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_LAN&#34; title=&#34;Virtual LAN&#34;&gt;VLANs&lt;/a&gt; on a switch, remember a VLAN is virtual network that although physically it may look like on the same network that does not always mean the case. By having VLANs you are segmenting the network and the only way to get to the other side is having a router. I have already configured the Cisco switch as posted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/&#34; title=&#34;Creating VLANs&#34;&gt;Creating VLANs&lt;/a&gt; but in summary I have three VLANs total VLAN 1 which is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Inter-Switch_Link&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Inter-Switch Link&#34;&gt;native VLAN&lt;/a&gt;, VLAN 2 and VLAN 3 (which is called support. If you like to understand how create VLANs on a switch follow the post above. If you look at the network topology below you can see where Cisco came up with the name &amp;quot;Router on Stick&amp;quot; each PC is on its own network and needs the router in order for traffic to pass between the networks. Like before I have three VLANs total. VLAN 1 which is the native VLAN, VLAN 2 and VLAN 3 (which is called &amp;quot;Support&amp;quot;). &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/01/31/configure-router-on-a-stick/router-on-a-sticke/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/router-on-a-sticke.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Router-On-A-Stick&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You have to create sub-interfaces on the router to route between different VLANs these sub-interfaces do not correspond to the VLANs so you could put any number but for manageability usually people use the same sub-interface has the VLAN ID. To create a sub-interface start typing the interface that will be physically connected to the switch at the end add a period and number. [code]Router#config t Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. Router(config)#interface fastEthernet 0/0.2 Router(config-subif)#[/code] You are now in the sub-interface configuration, we want to tell the router which VLAN this interface will be a part of. In this example I am typing &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;encapsulation dot1Q 2&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; dot1Q is an IEEE standard 802.1Q , the number &amp;quot;two&amp;quot; is the VLAN this interface will be a part of. Just like a real interface this interface must have an IP address for end devices to reach it. In this example we are using 192.168.2.1 with a Class C subnet mask. (i.e 255.255.255.0) [code]Router(config-subif)#encapsulation dot1Q 2 Router(config-subif)#ip address 192.168.2.1 255.255.255.0 Router(config-subif)#no shut[/code] We do the same for VLAN 3 (Support) in which we will create a new sub-interface in this example I am using sub-interface 3, and I&#39;m going to be putting this sub-interface in VLAN 3 by using &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;encapsulation dot1Q 3&amp;quot;.&lt;/strong&gt; Remember the sub-interface number has no effect on which VLAN this interface is a part of. I&#39;m also adding a IP address of 192.168.3.1 with a Class C subnet mask. [code]Router#config t Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. Router(config)#interface fastEthernet 0/0.3 Router(config-subif)# Router(config-subif)#encapsulation dot1Q 3 Router(config-subif)#ip address 192.168.3.1 255.255.255.0 Router(config-subif)#no shut[/code] The last VLAN is the native VLAN and by default is VLAN 1, for this configuration go to the physical interface and add an IP address for this example we are using 192.168.1.1 with a Class C subnet mask. [code]Router#config t Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. Router(config)#interface fastEthernet 0/0 Router(config-if)#ip address 192.168.1.1 255.255.255.0 Router(config-if)#no shut[/code] The last thing we have to setup is on the Cisco Switch in which we have to specify which interface on the switch will pass all the VLANs, this is known as the trunking port. Go into configuration mode and for this example we selected FastEthernet0/1 apply the &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;switchport mode trunk&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; command and since we are using the default native VLAN which is not always recommended that&#39;s all the configuration needed. We now have three different networks separated by VLANs, if you issue a &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;show ip route&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; on the router we will see each sub-interface and route to each of them. All devices should be able to ping each other. [code]Switch&amp;gt;en Switch#config t Enter configuration commands, one per line. End with CNTL/Z. Switch(config)#interface fastEthernet 0/1 Switch(config-if)#switchport mode trunk[/code] [code]Router#show ip route Codes: C - connected, S - static, I - IGRP, R - RIP, M - mobile, B - BGP D - EIGRP, EX - EIGRP external, O - OSPF, IA - OSPF inter area N1 - OSPF NSSA external type 1, N2 - OSPF NSSA external type 2 E1 - OSPF external type 1, E2 - OSPF external type 2, E - EGP i - IS-IS, L1 - IS-IS level-1, L2 - IS-IS level-2, ia - IS-IS inter area * - candidate default, U - per-user static route, o - ODR P - periodic downloaded static route Gateway of last resort is not set C 192.168.1.0/24 is directly connected, FastEthernet0/0 C 192.168.2.0/24 is directly connected, FastEthernet0/0.2 C 192.168.3.0/24 is directly connected, FastEthernet0/0.3[/code] I hope this information is helpful I have also attached a PDF of the running-config of both devices to give you an example of the configuration. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/router-on-stick-example-runconfig.pdf&#34;&gt;Router-On-Stick-Example-RunConfig&lt;/a&gt;) If you have any questions post them below. Like always if you an idea of the next topic let me hear it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/11/02/ospf-what-a-protocol/&#34;&gt;OSPF...What a Protocol!&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ipv6area.wordpress.com/2011/12/08/what-is-ipv6-an-introduction-to-ipv6/&#34;&gt;What is IPv6 ? An introduction to IPV6&lt;/a&gt; (ipv6area.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edugeek.net/forums/networks/89609-guest-vlans-guest-wifi-different-ip-range-out-filtered-internet.html&#34;&gt;Guest VLANS + Guest Wifi - Different IP Range, Out to Filtered Internet&lt;/a&gt; (edugeek.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mungauwamaseghe.wordpress.com/2012/01/31/journey-to-the-ccie-lab-part-44-bgp-link-bandwidth/&#34;&gt;Journey to the CCIE LAB - Part 44 - BGP Link Bandwidth&lt;/a&gt; (mungauwamaseghe.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gravatar.com/aslan77777&#34; title=&#34;ciscodaze@live.com&#34;&gt;Theophilus&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-08 17:11:20&#34;&gt;Jun 5, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw your comment on not having to use the encap command when using the actual interface (fa0/0), but I was wondering, (since you typically see books and tutorials NOT using the actual interface, but instead, typically fa0/0.1), are there any other ramifications to using one as opposed to the other?? Fa0/0 as opposed to Fa0/0.1?? Thanks, Kevin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Theophilus](http://aslan77777.wordpress.com &#34;ciscodaze@live.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-08 17:17:52&#34;&gt;Jun 5, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besided the encapsulation command, are there any ramifications to using Fa0/0 for vlan 1 (instead of Fa0/0.1, as typically shown in ROAS configs)? Thanks, Kevin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-08 18:13:58&#34;&gt;Jun 5, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Kevin, The only reason this is set on the physical interface is because it is using un-tagged traffic also know as the native VLAN. You can&#39;t set the encapsulation dot1q on a physical interface only sub-interfaces. A better way to do this is use a sub-interface followed by: encapsulation dot1Q [VLAN-ID] native I don&#39;t see any problems with this method besides security and monitoring. For example If you wanted to see all traffic passing in and out of the physical interface using Netflow or SNMP you would not see that in this example, you would only see the native VLAN traffic. For security you should not use the native VLAN in production so this example it is not using best practices therefore I would not recommend it. This post goes along with another post I did about creating VLANs on a switch: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/&#34;&gt;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/01/creating-vlans/&lt;/a&gt; Hope that Helps, Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Part 1 &amp;#8211; The Joys of Subnetting! | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/01/part-1-the-joys-of-subnetting/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-01 15:03:41&#34;&gt;Apr 0, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configure Router on a Stick (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Part 2 – The Joys of Subnetttting – VLSM! | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2012/04/23/part-2-the-joys-of-subnetttting-vlsm/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-23 21:08:49&#34;&gt;Apr 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configure Router on a Stick (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[How to configure a Catalyst 3750/3750-E/3750-X Series Switches Using LLDP (Link Layer Discovery Protocol) &amp;laquo; Pete&amp;#039;s Packet](http://petespacket.com/2012/03/08/how-to-configure-a-catalyst-37503750-e3750-x-series-switches-using-lldp-link-layer-discovery-protocol/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-03-08 14:00:56&#34;&gt;Mar 4, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configure Router on a Stick [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-01-31 22:34:25&#34;&gt;Jan 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are talking about the trunk link between the switch and the router it will pass up to the router and then be forwarded back down to the switch. So if you had a lot of traffic being forwarded between networks you could run into some bandwidth limits. To fix that you could configure a switch that does layer 3 routing and skip the router all together that way you would not be dependent on that one link to forward all of your traffic back and forth. The native VLAN by default is VLAN 1 and that can be changed. The only difference between a native VLAN and a regular VLAN is it passes un-tagged traffic. If you look at the router configuration I&#39;ve setup, the physical interface (fa0/0) notice how I don&#39;t have to put the encapsulation, because this is traffic is not tagged with a VLAN. To answer you question you can put everything on a VLAN and forget about the default/native VLAN. A good practice to use is to change it to a non-default number something other than 1 and a VLAN that you are not using in your network. However make sure every switch has the correct native VLAN or you will get messages about native VLAN mismatched. Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Philip](http://www.studio1250.com &#34;philip@studio1250.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-02-23 13:58:30&#34;&gt;Feb 4, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great article! Thanks for the info. I was talking to my friend about this last night and when I got into packet tracer I couldn&#39;t quite figure out how to assign multiple ip addresses to a single interface. I&#39;m glad you took the time to write up this example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-02-23 20:32:32&#34;&gt;Feb 4, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glad I could help. :) The configuration is pretty straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Theophilus](http://gravatar.com/aslan77777 &#34;ciscodaze@live.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-10 14:34:04&#34;&gt;Jun 0, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Trunking Administrative Modes | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/11/trunking-administrative-modes/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-02-11 16:05:33&#34;&gt;Feb 6, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[EIGRP… The Basics | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/28/eigrp-the-basics/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-02-28 19:53:58&#34;&gt;Feb 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Configure Router on a Stick (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[ITforMe](http://gravatar.com/pedrok00 &#34;peter.gavin@live.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-01-31 21:21:36&#34;&gt;Jan 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good post. Thanks for sharing. Can you confirm that with intervlan routing, that one would not run into the bandwidth limitations imposed by a traditional upstream router? (e.g. say, 50 ports feeding upstream to a physical router only to pipe back down into the switch). In other words, is a router on a stick configuration smart enough to know that if it needs to route across two VLANs that happen to live on the same port, that it isolates the flow of traffic to just that port? I&#39;m also interested in what your thoughts are on the default VLAN 1. It seems that it is often more than just the factory VLAN, but that it may hold special characteristics and limitations (e.g. routing, etc.). If that is the case, would you suggest taking a new stack of switches, and making all of the untagged ports to the systems/workstations on something like VLAN101, with a PVID of 101, so as to prevent any traffic from going across the default VLAN?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
