<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cisco Career Certifications on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/cisco-career-certifications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cisco Career Certifications on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 02:22:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/cisco-career-certifications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Converting Hexadecimal to Decimal and Binary</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/04/22/converting-hexadecimal-to-decimal-and-binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 02:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2015/04/22/converting-hexadecimal-to-decimal-and-binary/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The purpose of this post is to reference the CCNA Data Center (640-911) exam. This exam starts the conversation of IPv6 and since IPv6 is hexadecimal this post starts the talk about how we look at a hexadecimal values and learn how to convert them to binary and decimal. If you know subnetting skills then this won’t be that difficult. If you are new then check out The Wonders of Binary post as well as Part 1 and Part 2 of subnetting.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco VIRL is out ... for a price</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/12/05/cisco-virl-is-out-...-for-a-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 03:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/12/05/cisco-virl-is-out-...-for-a-price/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just wanted to put this up has Cisco has recently released VIRL. This is a network simulation platform that you can run Cisco operating systems on which are the same operating systems that run on Cisco hardware so anything you do in this simulation environment would be realistic if it was running on dedicated hardware. You would be able to test your changes before throwing them in production. Some things that are different between VIRL and CML (Cisco Modeling Labs)
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 1.0 Public is Out</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/10/21/gns3-1.0-public-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 20:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/10/21/gns3-1.0-public-is-out/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get your IOS, IOU, XRV, 1000v, HP, Juniper, Arista, and other images ready because that&#39;s the beauty of GNS3, it&#39;s here and ready to download. I&#39;m excited for this release although the last post I did was In May of 2014, which was about getting GNS3 Alpha 3 working on Windows, you can see the full post here: GNS3 Alpha – Install and Setup. I have followed the GNS3 releases throughout the six months of them releasing Alpha and beta releases, as well as looking at changlogs of each release.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Enhanced vPC on Nexus 5600</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/09/10/setting-up-enhanced-vpc-on-nexus-5600/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/09/10/setting-up-enhanced-vpc-on-nexus-5600/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I&#39;ve played around with two Cisco Nexus 5672UP switches which will be in production soon but before that I wanted to see what it took to get enhanced vPC online. Along the way I was into some new territory as I never stood up vPC before, so in this post I have posted some things to keep in mind and running-config examples, all of which I hope is helpful for a reference.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 12 &amp; 13)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/04/19/640-911-chapter-12-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 16:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/04/19/640-911-chapter-12-13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are at the last chapters of the CCNA Data Center 640-911 by Todd Lammle. Chapter 12 talks about redundant switched technologies and chapter 13 talks about security. Just like before I will go over the high-points, so let’s get started!
Chapter 12 Overview: In this chapter we get to learn about Spanning Tree Protocol and some history with it. With networks we like multiple ways to a destination however in the layer two area redundancy does not play well and that’s where spanning tree can help us.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 10 &amp; 11)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 01:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/04/16/640-911-chapter-10-11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just like before if you have followed, I have gone over the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle and in this post we cover two chapters. Feel free to comment below if you have any questions on either of these two chapters.
Chapter 10 Overview: Chapter 10 starts us back in the book, before we do any configuring and we learn about routing protocols, and remember the difference between static and dynamic routing (name implies it) Also know the default administrate distances of the different routing protocols (starts on page 297).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 8 &amp; 9)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/03/30/640-911-chapter-8-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 17:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/03/30/640-911-chapter-8-9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back where we left off, if you have followed I have gone over the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle and in this post we will cover two chapters 8 and 9. Comment below if you have any questions on these two chapters let&#39;s get started.
Chapter 8 Overview: We are actually making some progress, we configure the NX-OS with CLI there is not a GUI that I am aware of although SDN could be kind of in there but for this exam it does not even exist.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 7)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/27/640-911-chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you made it past the earlier chapters this one should be interesting, like before I am going through each chapter of the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Comment below if you have questions in this chapter, last week we learned about subnetting and in this chapter we will learn about the NX-OS which is Cisco&#39;s Data Center switches. Let&#39;s begin! Overview: This was short chapter in introducing the NX-OS product line and into the virtualized enviroments that data centers are now becoming.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 6)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/20/640-911-chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 19:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/20/640-911-chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s start chapter six of the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle, feel free to post questions if you have any. Like before I have covered the topics of the each chapter. Last week we learned about the different IP classes and today we get a course in subnetting. Let&#39;s go over what you should know if you want to pass the exam.
Overview: It seems I have talked subnetting to death on this blog, repetition, repetition, repetition.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 5)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 19:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/13/640-911-chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last week we covered chapter four which talked about the TCP/IP and the DoD models and what role they cover in networking as we learned that every application like FTP, DNS, DHCP depend on it. Like always post questions if you have any about the book CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I&#39;ll continue to cover topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 4)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 18:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off on Chapter 3 on CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Like before feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter three we discussed about Ethernet Technologies and in chapter four we will learn about the TCP/IP protocol which is fundamentally the protocol that makes the Internet work.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNP Security Refresh</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/03/ccnp-security-refresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 14:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/02/03/ccnp-security-refresh/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco recently published its 2014 Annual Security Report, and some interesting data was captured in 2013. One of the details was a talent gap in network security and because of this gap Cisco has a major revision in the CCNP Security certification starting in April. Its estimated that in short term or already present is shortage of more than a million security professionals worldwide! Like mentioned because of this Cisco is reworking the CCNP Security track.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 3)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/30/640-911-chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 18:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/30/640-911-chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picking up were we left on off on a series of blog posts that follow the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter two we discussed about internetworking and in chapter three we will learn about Ethernet technologies.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 2)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 19:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/23/640-911-chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am continuing the ongoing of series of blog posts that follow the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I figured that this type of post would help me and anybody else looking at studying for the exam. Feel free to post questions below as if on a study group, In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 1)</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/16/640-911-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 17:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2014/01/16/640-911-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I bought the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. I have decided it would be a good idea to go over the topics of each chapter of this book in series of blog posts. The idea of this is to work together if on a study group, go over the topics in each chapter of the book, talk about examples and to get an idea of what the exam would cover.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 1.0 Campaign</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/11/21/gns3-1.0-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 06:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/11/21/gns3-1.0-campaign/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s been almost 24 hours since GNS3 launched a campaign to bring in funds to support the open source network simulator and bring it up to version 1.0. A lot of new features are on the list, like switching, cloud processing, hassle free configuration, labs/training materials and 3rd party integrations. All of which are in the works for this new version added along with some pretty cool plug-ins. As of writing this post they are at $106,973 dollars which is 300 percent over funded!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA 2-0 What&#39;s New?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/09/30/ccna-2-0-whats-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/09/30/ccna-2-0-whats-new/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I brought this topic up in March of this year (See original post) but I wanted to re-post it to add some information because as of today this was your last day to pass the older CCNA exams. Cisco has a refreshed all the CCNA Routing and Switching exams. That includes the ICND1 (640-822), the ICND2 (640-816), and the all in wonder exam (640-816). You will notice some old references no longer mentioned on this refresh, so let&#39;s go over the differences and some of the changes Cisco has made to the associate-level certification track.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Go Professional with Cisco Certs?</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/09/14/why-go-professional-with-cisco-certs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 18:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/09/14/why-go-professional-with-cisco-certs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I have had the opportunity to take and thankfully pass Cisco certifications at the associate levels and there is one more associate exam, the CCNA Data Center which hopefully I will get later next year. While looking at the CCNA Data Center exam I also glanced over the professional arena that Cisco offers and if you’re like me I always like learning new things especially in technical field. Getting those “aha moments” once in a while makes it worth it, but beyond just over all knowledge of additional technologies why would you go on taking a professional Cisco cert?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed 640-554!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/06/29/passed-640-554/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/06/29/passed-640-554/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Short story, I am proud to say that I passed! I have studied off and on in the beginning of the year but I did set a date to take the exam which was June 28th .As that date was getting closer I buckled down and reviewed the materials again and focused in on some areas that I knew I was weak in.
So how was the 640-554 exam, what did I use to pass the exam and what exam am I focusing on next?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction into Cisco Configuration Professional</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/03/10/introduction-into-cisco-configuration-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2013/03/10/introduction-into-cisco-configuration-professional/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s walk through the basics with Cisco Configuration Professional as it is a helpful tool to use at the associate levels of the Cisco certification track and needed if you are looking at getting the CCNA Security certification. In this introduction we will introduce CCP and setup a community and then finally discover our devices within CCP. This is not the first GUI tool Cisco has produced to manage individual routers, an older tool called Cisco SDM also helped Network Administrators which supports the ISR Generation 1 routers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Data Center</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 02:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/11/21/ccna-data-center/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco has now introduced another associate level exam, the CCNA Data Center exam. Like the name suggests this exam focuses on the Data Center and if passed you can continue up the stack by also taking the CCNP Data Center exam which was also recently introduced as well. Still want more a little more, if you are up for the challenge you can also tackle the CCIE Data Center which is an exam that was introduced in March of 2012.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Security - 640-554</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 16:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network-security-lock Out with the old and in with new Cisco is updating its well-known certification CCNA Security. Candidates that are studying for the older exam (640-553) are suggested to take it on or before September 30th 2012. What has changed in the exam? For the most part Cisco SDM is no longer covered, as it has reached its &amp;quot;End of Life&amp;quot; and in fact Cisco Engineering stopped covering the product from developing and testing on February 26th 2012.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Learning Labs is Live!</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/13/cisco-learning-labs-is-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/13/cisco-learning-labs-is-live/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday was kind of exciting at least for me when I got an e-mail in the morning about Cisco Learning Labs. Studying for the CCNA, CCNP or CCIP is in itself changeling, but getting that hands-on experience is a another problem! When money is short that last thing you want to do is spend it on routers and switches, and most of them on eBay are used and the risk of failing devices makes it a scary choice.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I passed the ICND1 Exam</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/21/how-i-passed-the-icnd1-exam/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Well my first of the many Cisco certifications that I plan take in the future was a success! I was able to pass the ICND1 exam. This blog post is going to be a little different in that I want to share how I was able to pass this test and talk about my experience.
Well in January after finishing the Cisco Networking Academy in the Exploration series I wanted to go ahead and take shot at the ICND1 exam.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
