<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CDP on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/cdp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CDP on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/cdp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Discovery_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Discovery Protocol&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt;. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router&#34; title=&#34;Router&#34;&gt;router&lt;/a&gt; or switch is set up correctly  at least up to layer two in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt;. This also helps us discover &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; devices that are in are network and which &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interface_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Interface (computing)&#34;&gt;interfaces&lt;/a&gt; these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary  and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information&#34; title=&#34;Information&#34;&gt;information&lt;/a&gt; CDP gives out which helps you has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_administrator&#34; title=&#34;Network administrator&#34;&gt;network administrator&lt;/a&gt; build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet. So what is the purpose of CDP? CDP can gather device information from neighboring switches and routers without the need for a password. Like mentioned before this is great for troubleshooting a problem, discovering new devices that are not documented in your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_topology&#34; title=&#34;Network topology&#34;&gt;network topology&lt;/a&gt;, and verifying that each device is physically connected to the correct interfaces according to network documentation. CDP can discover the following details from neighboring devices that support CDP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Identifier: The hostname of the device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address List: Network and data-link addresses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local Interface: The interface on the switch or router issuing the command &lt;em&gt;Show CDP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port Identifier: Identifies the port used by the device to send CDP messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capabilities List: Information on what the device is like a router or a switch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platform: The model and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating_system&#34; title=&#34;Operating system&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/a&gt; running on the device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since CDP is enabled by default it does create a security risk, Cisco recommends that CDP be disabled on all interfaces that do not have need for it. You can disable CDP in two ways, by each interface with the sub-command &lt;em&gt;no cdp enable&lt;/em&gt; under the interface you wish to disable CDP. Or you can also disable CDP globally within the router or switch with the command &lt;em&gt;no cdp run&lt;/em&gt; under the configuration mode. That&#39;s just some general information about CDP and why CDP is useful. Although CDP could be a security risk it&#39;s still a helpful protocol to get some detailed information about your Cisco devices for inventory or to update your network topology. It can also be useful to just verify that the physical layer and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Link_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Data Link Layer&#34;&gt;data-link layer&lt;/a&gt; are working correctly for troubleshooting purposes. Like always I hope this information is informative and if you have an idea on the next topic that deals with wither ICND1 or ICND2 let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS Commands&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/&#34;&gt;Distance Vector Routing&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/ar/cisco-again-makes-ip-ngns-simpler-more-capable-less-costly/&#34;&gt;Cisco Again Makes IP NGNs Simpler, More Capable, Less Costly&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/&#34;&gt;Configure Cisco SDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
