<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spanning Tree Protocol on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/spanning-tree-protocol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spanning Tree Protocol on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 15:30:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/spanning-tree-protocol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oh...Spanning Tree</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2019/01/02/oh...spanning-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 15:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2019/01/02/oh...spanning-tree/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s the &amp;quot;S&amp;quot; word we don&#39;t like to hear, and often times it has degraded networks or even took them down entirely. (All Systems Down - an older but classic story) It&#39;s also one of those things that nobody really likes, we even had network companies, as well as IEEE try to replace it with something else. Remember the names like TRILL, and IEEE 802.1aq (SPB) or Cisco&#39;s FabicPath technologies? You had all of these different flavors that showed a lot progress, but they never really took off for one reason or another.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Store-and-Forward vs. Cut-Through Switching</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/05/store-and-forward-vs.-cut-through-switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/05/store-and-forward-vs.-cut-through-switching/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network-Cable-Color Switching in the network can happen in two ways, these layer-two devices send frames but they can forward them in different ways. These different modes have positive and negative effects which depend on the type of network environment that runs through them! Store-and-forward is just like the name suggests, the switch receives a frame on a port and stores the frame in it&#39;s memory buffer until the frame has been completely received.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the month of August I talked about the &amp;quot;beginnings&amp;quot; of layer two redundancy mainly looking at the basic foundations and fundamentals of having layer two redundancy. Let&#39;s continue are discussion about redundancy in the layer two environment. To review what STP does (Spanning Tree Protocol) it works at layer two of the OSI model. If more than one path is available in the network the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until the active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network-diagram In a perfect world we would never need redundancy on a network infrastructure, but as you know as well as I know we don&#39;t live in a perfect world. Hardware will eventually fail, bottlenecks will appear, and the speed of our network will become slower when we max the bandwidth on links. So having redundancy in routers, connections, and having a hierarchy network is one of best choices to make when improving the efficiently of the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
