<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network administrator on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/network-administrator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network administrator on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 04:58:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/network-administrator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Network Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/11/11/network-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 04:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/11/11/network-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Troubleshooting The thing that makes networks awesome is the fact that once you setup a network you&#39;re not done. That may sound like a drawback but it is excellent job security! Engineers or administrators must watch the performance of an organization&#39;s network to make sure that productivity is not affected. Network outages can have a huge effect on an organization, lost revenue and the cost of unproductive employees can severely damage the organization, Earlier this year I also talked about the troubleshooting process which goes hand in hand with network troubleshooting.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Network Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/17/common-network-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 16:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/17/common-network-attacks/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network attacks have always been around but they are getting more advanced every day. These attacks are also easy to set up and use. In the past these types of attacks would have to be pulled off by someone who really knew about computers and to know what they are doing. That&#39;s a true hacker, now there are programs that do the same damage and sometimes more with a couple clicks of a mouse, so now anybody can bring down a network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IDS vs. IPS</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 15:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are tons of network attacks out there. Using a firewall helps but does look for signature based attacks. Access Control Lists are like firewalls and only look at the protocols like HTTP, FTP POP, etc. Cisco has developed some tools that will help network administrators combat the issue; IDS, (Intrusion Detection System) and IPS. (Intrusion Prevention System) Let&#39;s go into IDS first, Cisco IDS is a physical device and is like an alarm system it will alert you when an attack happens but that&#39;s it, the system won&#39;t block the connection.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
