<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EtherChannel on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/etherchannel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EtherChannel on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 13:15:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/etherchannel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Layer Three EtherChannel</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/05/07/configuring-layer-three-etherchannel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 13:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/05/07/configuring-layer-three-etherchannel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you want more speed all you need is EtherChannel, EtherChannel can be configured as a layer three logical interface instead of just sitting at layer two. This is very helpful if we are running layer three down to the access layer switches, instead of at the distribution layer. You also could see this in a collapsed core design, we also don’t have to worry too much about STP when we configure EtherChannel’s.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring EtherChannel (PAgb)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 15:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/10/12/configuring-etherchannel-pagb/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bundling physical links into one logical link is a common practice to up the bandwidth between switches, you may have this also configured on a server to bundle connections as well. In this tutorial I have two 2960 switches both of them trunking all VLANs on two gigabit ports. So in the end game is get 2gbps instead of 1gbps between switches while using Cisco’s proprietary protocol PAgb. It is important to remember that both of these protocols (PAgb and LACP) are link aggregation protocols only, their job is to make sure that EtherChannel is setup correctly by negotiating.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Understanding of EtherChannel</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/04/basic-understanding-of-etherchannel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/04/basic-understanding-of-etherchannel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network cables Let&#39;s start the New Year with understanding EtherChannel which is having more than one link connected to a server, switch, or router and treating it like one logical link. This is a fault-tolerant technique that is becoming a common setup in highly available, core devices. Cisco has come up with their own proprietary version call EtherChannel. The open standard that IEEE approved is 802.3ad which works with other venders and is often called LAG for short.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
