<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 18:05:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Graylog with AWS Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/06/21/graylog-with-aws-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 18:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2019/06/21/graylog-with-aws-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Graylog has been through some changes last time I talked about them, hitting version 3.0 in February is awesome and one of things that make Graylog run well is Elasticsearch backend. Although Elasticsearch is not too hard to setup it usually runs better on bare metal, so there is cost of that as well as maintenance of the cluster is important, updates and upgrades. Depending your team experience you may not have time to learn it or run it the way it should be.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barracuda Load Balancer- Powershell</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/12/14/barracuda-load-balancer-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 15:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2018/12/14/barracuda-load-balancer-powershell/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Working on my Powershell skills, I was playing around with a Barracuda Load Balancer and noticed it supported some APIs which is kind of cool. At first I was playing around with it in postman and got to login and put some servers in maintenance mode, but then thought it would be really neat if I could get this working in Powershell, that way us humans can just run a script and even thinking in the &amp;quot;future&amp;quot; maybe have some automated process (a.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TFTP &amp; FTP Server on Centos 7</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/09/16/tftp-ftp-server-on-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/09/16/tftp-ftp-server-on-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you ever needed a TFTP or an anonymous FTP server to transfer files, logs, or crash debugs to and from your network devices it can be a little tricky if you don&#39;t have anything setup. There are some free quick programs out there if you are in a pinch for one-time transfers but if you ever wanted to have something in infrastructure that is ready to go for this kind of stuff just follow this tutorial below.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Graylog on Centos 7</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/01/01/installing-graylog-on-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2016/01/01/installing-graylog-on-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s start out 2016 with setting up a logging system called Graylog. If you have not used Graylog before then I encourage you to check it out. This is an open source log management system and is pretty flexible as it can capture, index and analyze almost anything. Once up and running this system can be scaled out for an enterprise wide log management system. High availability, clustered, and replicated is what Graylog thrives on.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco VIRL – Update</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/11/18/cisco-virl-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 13:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/11/18/cisco-virl-update/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cisco released VIRL almost a year ago and it’s not at the 1.0 version yet but it’s getting close as they have done some good work towards the product since it first lunched. Cisco VIRL is like GNS3 which is simulation platform that runs Cisco’s current operating systems so instead of buying used Cisco hardware you can run this program on your computer. This software is geared towards proof-of-concept designs, for personal and training on Cisco Certifications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Rancid</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/02/27/configuring-rancid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/02/27/configuring-rancid/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In my last post I talked about Installing Rancid on Centos 7 so be sure to check that out. In this post we now want to actually use Rancid so I’ll walk through on how to setup Rancid to login into network equipment and get configurations.
To recap: Rancid is a great tool to help monitor a device configuration for any changes. It also keeps track of them by using CVS (Concurrent Version System) for backups, so you can go back and compare versions or revert to a previous configuration.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up GNS3 1.1 on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/10/28/setting-up-gns3-1.1-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 12:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/10/28/setting-up-gns3-1.1-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s only been a week since GNS3 1.0 was released and it&#39;s already been updated to 1.1 so in this post I have Ubuntu 14.04 LTS with the latest updates and its time to set up GNS3. GNS3 is an open source tool that helps network professionals run a virtual network right on their computer, GNS3 is not a simulation program but rather an emulation program. So if you wanted to test a configuration change but did not want to run it on production you can run it in GNS3 instead.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some QoS Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/08/05/some-qos-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 02:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/08/05/some-qos-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When I started taking classes from the Cisco CCNA Discover books years ago, I remember for the first part of the book it talked about QoS and the theory behind it. To me QoS was a very interesting but after a chapter or two we never mentioned it again or really knew how to configure it. It seemed like it disappeared but it always something being tested on so we know it was there, somewhere… QoS can be a little boring and it does get a reputation of being difficult to understand, like where and how do I implement QoS?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install RSYSLOG &amp; LogAnalyzer on CentOS 6-5</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/06/11/install-rsyslog-loganalyzer-on-centos-6-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/06/11/install-rsyslog-loganalyzer-on-centos-6-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I am looking at rsyslog which is fast syslog system and Loganalyzer as an upfront web GUI for those logs. The Loganalyzer application offers searching of various syslogs, all of which is open source and available to download. In this guide I will go through the steps to get these two applications to work together and in the end of this tutorial we should have a working syslog system ready to take logs!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 Alpha – Install and Setup</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/05/10/gns3-alpha-install-and-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 01:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/05/10/gns3-alpha-install-and-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So Alpha 3 came out last week with a bunch updates and I decided to give it run this week. I&#39;m not doing anything that difficult with the program so maybe I&#39;m not breaking it in all the way but I also was looking at some installation notes for Ubuntu and other Linux flavors, I figured I’ll try to install it on a Windows machine and not Linux (call me lazy) feel free to follow this guide.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 01:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Cisco Lab When it comes to learning and getting started with Cisco there are some tools that will help out a lot like Packet Tracer, GNS3 and other emulators. These are great tools for that &amp;quot;simulation&amp;quot; of hands on learning, but you can&#39;t always stay in that area. I find it best to get hands on with &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; Cisco Gear and so with this post I&#39;ll go through my current setup of what I have and ask that question when it is a good time to get a lab?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Nexus 1000v?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/03/17/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 17:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/03/17/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network_cloud I have worked with the Nexus 1000v product and wanted to share my thoughts on it. I want to explain in this blog what this product is and what it does. The Nexus 1000v can be virtual or a hardware appliance and is considered to be a virtual switch that runs in VMware. The major benefit to this product is the visibly you get when running in a virtual environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trunking Administrative Modes</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/02/11/trunking-administrative-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 22:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/02/11/trunking-administrative-modes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            cisco-switch-blade When looking at the CCNA it is good idea to get a hold of trunking between switches along with that there are a couple of administrative modes that each physical interface on Cisco switch can be when you are trunking between them. Remember that when we are trunking it usually carries all VLANs (This can be changed) but there are different ways to make trunking between links happen. When you are in an interface on a Cisco switch you can change the operational mode of that interface by issuing the switchport mode command.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color Code Your Routers</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/11/30/color-code-your-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 17:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/11/30/color-code-your-routers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I came across an interesting idea, what if you could color code your devices in command line? So such as if you were operating routers at a core level you could color code the CLI to the color red, and the branch routers green and etc. I wasn&#39;t sure if this would possible but doing some searching through the internet I found a guy Ivan Pepelnjak who wrote how to do this a couple years ago and wrote a couple books as well, check out his blog/website at http://www.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/11/11/network-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 04:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/11/11/network-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Troubleshooting The thing that makes networks awesome is the fact that once you setup a network you&#39;re not done. That may sound like a drawback but it is excellent job security! Engineers or administrators must watch the performance of an organization&#39;s network to make sure that productivity is not affected. Network outages can have a huge effect on an organization, lost revenue and the cost of unproductive employees can severely damage the organization, Earlier this year I also talked about the troubleshooting process which goes hand in hand with network troubleshooting.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure SSH on Dell Power-Connect</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/26/how-to-configure-ssh-on-dell-power-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 15:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/10/26/how-to-configure-ssh-on-dell-power-connect/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            keys Although not dealing with Cisco directly Dell switches are around in network closets and with my limited experience with them I thought this would be a perfect blog post to show the differences between Dell and Cisco. I like to think of Dell CLI like a dumb downed version of the Cisco CLI so I had some time to play around with a Dell 6248P switch and wanted to figure out how to get SSH working in the thing.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the month of August I talked about the &amp;quot;beginnings&amp;quot; of layer two redundancy mainly looking at the basic foundations and fundamentals of having layer two redundancy. Let&#39;s continue are discussion about redundancy in the layer two environment. To review what STP does (Spanning Tree Protocol) it works at layer two of the OSI model. If more than one path is available in the network the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until the active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link-State Protocols</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/31/link-state-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/31/link-state-protocols/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network-Cables Weeks ago and maybe months :), I talked about distance vector protocols and with that you probably got the feeling that when using a distance vector protocol it does not give a full network graphical representation of the entire network. Only the directly connected routes can&#39;t remember? Check out this post Distance Vector Routing. Link state protocols are faster to converge network changes compared to distance vector however when compared to distance vector setup they can be harder to set up, maintain, and troubleshoot when problems arise.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Codes of ICMP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post I wanted to talk about the widely used Ping command. Which is one of the best methods (I think) to begin network troubleshooting. When part of the network goes down it is sometimes hard to figure out why? When you issue the ping command or the extended ping command in a Cisco router several ICMP codes can come up on the router. Let&#39;s discuss them! The first status code &amp;quot;!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the Cisco Discovery Protocol. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between router or switch is set up correctly at least up to layer two in the OSI model. This also helps us discover Cisco devices that are in are network and which interfaces these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed information CDP gives out which helps you has a network administrator build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Vector Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 16:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Couple weeks ago I talked about routing protocols and in the post I mentioned two routing protocol features distance vector and link state. Although these protocols fundamentally do the same thing by getting information on remote networks they get this information in a different way. For today let&#39;s introduce distance vector routing. With a distance vector routing protocol, a router learns about a route to a different network (that&#39;s the purpose of a routing protocol) the router only knows the &amp;quot;distance&amp;quot; to get there this is usually called the metric.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World IPv6 Day!!</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/08/world-ipv6-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 18:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/08/world-ipv6-day/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            IPv6 So what is IPv6 day? Today major companies like Google, Facebook, Yahoo and ISPs (Internet Service Providers) test their IPv6 deployments. Why is this important? Well if you follow IPv4 news you might already know that IPv4 addresses have been exhausted and the need to move to different address space is critical, if new web services are to be deployed. The question is can we run both? Although running two different IP addressing protocols is likely, by &amp;quot;stacking&amp;quot; them that is one reason the Internet Society wanted major sites and ISPs to test out the IPv6 address space.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS Commands</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 17:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the master list of some of the many Cisco IOS Commands that go with the CCNA track. This list also talks about what each command does in brief detail. You may also find that some commands may or may not be used for a CCNA level but offer some important information. If you don&#39;t know what a command does or understand it, I would look at Cisco documentation. Since this is a pretty big list of commands you can see the links to move to the different sections within this page.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VTP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some people hate it, some people love it. It&#39;s the Cisco proprietary VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) which in short means that Cisco switches can exchange VLAN configuration, instead of manually configuring each switch with the same VLANs. I also suggest if you don&#39;t know what a VLAN is check out the post Creating VLANs Let&#39;s get right into understanding VTP. The thing that makes VTP shine is what it does, although simple to understand it saves time by automatically distributing VLAN information.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Static Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/02/configure-static-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Plugging Cisco routers together and hoping they work out of the box is not something you should hope for. A router can learn about networks in two ways, manually from configured static routers which we will talk about today and dynamic routing protocols which will talk about on Wednesday. Let&#39;s get started! Static routes are not that uncommon they at first need some attention to get set up but after it is working nothing needs to change.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding AAA</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/29/understanding-aaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/29/understanding-aaa/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            User The wonderful AAA which in the Cisco world means, Authentication, Authorization, and Accounting but what does that really mean? In today&#39;s post that&#39;s what we are going to be talking about. What is AAA and what are the benefits of using it along with what is it? The first &amp;quot;A&amp;quot; of AAA is Authentication which provides the method of identifying users, including login and password dialog, challenge and response, messaging support, and, depending on the security protocol you select, encryption.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure a Site-to-Site VPN via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 18:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure a site-to-site VPN on a router using the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. (See the post Configuring SDM) Let&#39;s start configuring a site-to-site VPN with SDM! This tutorial is assuming that the configurations to set up Cisco SDM have already been completed.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 17:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Awhile back I talked about the differences between IPS and IDS. (See the post Cisco IDS vs. IPS ) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure an IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) on a router using the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. ( See the post Configure Cisco SDM) Let&#39;s start configuring an IPS with SDM!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Zone Based Firewalls via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 15:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last month I talked about the fundamentals for understanding zone based firewalls (See the post Understanding Zone Based Firewalls). So for today&#39;s post I want to go ahead and talk about configuring the zone based firewalls but with the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and reduce ownership costs. (See the post Configure Cisco SDM) Instead of talking about what is zone based firewalls lets jump into the configuration of them.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Cisco SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/18/configure-cisco-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we will be going over the steps that are required to set up the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger) The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. SDM is fairly easy to set up but you still need at least some experience in the router command-line to get SDM working. This tutorial is already assuming that the Cisco SDM program has been installed on the PC.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Process</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 18:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/15/troubleshooting-process/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Troubleshooting Today&#39;s post is going to be talking about troubleshooting and where to start the troubleshooting process. Yes there is an actual process that every technician should be aware of. You can also use this troubleshooting process at home, you may not know how to fix it but at least you know where the issue is and find someone who can. Before we begin if you haven&#39;t seen yet, let me introduce to you the troubleshooting process:
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Port Security</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/31/configuring-port-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/31/configuring-port-security/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Secure Today this tutorial is going to be talking about how to configure port security on a Cisco Catalyst switch. Port security is one of the first things you can do to keep your network secure from unauthorized access. Port security can restrict devices so only devices you allow are granted access to network resources. If and when an unauthorized device is connected to a port you can decide what you want the switch to do.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Zone Based Firewalls</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/18/understanding-zone-based-firewalls/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier we talked about using CBAC (See the post Understanding CBAC) the &amp;quot;classic firewall&amp;quot; and we mention some information about zone based firewalls but not nearly enough. So today we will be talking about zone based firewalls. Why are they different? We also will learn the basics about what is zone based and what are the advantages compared to CBAC. You can think of zone based has making interfaces in a quarantine zone, each interface by default if set up in a zone is denied access to any other interface.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cracking WEP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/14/cracking-wep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2011 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/14/cracking-wep/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            BackTrack is Linux network security audit tool for security professionals. This tool is used for testing and penetrating networks. That being said** This tutorial is for educational use only. This is meant only to teach that WEP is an insecure option, and is recommend to use a harder encryption. Using this tutorial on a network that you do not have permission to access or is not yours, could be illegal! ** This was tested on BackTrack version 4 and the steps outlined in this tutorial were successful.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telecommuting Services</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/11/telecommuting-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 17:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/11/telecommuting-services/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is going to talk about the major technologies that make Teleworking or also called telecommuting possible. This is when an employee performs his or her job away from the office, usually from their home office. By doing this it allows personal convenience, less travel to and from the workplace. At an Organization level it provides continuity of operations, Secure, reliable and manageable access to information, cost-effective integration of data, voice, video and applications.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IDS vs. IPS</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 15:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are tons of network attacks out there. Using a firewall helps but does look for signature based attacks. Access Control Lists are like firewalls and only look at the protocols like HTTP, FTP POP, etc. Cisco has developed some tools that will help network administrators combat the issue; IDS, (Intrusion Detection System) and IPS. (Intrusion Prevention System) Let&#39;s go into IDS first, Cisco IDS is a physical device and is like an alarm system it will alert you when an attack happens but that&#39;s it, the system won&#39;t block the connection.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install BackTrack</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 18:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/01/install-backtrack/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a full install of BackTrack 4 this can be in a virtual machine, dual-boot, or the main OS. So you burned the image that you downloaded from http://www.backtrack-linux.org/ and are ready to go! If not I would recommend you do that first. BackTrack is a Linux penetration testing for network security. This is a free tool that IT administrators can use to audit their network. First put the disk into the tray and restart your computer.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding CBAC</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although using hardware firewalls are an excellent step forward when securing your network. They can cost money and are not cheap to set up and configure. Using CBAC is built-into the Cisco IOS router and helps filter those unwanted protocols that are in your network. When setting up routers as firewalls you have some choices like using CBAC the &amp;quot;Classic&amp;quot; firewall, or zone based policy (ZBF). Today we will talk about CBAC and how to understand the core components of what make CBAC possible.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TACACS Plus and RADIUS</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/10/tacacs-plus-and-radius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 15:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/10/tacacs-plus-and-radius/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TACACS+ and RADIUS are both used to control access to network resources, but both of these protocols are different in how they operate depending how you want to secure your network. These protocols need to have (AAA) authentication, authorization, and accounting setup on the routers before you can set up these access server protocols. First let&#39;s get some information on why we would need this type of access server protocol setup.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
