<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OSI model on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/osi-model/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OSI model on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 03:09:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/osi-model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HDLC vs. PPP</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/hdlc-vs.-ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 03:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2012/02/hdlc-vs.-ppp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-Level_Data_Link_Control&#34; title=&#34;High-Level Data Link Control&#34;&gt;HDLC&lt;/a&gt; and PPP are considered to be in layer 2 of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt;. There are some differences between which will be describe in this post, If you would like to learn more about at least the basic configuration of PPP including PAP and CHAP check out the post I wrote about year ago. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/18/basic-ppp-configuration/&#34; title=&#34;Basic PPP Configuration&#34;&gt;Basic PPP Configuration&lt;/a&gt;) HDLC was first developed by the ISO Cisco tweaked the protocol sometimes called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_HDLC&#34; title=&#34;Cisco HDLC&#34;&gt;cHDLC&lt;/a&gt; and because of this it only works with Cisco equipment. PPP is defined by RFC 1968 which is an open standard and is able to work on multi-vender equipment. The default setting of a Cisco serial interfaces is to use HDLC encapsulation, You generally don&#39;t have to change this unless you are working with multivendor environments. Then you are going to have to change that encapsulation type to PPP or if you want some of the features that PPP offers. PPP offers many features that HDLC does not including the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Password_authentication_protocol&#34; title=&#34;Password authentication protocol&#34;&gt;Password Authentication Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (PAP) and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Challenge-Handshake_Authentication_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Challenge-Handshake Authentication Protocol&#34;&gt;Challenge-Handshake Authentication Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (CHAP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compression capabilities with Stacker or Predictor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PPP Multilink, the ability to bundle physical channels into a single logical channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Error_detection_and_correction&#34; title=&#34;Error detection and correction&#34;&gt;Error detection&lt;/a&gt; and error recovery features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encapsulation for multiple routed protocols, including IP, Novell &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internetwork_Packet_Exchange&#34; title=&#34;Internetwork Packet Exchange&#34;&gt;IPX&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AppleTalk&#34; title=&#34;AppleTalk&#34;&gt;AppleTalk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;also-note-that-passwords-are-case-sensitive-when-using-pap-and-chap-multilink-ppphttpenwikipediaorgwikipoint-to-point_protocol-point-to-point-protocol-mppp-basically-allows-us-to-bundle-multiple-physical-wan-links-into-one-logical-link-there-are-some-different-reasons-for-doing-this-and-they-generally-depend-on-the-network-topology-but-the-common-reason-is-using-it-over-isdnhttpenwikipediaorgwikiintegrated_services_digital_network-integrated-services-digital-network-links-to-allow-the-data-packets-to-be-broken-up-into-fragments-in-turn-this-fragmentation-allows-for-greater-load-balancing-where-the-physical-links-will-carry-a-similar-load-than-one-link-carry-most-of-the-load-this-is-like-etherchannelhttpenwikipediaorgwikietherchannel-etherchannel-ppp-also-allows-us-to-enable-one-of-two-compression-techniques-stacker-or-predictor-both-are-enabled-with-the-interface-level-command-_compress_-the-differences-between-the-two-are-beyond-the-ccna-but-a-simple-web-search-would-do-if-you-are-itching-for-an-answer-like-always-i-hope-this-short-and-sweet-post-is-helpful-and-if-you-have-questions-feel-free-to-post-them-also-give-me-some-other-ideas-that-deal-with-either-icnd1-or-icnd2-check-back-later-as-i-want-to-bring-up-a-more-in-depth-look-about-ppp&#34;&gt;Also note that Passwords are case sensitive when using PAP and CHAP. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Point-to-Point_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Point-to-Point Protocol&#34;&gt;Multilink PPP&lt;/a&gt; (MPPP) basically allows us to bundle multiple physical WAN links into one logical link. There are some different reasons for doing this and they generally depend on the network topology, but the common reason is using it over &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_Services_Digital_Network&#34; title=&#34;Integrated Services Digital Network&#34;&gt;ISDN&lt;/a&gt; links to allow the data packets to be broken up into fragments. In turn this fragmentation allows for greater load balancing, where the physical links will carry a similar load than one link carry most of the load. (This is like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EtherChannel&#34; title=&#34;EtherChannel&#34;&gt;EtherChannel&lt;/a&gt; ). PPP also allows us to enable one of two compression techniques, Stacker or Predictor. Both are enabled with the interface-level command &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;compress&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; The differences between the two are beyond the CCNA but a simple web search would do if you are itching for an answer. Like always I hope this short and sweet post is helpful and if you have questions feel free to post them, also give me some other ideas that deal with either ICND1 or ICND2. Check back later as I want to bring up a more in depth look about PPP.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/14/icnd2-passed/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;ICND2 – Passed! | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-05-14 20:33:01&#34;&gt;May 1, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] HDLC vs. PPP (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In the month of August I talked about the &amp;quot;beginnings&amp;quot; of layer two &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Redundancy_%28engineering%29&#34; title=&#34;Redundancy (engineering)&#34;&gt;redundancy&lt;/a&gt; mainly looking at the basic foundations and fundamentals of having layer two redundancy. Let&#39;s continue are discussion about redundancy in the layer two environment. To review what STP does (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanning_Tree_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Spanning Tree Protocol&#34;&gt;Spanning Tree Protocol&lt;/a&gt;) it works at layer two of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt;. If more than one path is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Network Layer&#34;&gt;network&lt;/a&gt; the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until the active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.) So although there are multiple links connected physically to offer redundancy, logically the switches in the network only see one path that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethernet_frame&#34; title=&#34;Ethernet frame&#34;&gt;Ethernet frame&lt;/a&gt; can travel. Remember without STP networks would be on the fritz when we introduce redundancy in the environment. STP or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IEEE_802.1D&#34; title=&#34;IEEE 802.1D&#34;&gt;IEEE 802.1D&lt;/a&gt; is an open standard so it is not just on Cisco equipment but others as well which helps in a multivendor situation. So how does looping occur without the use STP? Looking at the picture below we can see the broadcasts frames are flooding the network which is by design but the thing that changes is these broadcasts will continue to flood the network because there is on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_to_live&#34; title=&#34;Time to live&#34;&gt;TTL&lt;/a&gt; (Time-To-Live) on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Link_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Data Link Layer&#34;&gt;data link layer&lt;/a&gt; of the OSI model. As more packets are passed and created the network will become slower and slower and eventually devices on the network will become unavailable this called a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcast_radiation&#34; title=&#34;Broadcast radiation&#34;&gt;broadcast storm&lt;/a&gt;. [caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1534&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;584&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;STP Loop Example (Broadcast Storm)&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/stpfl.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/stpfl.png&#34; alt=&#34;An example of an STP loop&#34; title=&#34;STP Loop&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] There are also more problems when not using STP besides broadcast storms like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MAC_address&#34; title=&#34;MAC address&#34;&gt;MAC address&lt;/a&gt; table becoming unstable in each switch. This causes the MAC table to be unreliable because of the looping frames in the network. These frames are usually sent to the wrong locations in the network. Multiple frames can also be a problem because of looping frames multiple frames appear on the network and if they are delivered to the intended host it can confuse the host and more likly drop the frames. So looking at the same picture but with STP enabled we can see that broadcast frame will travel the network without looping. On S1 one of the ports is in a blocking state and blocks all traffic coming into that port and traffic coming out of that port. [caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1539&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;584&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;STP Enabled&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/stp-enable/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/stp-enable.png&#34; alt=&#34;STP Enabled&#34; title=&#34;STP Enable&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] The magic about STP is when the link between S2 and S3 becomes disconnected it will bring the link between S2 and S1 online and continue to send packets! When the link becomes available again it switch back to blocking on S1. So let&#39;s stop there for now and check back next week to see the last chapter of STP, how does it calculate which switch goes to blocking? What other advantages does STP offer? That&#39;s all next week, I hope this information is helpful and if you have an idea of the next topic that deals with either ICND1 or ICND2 let me hear it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/&#34;&gt;The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.co.uk/2011/08/03/network_resiliency/&#34;&gt;Belt and braces stop the network falling down&lt;/a&gt; (go.theregister.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.avaya.com/blogs/archives/2011/08/resiliency-and-redundancy---not-the-same.html&#34;&gt;Resiliency and Redundancy - NOT the same&lt;/a&gt; (avaya.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techbookshelf.com/2011/08/31/cisco-nexus-vpc-configuration-and-spanning-tree-elimination/&#34;&gt;Cisco Nexus vPC Configuration and Spanning-Tree Elimination&lt;/a&gt; (techbookshelf.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-07 18:51:46&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve do you have any questions? Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Steve]( &#34;svu@uppertraining.com&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-07 12:27:32&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome Site. Ryan can you please contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Welcome CCT (Cisco Certified Technician Certification) | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/21/welcome-cct-cisco-certified-technician/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-21 20:44:38&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[The “Ending” of Layer Two Redundancy | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/14/the-%e2%80%9cending%e2%80%9d-of-layer-two-redundancy/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-14 11:17:26&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] Post navigation ← Previous [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Store-and-Forward vs. Cut-Through Switching | Cisco Skills](http://ciscoskills.net/2011/10/05/store-and-forward-vs-cut-through-switching/ &#34;&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-10-05 10:16:16&#34;&gt;Oct 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/08/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/network-diagram.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/network-diagram.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;network-diagram&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In a perfect world we would never need redundancy on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_Layer&#34; title=&#34;Network Layer&#34;&gt;network&lt;/a&gt; infrastructure, but as you know as well as I know we don&#39;t live in a perfect world. Hardware will eventually fail, bottlenecks will appear, and the speed of our network will become slower when we max the bandwidth on links. So having redundancy in routers, connections, and having a hierarchy network is one of best choices to make when improving the efficiently of the network. But in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&#34; title=&#34;OSI model&#34;&gt;OSI model&lt;/a&gt; there is one layer that can&#39;t have redundancy at least logically and that is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstraction_layer&#34; title=&#34;Abstraction layer&#34;&gt;Layer&lt;/a&gt; two of the OSI model. If you follow this blog way back when I talked about the OSI model, layer two belongs to the switches and by design the ethernet frame does not support a TTL (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_to_live&#34; title=&#34;Time to live&#34;&gt;Time-To-Live&lt;/a&gt;) like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Internet Protocol&#34;&gt;IP packet&lt;/a&gt;. So bring forth STP, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanning_Tree_Protocol&#34; title=&#34;Spanning Tree Protocol&#34;&gt;Spanning Tree Protocol&lt;/a&gt; which works at layer two of the OSI model. If more than one path is available in the network the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.) So although there are multiple links connected physically to offer redundancy, logically the switches in the network only see one path that ethernet frame can travel. &lt;strong&gt;Your Thought:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait...I have plugged into multiple Cisco switches before to create a redundant path and I did not notice anything wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s because by default STP is enabled, to the average person they can plug away and create redundant paths with switches and cause no harm to the network. But if STP has been disabled on those switches or switches that don&#39;t support STP (dumb switches), a Layer 2 loop can occur. A Layer 2 loop is a nightmare if this happens in a production network and can happen in seconds. Loops result in high &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_processing_unit&#34; title=&#34;Central processing unit&#34;&gt;CPU&lt;/a&gt; load on all switches caught in the loop. Because the same frames are constantly being forwarded back and forth between all switches in the loop, the CPU of the switch ends up having to process a lot of data. This slows down performance on the switch when legitimate traffic arrives.  A host caught in a network loop is not accessible to other hosts on the network. Because the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MAC_address&#34; title=&#34;MAC address&#34;&gt;MAC address&lt;/a&gt; table is constantly changing with the updates from the broadcast frames, the switch does not know which port to send the unicast frames out to reach the destination. The unicast frames end up looping around the network as well. As more and more frames end up looping on the network, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcast_radiation&#34; title=&#34;Broadcast radiation&#34;&gt;broadcast storm&lt;/a&gt; occurs. What makes this even more fun is if you try connecting to the switches to solve this problem, good luck :). Most of the time you have to physically turn off the switches to kill the broadcast storm and if it happened once expect it to happen again. To make things worse if any end-devices are connected to the switch ports that are experiencing a broadcast storm they too have a hard time keeping up with the mountain of broadcast frames being sent and sometimes malfunction. Usually you would have to disconnect the switch from the redundant links and apply STP to it and then re-connect the redundant links in order for your network to be broadcast storm free. Although I&#39;m just getting started I think by just introducing this topic will help you better understand it later, I will get into more of this STP magic and how this really helps us design a hierarchy network. Like always I hope this information was informative and if you can&#39;t wait a simple search about STP will help. You can also go right to the source for more STP information at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_Systems&#34; title=&#34;Cisco Systems&#34;&gt;Cisco&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; Support and Documentation. Have an idea of the next topic either ICND1 or ICND2 let me know about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/&#34;&gt;Cisco Discovery Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cisco.com/smallbusiness/get-data-to-its-destination-faster/&#34;&gt;Get Data to Its Destination Faster&lt;/a&gt; (blogs.cisco.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/01/17/the-osi-layer/&#34; title=&#34;The OSI Layer&#34;&gt;The OSI Layer&lt;/a&gt;  (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.co.uk/2011/06/16/network_tuning/&#34;&gt;When tuning the server, don&#39;t forget the network&lt;/a&gt; (go.theregister.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy | Cisco Skills&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-09-07 12:08:56&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...] The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy (ciscoskills.net) [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
