<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://ciscoskills.net/tags/institute-of-electrical-and-electronics-engineers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:00:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ciscoskills.net/tags/institute-of-electrical-and-electronics-engineers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Middle of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/09/07/the-middle-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the month of August I talked about the &amp;quot;beginnings&amp;quot; of layer two redundancy mainly looking at the basic foundations and fundamentals of having layer two redundancy. Let&#39;s continue are discussion about redundancy in the layer two environment. To review what STP does (Spanning Tree Protocol) it works at layer two of the OSI model. If more than one path is available in the network the STP algorithm basically shutdowns the redundant links until the active link is unavailable (shutdown, disabled, etc.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Super WiFi</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/29/welcome-super-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 15:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/07/29/welcome-super-wifi/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            WiFi_Logo Wow July is almost over and I only posted one topic! Before August comes up I wanted to post at least one more topic which deals with the wireless side of the networking world. Ever heard of Super WiFi? The IEEE has published this standard recently its official number is 802.22. What does Super WiFi bring to the table compared to other WiFi Standards? Well according to IEEE these speeds can bring up to 22Mbps to devices as far has 62 miles!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11b</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/07/802.11b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 17:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/04/07/802.11b/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off the discussion, todays post will be talking about 802.11b wireless standard that was developed by IEEE. Yesterday&#39;s post we talked about the 802.11a standard. (See the post 802.11a) We also we talked about the 802.11 – Legacy standard (See the post 802.11 – Legacy) and in the beginning of the week I went over some Basic Wireless Concepts (See the post Basic Wireless Concepts) So now that we are up to speed lets learn about the 802.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11ac Standard</title>
      <link>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/21/802.11ac-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 18:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ciscoskills.net/2011/02/21/802.11ac-standard/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some things are making news in the wireless world, the IEEE wants another wireless standard in the mix called the 802.11ac, now the fastest standard they have is the 802.11n(speeds up to 300 Mbps), which was recently published in October of 2009. What is so great about the 802.11ac development? Well one thing is the speed, it is estimated that it will be able to carry up to 1 gigabit per second!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
