<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Datagram Protocol on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/user-datagram-protocol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in User Datagram Protocol on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 16:15:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/user-datagram-protocol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding UDP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 16:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/28/understanding-udp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Forever ago I talked about TCP (Understanding TCP) and I said that in that post that UDP would be another day, well this is the day where we get to understand UDP, which stands for User Datagram Protocol. UDP is the total opposite of the TCP communication. UDP in short sends information or data without notifying the receiver that its sending data. UDP is considered a connectionless protocol, and does not guarantee the reliability or order the packets like TCP does.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Network Attacks</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/17/common-network-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 16:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/17/common-network-attacks/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network attacks have always been around but they are getting more advanced every day. These attacks are also easy to set up and use. In the past these types of attacks would have to be pulled off by someone who really knew about computers and to know what they are doing. That&#39;s a true hacker, now there are programs that do the same damage and sometimes more with a couple clicks of a mouse, so now anybody can bring down a network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding CBAC</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/02/22/understanding-cbac/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although using hardware firewalls are an excellent step forward when securing your network. They can cost money and are not cheap to set up and configure. Using CBAC is built-into the Cisco IOS router and helps filter those unwanted protocols that are in your network. When setting up routers as firewalls you have some choices like using CBAC the &amp;quot;Classic&amp;quot; firewall, or zone based policy (ZBF). Today we will talk about CBAC and how to understand the core components of what make CBAC possible.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
