<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scripting on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/scripting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scripting on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 12:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/scripting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PRTG Daily Email Powershell Script</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/06/03/prtg-daily-email-powershell-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2015/06/03/prtg-daily-email-powershell-script/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So I don&#39;t write much powershell but recently I needed a way to send daily emails out of PRTG. Thanks Paessler which has kept it simple with their PRTG monitoring system as the hardest part of this script was getting the data in HTML, remember I don&#39;t write much powershell. ;) If you have not used PRTG before check it out if you need some alerting in your environment. Personally this is one of my favorite systems for just monitoring because a lot of other monitoring systems include everything but the kitchen sink and reality we just need to know what&#39;s up and what&#39;s down.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy Running-Config From PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/08/16/copy-running-config-from-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 03:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/08/16/copy-running-config-from-powershell/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I will be up front on this I really never had that much experience with power-shell scripts but I wanted a quick way to connect to routers and switches and issue the show run command and have that script output everything into one file. So some searching around I decided to drive into power-shell to see if I could get something to work. One of my first problems was to find a way to have power-shell SSH into my devices I found out about SharpSSH which look interesting but I also found SSH.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
