<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TeraTerm on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/teraterm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TeraTerm on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:23:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/tags/teraterm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Password Recovery – Cisco IOS Routers</title>
      <link>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2012/07/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://archive.ciscoskills.net.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2012/07/password-recovery-cisco-ios-routers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/lock.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://systemstechblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/lock.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Secure&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; In this post I want to cover how to recover passwords on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cisco_IOS&#34; title=&#34;Cisco IOS&#34;&gt;Cisco IOS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router_%28computing%29&#34; title=&#34;Router (computing)&#34;&gt;Router&lt;/a&gt;. This is helpful in lab environments as well as production environments. Although this method can be used the correct &amp;quot;legal&amp;quot; way you can also use this method to break into these devices &amp;quot;illegally&amp;quot; if you have physical console access to the device. However to get into it physical power must be turned off first causing a disruption in the environment, let get started! So I have a router called R2-D2 at ACME Corp, I have been given permission to recover the password and access the device. I have tried some passwords that where written down but all failed. [code]R2-D2 con0 is now available Press RETURN to get started. *************************************************************************** * L E G A L N O T I C E -- Y O U M U S T R E A D * *************************************************************************** * * * You must have explicit permission to access or configure this * * device. All activities performed on this device are logged and * * violations of this policy may result in criminal prosecution. * * * *************************************************************************** * * * This system is for the use of authorized users only. Individuals using * *this computer system without authority, or in excess of their authority, * * are subject to having all of their activities on this system monitored * * and recorded by system personnel. * * * * * * Anyone using this system expressly consents to such monitoring and is * * advised that if such monitoring reveals possible evidence of criminal * * activity, system personnel may provide the evidence of such monitoring * * to law enforcement officials. * * * =========================================================================== User Access Verification Username: admin Password: % Login invalid Username: admin Password: % Login invalid[/code] It is after-hours so I can physically power off the device and that&#39;s what I need to do next. Immediately I have to press the &amp;quot;break sequence&amp;quot; (which depends on the terminal application you are using. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tera_Term&#34; title=&#34;Tera Term&#34;&gt;TeraTerm&lt;/a&gt; this sequence is ALT + B) I like to think of this as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BIOS&#34; title=&#34;BIOS&#34;&gt;BIOS&lt;/a&gt; like on a computer, but it is normally called ROMon in Cisco terms or ROM Monitor, notice the prompt? At this prompt you have to type &amp;quot;confreg 0x2142&amp;quot; which ignores or bypass the startup-config file. Then type the command &amp;quot;reset&amp;quot; to reload the router which will bypass the statup-config. [code]System Bootstrap, Version 12.4(13r)T, RELEASE SOFTWARE (fc1) Technical Support: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/techsupport&#34;&gt;http://www.cisco.com/techsupport&lt;/a&gt; Copyright (c) 2006 by cisco Systems, Inc. Initializing memory for ECC . c2811 platform with 262144 Kbytes of main memory Main memory is configured to 64 bit mode with ECC enabled Upgrade ROMMON initialized PC = 0xbfcd0d54, Cause = 0x2000, Status Reg = 0x3040a803 rommon 1 &amp;gt; confreg 0x2142 You must reset or power cycle for new config to take effect rommon 2 &amp;gt;[/code] Now that the router bypassed its startup-config we have to go into the privilege mode and type the command &amp;quot;copy startup-config running-config&amp;quot; which will load the startup-config into the running-config. [code]DRAM configuration is 64 bits wide with parity enabled. 239K bytes of non-volatile configuration memory. 125440K bytes of ATA CompactFlash (Read/Write) --- System Configuration Dialog --- Would you like to enter the initial configuration dialog? [yes/no]:no Press RETURN to get started! ---Output Omitted--- Router#copy startup-config running-config Destination filename [running-config]? 2341 bytes copied in 0.288 secs (8128 bytes/sec) R2-D2#[/code] Next we change the password to something that we know, I&#39;m changing the login password and the enable secret: [code]R2-D2(config)#username admin password $%^cisco R2-D2(config)#enable secret !!@@cisco[/code] After that we have to change config-register back to the default 0x2102 which will load the startup-config file when reloaded. [code]R2-D2(config)#config-register 0x2102 R2-D2#copy startup-config running-config Destination filename [running-config]? 2341 bytes copied in 0.292 secs (8017 bytes/sec) R2-D2#reload[/code] Copy the running-config to save those password changes by using the &amp;quot;copy running-config startup-config command and reload the device one last time to confirm changes. you should be able to access the device and the configuration by using the passwords you just created . :) I hope this information was helpful some may ask what do those config-resister values do? Well there is some documention on Cisco&#39;s website and it goes over the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/en/US/products/hw/routers/ps133/products_tech_note09186a008022493f.shtml&#34; title=&#34;Use of the Configuration Register on All Cisco Routers&#34;&gt;Use of the Configuration Register on All Cisco Routers&lt;/a&gt; and if you have other questions comment below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/&#34;&gt;Basic Cisco ASA Overview&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/06/28/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/&#34;&gt;Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ciscoskills.net/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/&#34;&gt;CCNA Security - 640-554&lt;/a&gt; (ciscoskills.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/irisdan/basics-of-cisco-switch-administration&#34;&gt;Basics of cisco switch administration&lt;/a&gt; (slideshare.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netcomm-solutions.com/&#34; title=&#34;imran@sheensol.com&#34;&gt;Network Communications&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-10-30 03:01:29&#34;&gt;Oct 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really appreciate your efforts in writing really helpful points in password recovery. Because there are many users who face difficulties in case of password recovery...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
#### 
[Ryan](http://systemstechblog.wordpress.com &#34;lewiryan@isu.edu&#34;) - &lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-10-30 19:28:04&#34;&gt;Oct 2, 2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glad I could help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
