<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cisco Systems on Cisco Skills</title>
    <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/cisco-systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cisco Systems on Cisco Skills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 15:45:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/tags/cisco-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inter-VLAN Routing on the Nexus 5k</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 15:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/03/13/inter-vlan-routing-on-the-nexus-5k/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I previously had the chance to play around with the 5596UP switch, and made some notes on how to configure inter-vlan routing. Since this was a 5596UP switch I needed a layer 3 card to take advantage of it. The next-generation units the 5600 include layer 3 without a card required along with introducing 40GB uplinks! However in this post let&#39;s go back to the basics and configure inter-vlan routing on a nexus switch and in this case I am using a 5596UP.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 4)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 18:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/02/06/640-911-chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Continuing where we left off on Chapter 3 on CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Like before feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter three we discussed about Ethernet Technologies and in chapter four we will learn about the TCP/IP protocol which is fundamentally the protocol that makes the Internet work.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>640-911 (Chapter 3)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/30/640-911-chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 18:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2014/01/30/640-911-chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picking up were we left on off on a series of blog posts that follow the CCNA Data Center Study Guide from Todd Lammle. Feel free to post questions below. In these post I am only going over the topics of each chapter of the book, plus any examples the book offers and to get an idea of what the Cisco exam would cover. In chapter two we discussed about internetworking and in chapter three we will learn about Ethernet technologies.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting FEX (5k to 2k)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/12/01/connecting-fex-5k-to-2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 15:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/12/01/connecting-fex-5k-to-2k/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I was pretty excited to get my hands on some of the Cisco Nexus product line which focuses on switching in the data center. The gear I have is an evaluation unit so I made some notes and one thing I was impressed is how easy it is to connect a Nexus 5K to a Nexus 2k also known as a fabric extender. I have kept it simple as the gear I have is a single Nexus 5596 along with a single Nexus 224TP-E who needs redundancy right?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Your Network Healthy?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/07/19/is-your-network-healthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 01:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/07/19/is-your-network-healthy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Networks are becoming more &amp;quot;borderless&amp;quot; as Cisco likes to call it and it&#39;s definitely true. Having the ability to get access to resources remotely without having to be at our office physically is a nice touch, you may even notice higher productivity and who doesn&#39;t want that! Networks have to be in a healthy state in order for people remotely and people at the office to get their work done.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look at GNS3 - New Version</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/07/06/look-at-gns3-new-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 18:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/07/06/look-at-gns3-new-version/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Look at GNS3 - New Version: A new version of GNS3 released on July 5th 2013 is available for download. You can download GNS3 v0.8.4 at gns3.net. This release includes improvements and new features. Some of the important one are:
Lots of GUI improvements. New hub device. New Idlemax and Idlesleep settings (advanced manipulation of IDLE PC). IOS image and settings test button. New Tool menu to start external scripts/tools. Drag &amp;amp; drop of multiple devices when pressing SHIFT.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site-To-Site VPN via CCP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/05/02/site-to-site-vpn-via-ccp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 02:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/05/02/site-to-site-vpn-via-ccp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I have ran through before on how to create a site-to-site VPN with Cisco SDM which sounds like a repeat but I thought why not bring CCP into light and since I&#39;m studying the newly created CCNA Security (640-554) I figured let&#39;s create a tutorial on it. In this lab I am going to post the running-config of both locations so you can either run it through Packet Tracer or live equipment if you wish.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring AAA – Locally</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/04/04/configuring-aaa-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 01:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/04/04/configuring-aaa-locally/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A while back I talked about AAA but never put out a post on how configure it until now. In this post I am going to be going over the configuration steps of how to configure AAA locally on a Cisco router, (The same commands would also work on Cisco switch). To review what exactly AAA does check my earlier post Understanding AAA. Like mentioned in my earlier post of Understanding AAA it gets better if you have some type of radius or tacacs+ server.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction into Cisco Configuration Professional</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/03/10/introduction-into-cisco-configuration-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2013/03/10/introduction-into-cisco-configuration-professional/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s walk through the basics with Cisco Configuration Professional as it is a helpful tool to use at the associate levels of the Cisco certification track and needed if you are looking at getting the CCNA Security certification. In this introduction we will introduce CCP and setup a community and then finally discover our devices within CCP. This is not the first GUI tool Cisco has produced to manage individual routers, an older tool called Cisco SDM also helped Network Administrators which supports the ISR Generation 1 routers.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 01:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/09/08/cisco-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A Cisco Lab When it comes to learning and getting started with Cisco there are some tools that will help out a lot like Packet Tracer, GNS3 and other emulators. These are great tools for that &amp;quot;simulation&amp;quot; of hands on learning, but you can&#39;t always stay in that area. I find it best to get hands on with &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; Cisco Gear and so with this post I&#39;ll go through my current setup of what I have and ask that question when it is a good time to get a lab?
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade ASA IOS via ASDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/29/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 01:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/29/upgrade-asa-ios-via-asdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this short but helpful post, I&#39;ll go through the process of upgrading the ASA IOS via the ASDM. This is a pretty painless method if all goes well the only thing you have to do schedule downtime if this box is in production, and grab the ASA IOS image from Cisco. For this post all have been covered let&#39;s get started! First things first is always backup your configuration before upgrading and I always read the release notes that Cisco provides when I download the IOS image, it&#39;s good reading and important because usually new features are introduced and sometime the ASDM can&#39;t paraphrase and parse the new configuration which way I usually upgrade the ASDM first.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Cisco ASA Overview</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/06/24/basic-cisco-asa-overview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Firewall The Cisco 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliances are of course an excellent firewall but the ASA also offers (depending on the model) other security services as well, like IPS systems, VPN, content security, unified communications and remote access. These ASA&#39;s can be used as a standalone appliance&#39; that can handle the need for branch offices to enterprise data centers. Or they can be included in high-performance blades that work together with the Cisco Catalyst 6500 Series, and recently new they can also run in a virtual instance which provides tenant isolation for public and private clouds!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCNA Security - 640-554</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 16:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/05/28/ccna-security-640-554/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network-security-lock Out with the old and in with new Cisco is updating its well-known certification CCNA Security. Candidates that are studying for the older exam (640-553) are suggested to take it on or before September 30th 2012. What has changed in the exam? For the most part Cisco SDM is no longer covered, as it has reached its &amp;quot;End of Life&amp;quot; and in fact Cisco Engineering stopped covering the product from developing and testing on February 26th 2012.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Nexus 1000v?</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/03/17/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 17:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/03/17/what-is-the-nexus-1000v/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network_cloud I have worked with the Nexus 1000v product and wanted to share my thoughts on it. I want to explain in this blog what this product is and what it does. The Nexus 1000v can be virtual or a hardware appliance and is considered to be a virtual switch that runs in VMware. The major benefit to this product is the visibly you get when running in a virtual environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trunking Administrative Modes</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/02/11/trunking-administrative-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 22:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/02/11/trunking-administrative-modes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            cisco-switch-blade When looking at the CCNA it is good idea to get a hold of trunking between switches along with that there are a couple of administrative modes that each physical interface on Cisco switch can be when you are trunking between them. Remember that when we are trunking it usually carries all VLANs (This can be changed) but there are different ways to make trunking between links happen. When you are in an interface on a Cisco switch you can change the operational mode of that interface by issuing the switchport mode command.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Tiers</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/21/the-three-tiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 19:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2012/01/21/the-three-tiers/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network_switch Working towards the CCNA Cisco talks about a hierarchical network there are three layers to this design. Access Layer, distribution layer and the core layer. Each of them have their own set of functions and is also considered to be a best practice when the network continues to grow and for redundancy along with just a better way to manage it. The Access layer is the layer that devices connect to, such as PCs, printers, and IP Phones.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome CCT (Cisco Certified Technician Certification)</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/09/21/welcome-cct-cisco-certified-technician-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/09/21/welcome-cct-cisco-certified-technician-certification/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Switching gears for today, Cisco has introduced a certification for onsite support technicians, who need product-specific technical skills to diagnose, restore, repair, and replace critical Cisco equipment. This certification which was introduced this summer now has questions about it from CLN (Cisco Learning Network) and other Cisco sites. So what is this new cert and any changes to ICND1 or ICND2? Short answer is no, this certification is on par with ICND1 or CCENT according to Cisco but is focused on support groups like TAC (Technical Assistance Center), NOC (Network Operations Centers) and 3rd party support.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link-State Protocols</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/31/link-state-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/31/link-state-protocols/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Network-Cables Weeks ago and maybe months :), I talked about distance vector protocols and with that you probably got the feeling that when using a distance vector protocol it does not give a full network graphical representation of the entire network. Only the directly connected routes can&#39;t remember? Check out this post Distance Vector Routing. Link state protocols are faster to converge network changes compared to distance vector however when compared to distance vector setup they can be harder to set up, maintain, and troubleshoot when problems arise.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Codes of ICMP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/24/the-codes-of-icmp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post I wanted to talk about the widely used Ping command. Which is one of the best methods (I think) to begin network troubleshooting. When part of the network goes down it is sometimes hard to figure out why? When you issue the ping command or the extended ping command in a Cisco router several ICMP codes can come up on the router. Let&#39;s discuss them! The first status code &amp;quot;!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of Layer Two Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/08/10/the-beginnings-of-layer-two-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            network-diagram In a perfect world we would never need redundancy on a network infrastructure, but as you know as well as I know we don&#39;t live in a perfect world. Hardware will eventually fail, bottlenecks will appear, and the speed of our network will become slower when we max the bandwidth on links. So having redundancy in routers, connections, and having a hierarchy network is one of best choices to make when improving the efficiently of the network.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Discovery Protocol</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/07/06/cisco-discovery-protocol/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today&#39;s post let&#39;s talk about CDP the Cisco Discovery Protocol. This protocol helps us in two ways, it first helps us verify that a connection between router or switch is set up correctly at least up to layer two in the OSI model. This also helps us discover Cisco devices that are in are network and which interfaces these devices are connected too and from are Cisco equipment. The Cisco discovery protocol is Cisco proprietary and before I go any further let me mention that CDP is a security risk because of the detailed information CDP gives out which helps you has a network administrator build a current network infrastructure, this can also hurt you because this information can easily be sniffed by programs that are easily searched on the internet.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Vector Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 16:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/15/distance-vector-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Couple weeks ago I talked about routing protocols and in the post I mentioned two routing protocol features distance vector and link state. Although these protocols fundamentally do the same thing by getting information on remote networks they get this information in a different way. For today let&#39;s introduce distance vector routing. With a distance vector routing protocol, a router learns about a route to a different network (that&#39;s the purpose of a routing protocol) the router only knows the &amp;quot;distance&amp;quot; to get there this is usually called the metric.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classful vs. Classless Routing</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 16:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/06/01/classful-vs.-classless-routing/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud-Computing-icon Before the internet and general networking become popular into what it is now, there were and still are routing protocols that only do classful routing. What is classful routing? When I was talking about Dynamic Routing earlier (See the post Dynamic Routing Protocols) I mentioned there was a difference between classful routing and classless routing. So in today&#39;s post let&#39;s focus on these two but important topics when using routing protocols.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS Commands</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 17:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/25/cisco-ios-commands/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is the master list of some of the many Cisco IOS Commands that go with the CCNA track. This list also talks about what each command does in brief detail. You may also find that some commands may or may not be used for a CCNA level but offer some important information. If you don&#39;t know what a command does or understand it, I would look at Cisco documentation. Since this is a pretty big list of commands you can see the links to move to the different sections within this page.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VTP</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 16:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/05/11/understanding-vtp/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some people hate it, some people love it. It&#39;s the Cisco proprietary VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) which in short means that Cisco switches can exchange VLAN configuration, instead of manually configuring each switch with the same VLANs. I also suggest if you don&#39;t know what a VLAN is check out the post Creating VLANs Let&#39;s get right into understanding VTP. The thing that makes VTP shine is what it does, although simple to understand it saves time by automatically distributing VLAN information.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure a Site-to-Site VPN via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 18:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/27/configure-a-site-to-site-vpn-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure a site-to-site VPN on a router using the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. (See the post Configuring SDM) Let&#39;s start configuring a site-to-site VPN with SDM! This tutorial is assuming that the configurations to set up Cisco SDM have already been completed.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 17:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/22/configure-ips-intrusion-prevention-system-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Awhile back I talked about the differences between IPS and IDS. (See the post Cisco IDS vs. IPS ) So for today&#39;s post let&#39;s learn how to configure an IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) on a router using the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and cut ownership costs. ( See the post Configure Cisco SDM) Let&#39;s start configuring an IPS with SDM!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Zone Based Firewalls via SDM</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 15:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/20/configuring-zone-based-firewalls-via-sdm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last month I talked about the fundamentals for understanding zone based firewalls (See the post Understanding Zone Based Firewalls). So for today&#39;s post I want to go ahead and talk about configuring the zone based firewalls but with the Cisco SDM (Security Device Manger). The Cisco SDM is a Web-based device management tool a GUI for Cisco routers this can simplify router deployments and reduce ownership costs. (See the post Configure Cisco SDM) Instead of talking about what is zone based firewalls lets jump into the configuration of them.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Learning Labs is Live!</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/13/cisco-learning-labs-is-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/04/13/cisco-learning-labs-is-live/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday was kind of exciting at least for me when I got an e-mail in the morning about Cisco Learning Labs. Studying for the CCNA, CCNP or CCIP is in itself changeling, but getting that hands-on experience is a another problem! When money is short that last thing you want to do is spend it on routers and switches, and most of them on eBay are used and the risk of failing devices makes it a scary choice.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IDS vs. IPS</title>
      <link>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 15:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lewiryan.github.io/ciscoskills/2011/03/09/cisco-ids-vs.-ips/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are tons of network attacks out there. Using a firewall helps but does look for signature based attacks. Access Control Lists are like firewalls and only look at the protocols like HTTP, FTP POP, etc. Cisco has developed some tools that will help network administrators combat the issue; IDS, (Intrusion Detection System) and IPS. (Intrusion Prevention System) Let&#39;s go into IDS first, Cisco IDS is a physical device and is like an alarm system it will alert you when an attack happens but that&#39;s it, the system won&#39;t block the connection.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
